<?xml-model href="potterScripts.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
  <header><!--metadata in here -->
    <title>Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</title>
    <screenWriter>Steven Kloves</screenWriter>
    <productionStart date="yyyy-mm-dd"/>
    <!--Optional: if available. -->
    <release date="2002-11-14"/>
    <!--Look this up and verify -->
    <digitalProject>
      <editor who="#bca">Bianka Alexander</editor>
      <advisor who="#ebb">Elisa Beshero-Bondar</advisor>
      <span from="2020-10-01" to="2021-05-06"/>
      <desc>.......</desc>
      <sourceText>
        <siteName>.....</siteName>
        <link><!--Website URL --></link>
        <dateRetrieved>yyyy-mm-dd</dateRetrieved>
      </sourceText>
    </digitalProject>
  </header>

<script>
  <scene><stage>FADE IN:</stage>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" PRIVET DRIVE - DAY "> WIDE HELICOPTER SHOT. Privet Drive. CAMERA CRANES
      DOWN, DOWN, OVER the rooftops, FINDS the SECOND FLOOR WINDOW of NUMBER 4. HARRY POTTER sits in
      the window. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HARRY'S BEDROOM - DAY "> Harry pages through a SCRAPBOOK, stops on a
      MOVING PHOTO of Ron and Hermione. SQUAWK! Harry jumps. HEDWIG pecks at the LOCK slung through
      her cage door, then glowers at Harry. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I can't, Hedwig. I'm not allowed to use magic outside of school. Besides, if
      Uncle Vernon -- At the sound of the name, HEDWIG SQUAWKS again, LOUDER. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> Har-ry Pot-ter! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Now you've done it. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" KITCHEN - DAY "> While AUNT PETUNIA puts the finishing touches to a
      PUDDING of WHIPPED CREAM and SUGARED VIOLETS, UNCLE VERNON struggles with DUDLEY'S BOW TIE,
      all the while glowering at Harry. </stage>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> I warned you. If you can't control that bloody bird, it'll have to go. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> She's bored. If I could just let her out for an hour or two -- </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> And have you sending secret messages to your freaky little friends? No,
      sir. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> But I haven't gotten any messages. From any of my friends. Not one. All
      summer. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUDLEY"> Who'd want to be friends with you? </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> I should think you'd be more grateful. We raise you since you were a
      baby, give you food off our table, even let you have Dudley's second bedroom... purely out of
      the goodness of our hearts. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUDLEY"> I thought he got the second bedroom because Mum was afraid he'd turn us into
      dung beetles if you put him back in the cupboard under the stairs. <stage>AUNT PETUNIA stops
        cold, exchanges a dark look with Uncle Vernon, then sees Dudley extending a finger for the
        pudding.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA"> Not yet, popkin. That's for when the Masons arrive. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Which should be any moment. Now. Let's run through our schedule one more
      time. Petunia, when the Masons get here, you will be -- </sp>
    <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA"> In the lounge, waiting to welcome them graciously to our home. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Good. And Dudley? </sp>
    <sp who="#DUDLEY"> I'll be waiting to open the door. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Excellent. <stage>turning on Harry</stage> And you? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I'll be in my bedroom, making no noise and pretending I don't exist. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Too right you will. With any luck, this could well be the day I make the
      biggest deal of my career. <stage>DOORBELL RINGS. Instantly, Uncle Vernon shoves Harry out of
        the kitchen and into the hallway.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Upstairs! Hurry! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HARRY'S BEDROOM - DAY "> Harry enters, turns, and stops dead: a tiny
      CREATURE with bat-like ears and bulging green eyes is jumping on his bed as if it were a
      trampoline. This is DOBBY. </stage>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Harry Potter! Such an honor it is! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> What... Who are you? </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby, sir. Dobby the house elf. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I see. Not to be rude or anything, but this isn't a great time for me to have
      a house-elf in my bedroom. </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Oh, yes, sir, Dobby understands. It's just that, Dobby has come to tell you...
      it is difficult, sir... Dobby wonders where to begin. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Why don't you sit down? </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> S-s-sit down? <stage>Suddenly Dobby BURSTS INTO TEARS. LOUD TEARS. Harry
        panics.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Shhhh! I'm sorry. I didn't mean to offend you or anything -- </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Offend Dobby! Dobby has heard of your greatness, sir, but never has he been
      asked to sit down by a wizard, like an equal... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You can't have met many decent wizards then. Dobby shakes his head, then
      without warning, LEAPS off the bed and starts to BANG HIS HEAD FURIOUSLY ON THE FLOOR. </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Bad Dobby! Bad Dobby! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" LIVING ROOM - DAY "> Uncle Vernon pours champagne for MR. and MRS.
      MASON. As Dobby's HEAD BANGING sounds from above, all eyes shift to the ceiling. Uncle Vernon
      chuckles nervously. </stage>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Don't mind that. It's just the... cat. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUDLEY"> Cat? What cat? </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Our cat, tiger. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HARRY'S BEDROOM - DAY "> Dobby gets back to his feet, wobbling, eyes
      spinning dizzily. Harry regards him with a mixture of concern... and wariness. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Are you... all right? </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby had to punish himself, sir. Dobby almost spoke ill of his family, sir. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Your... family? </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> The wizard family Dobby serves, sir. Dobby is bound to serve one family
      forever. If they ever knew Dobby was here... Dobby shudders in fear, then looks up, WHISPERS
      urgently. </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> But Dobby had to come. Dobby has to protect Harry Potter. To warn him.
        <stage>in a fierce whisper</stage> Harry Potter must not go back to Hogwarts School of
      Witchcraft and Wizardry this year. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Not go back? But... I have to. </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> This is a plot. A plot to make most terrible things happen. If Harry Potter
      goes back to school he will be in great danger. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> What terrible things? Who's plotting them? Dobby makes a funny CHOKING and
      GAGGING noise. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Okay! I understand. You can't say -- Too late. Dobby grabs the bedside lamp
      and starts beating himself about the head and YELPING LOUDLY. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" LIVING ROOM - DAY "> Uncle Vernon is in the midst of telling a joke. </stage>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> They arrive at the ninth hole and -- DOBBY'S YELPS INTERRUPT, ringing
      out from above. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRMASON"> Sounds as if that cat of yours has dragged something in with it, Dursley. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Not to worry. I'll sort it out. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HARRY'S BEDROOM - DAY "> Harry wrestles the lamp away from Dobby. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Stop! Stop! FOOTSTEPS THUNDER on the landing. Quickly, Harry grabs Dobby by
      the pillowcase and pitches him into the wardrobe... just as the door FLINGS OPEN. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> What the devil are you doing up here! You've just ruined the punch line
      of my Japanese golfer joke. One more sound and you'll wish you'd never been born, boy! He
      stomps flat-footed from the room and SLAMS THE DOOR. Harry lets Dobby out of the wardrobe. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> See why I've got to go back? I don't belong here. I belong in your world -- at
      Hogwarts. It's the only place I've got... friends. </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Friends who don't even write to Harry Potter? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Well, I expect they've been -- hang on, how do you know my friends haven't
      been writing me? Guiltily, Dobby takes out a STACK of LETTERS. </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Harry Potter mustn't be angry with Dobby -- Dobby hoped if Harry Potter
      thought his friends had forgotten him... Harry Potter might not want to go back to school,
      sir... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Give me those. Now. Dobby frowns sadly, then DASHES out the door. Panicking...
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HALLWAY/STAIRS/KITCHEN - DAY "> ... Harry flies desperately after,
      Dobby bouncing like a ping-pong ball down the stairs and into the kitchen. As Harry races in,
      he finds Dobby on the counter, waving his arms. Aunt Petunia's masterpiece of a pudding RISES,
      then floats into the living room, HOVERING over the Mason's heads. The Masons don't see, but
      the Dursleys -- goggle-eyed--do. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Dobby... Please... No... </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Harry Potter must say he's not going back to school. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I can't. Hogwarts is my home. </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY">
      <stage>a tragic expression</stage> Then Dobby must do it, sir. For Harry Potter's own good.
      Dobby SNAPS HIS FINGERS. The pudding PLUMMETS... straight onto the Masons. They stand
      blinking, covered head to foot with whipped cream and sugared violets. The Masons exit. Uncle
      Vernon and Aunt Petunia race after them. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> I'm sorry. It's our nephew. Very disturbed. Meeting strangers upsets
      him, so we kept him upstairs... </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" DURSLEY HOUSE - DAY "> The Masons RACE out of the house, the Dursleys
      FOLLOWING. </stage>
    <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA"> We have ice cream... The Masons get into their car and drive off, just
      as a SHRIEKING SOUND splits the sky. An OWL SWOOPS down, and DROPS a LETTER at Uncle Vernon's
      feet. He picks up the letter, opens it. As he reads it, a mad gleam dances in Uncle Vernon's
      eye. He turns and races back inside the house. Aunt Petunia follows. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" DURSLEY HOUSE - NIGHT "> Uncle Vernon runs back into the living room,
      extends the letter to Harry. </stage>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Go on. Read it. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> 'Dear Mr. Potter. We have received intelligence that a Hover Charm was used at
      your place of residence at twelve minutes past seven this evening. As you know, underage
      wizards...' </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> '... are not permitted to perform spells outside school.' </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON">
      <stage>snatching the letter</stage> You didn't tell us you weren't Allowed to use magic at
      home. Slipped your mind, didn't it? </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Well, I've got news for you, boy. I'm locking you up! And if you try to
      magic yourself out, they'll expel you! You're never going back to that school! Never! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where="/INT. HARRY'S BEDROOM - NEXT DAY "> A SHORT MONTAGE BEGINS: Uncle Vernon
      fits IRON BARS to the inside of Harry's window. Drills a METAL FLAP to the base of the bedroom
      door. Fits a FAT, GREY LOCK to the door itself. Soaking with sweat, he casts Harry a nasty
      grin and pulls shut the DOOR. It closes with the DULL CLANK of a cell. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HARRY'S BEDROOM - NIGHT "> Harry stares gloomily out the window. The
      METAL FLAP RATTLES and Dudley's pudgy hand slides a BOWL of TINNED SOUP onto the floor. He
      grins cruelly through the opening. </stage>
    <sp who="#DUDLEY"> I know what day it is. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Well done, Dudley. Finally learned the days of the week, have you. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUDLEY"> Today's your birthday. And nobody cares. Dudley SNAPS SHUT the flap. Harry
      sighs, takes the soup and a bit of stale bread, and crosses to Hedwig. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> It's no good turning your beak up. It's all we've got. Harry feeds a piece of
      bread to Hedwig... as we... <stage>DISSOLVE TO: SAME SCENE - LATER Harry leans against the
        wall. Asleep. There is a gentle TAPPING SOUND. Harry opens his eyes and is stunned to
        see...RON WEASLEY staring through the bedroom window.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hiya, Harry. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" DURSLEY HOUSE - NIGHT "> An OLD, TURQUOISE-COLORED FORD ANGLIA floats
      in midair. Ron leans out the back window. His brother FRED sits in the driver's seat. Fred's
      twin George is in the passenger seat. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Fred? George? What're you doing here? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Rescuing you, of course. Where's your trunk? </sp>
    <stage>CLOSEUP - HARRY'S TRUNK Stuffed with clothes, spellbooks. The trunk CLOSES, SNAPS, SHUT.
      Harry drags the trunk to the windowsill, watches Ron tie off a fierce knot on the bars of
      Harry's window. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Stand back.</sp>
    <stage>Harry steps back. Ron turns, nods to Fred. INSERT - FRED'S FOOT Fred STEPS ON the
      accelerator.</stage>


  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" DURSLEY HOUSE - NIGHT "> The Ford Anglia FLIES UP into the air, the
      rope SNAPS TIGHT, and -- CRUNCH! -- the bars are TORN from the window. Bricks and bars RAIN
      DOWN onto the lawn below, a mangled mess. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" UNCLE VERNON'S BEDROOM - NIGHT "> Uncle Vernon WAKES... </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where="/EXT. HARRY'S BEDROOM/THE CAR - MOMENTS LATER "> Harry pushes the trunk
      over the sill into the Anglia's boot, then scrambles through the window himself,
      when...SQUAWK! </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hedwig! Harry clambers back, grabs Hedwig's cage, swings it onto the ledge,
      when... BAM! The bedroom door CRASHES OPEN. </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Petunia! He's getting away! <stage>As Harry leaps for the windowsill,
        Uncle Vernon CHARGES FORWARD and SNATCHES his ankle. Harry tumbles into the darkness, one
        hand gripping Hedwig's cage, the other reaching out and... CATCHING Ron's at the last
        possible second. Uncle Vernon puts both hands to Harry's ankle, pulls harder. Ron braces
        himself, pulls back. Harry hangs, stretched high over the lawn, directly above the mangled
        steel bars.</stage>
      <stage>CLOSEUP: Harry's hand begins to slip from Ron's fingers. INSIDE OF CAGE: Hedwig PECKS
        feverishly at the LOCK. CLOSE-UP: Ron. PANICKED.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hold on, Harry! </sp>
    <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Oh no, boy! You and that bloody pigeon aren't going anywhere!
        <stage>CLOSE-UP: Harry's hand begins to slip away from Ron's. INSIDE OF CAGE: Hedwig PECKS
        HARDER and... the CAGE OPENS. Hedwig SWOOPS into the sky, WHEELS BACK and hammers her beak
        into Uncle Vernon's hand. He ROARS, stumbles back and... Ron and George pull Harry into the
        air.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Put your foot down, Fred! <stage>Like a rocket, the Anglia sails into the stars.
        Harry glances back, sees Aunt Petunia and Dudley join Uncle Vernon at the window. As Hedwig
        races up, soaring just beyond the car window, Ron turns to Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> By the way, Harry. Happy Birthday. <stage>DISSOLVE TO: </stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" THE BURROW - EARLY MORNING "> As the Anglia drops through a pink sky, a
      haphazard mess of a HOUSE, built around a towering central chimney, appears below. By the
      road, a lopsided SIGN reads: THE BURROW. FLUMPH! The car touches down in a WHIRLING CONE of
      dust, scatters a group of chickens, and fishtails to a halt. The boys spill quickly out of the
      car. FRED WHISPERS urgently. </stage>
    <sp who="#FRED"> Hurry! Let's nip inside before Mum wakes up! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" FRONT ROOM - THE BURROW - MOMENTS LATER "> The boys sneak inside,
      gently close the door. Harry stops. Magical objects surround him: A CLOCK displays different
      chores for each family member. A pair of NEEDLES knit a sweater by themselves. And a stack of
      PLAYING CARDS that. A stack of PLAYING CARDS SHUFFLE themselves, providing a cooling breeze
      for Ron's aging rat, SCABBERS. Ron shrugs, averts his eyes self- consciously. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> It's not much. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I think it's... brilliant! Ron looks up. Sees Harry's mesmerized face.
      Slowly...GRINS. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> WHERE... HAVE... YOU... BEEN?! <stage>The boys nearly jump out of their
        skin. MRS. WEASLEY stands in the doorway. Furious. She smiles sweetly at Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Harry! How wonderful to see you. <stage>back to the boys</stage> Beds
      empty! No note! You could've died! You could've been seen! <stage>again, to Harry</stage> I
      don't blame you, of course, dear. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> They were starving him, Mum! There were bars on his window! </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> You best hope I don't put bars on your window, Ronald Weasley!
        <stage>softening instantly</stage> Care for a spot of tea, Harry? </sp>
    <sp who="#GINNY"> Mummy. Have you seen my jumper -- <stage>A small, RED-HEADED GIRL appears.
        Sees Harry. And... SQUEALS. Dashes back up the stairs. Ron frowns.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Ginny. Been talking about you all summer. Dead annoying, really. </sp>
    <sp who="#GEORGE"> Dad's home! <stage>The front door OPENS and ARTHUR WEASLEY enters. A tall man
        with red hair, his robes look dusty and travel-worn.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> What a night! Nine raids! Nine! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>to Ron</stage> Raids? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Dad works at the Ministry of Magic. In the Misuse of Muggle Artefacts Office. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> The Misuse of Muggle Artefacts...? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> That's when wizards bewitch something to drive Muggles mad. Shrinking door keys,
      that kind of thing. Dad loves Muggles. Thinks they're fascinating. <stage>Mr. Weasley hangs up
        his cloak, turns. Blinks.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Well now. Who are you? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Harry, sir. Harry Potter. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Good Lord, are you really? Ron's told us all about you, of course. When
      did you get here? </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY">
      <stage>darkly</stage> This morning. Your sons flew that enchanted car of yours to Surrey house
      and back last night. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Did you now! How'd it go?! <stage>catching his wife's eye</stage> I... I
      mean... That was very wrong, boys. Very wrong indeed. So, Harry. You must know all about
      Muggles. Tell me, what exactly is the function of a parking meter? <stage>Harry is about to
        answer, when he notices an OWL (ERROL) soaring toward the kitchen window. To Harry's horror,
        the owl doesn't pull up. It just flies... SMACK!... into the glass.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> That must be Errol with the post. Fetch him, will you, George?
        <stage>George takes the unconscious Errol, absently lays him on a draining board, and takes
        the LETTERS clutched in his claws.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GEORGE"> It's our Hogwarts letters! And look. They've sent Harry's as well. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Dumbledore must know you're here, Harry. Doesn't miss a trick, that man. </sp>
    <sp who="#FRED">
      <stage>reading his</stage> This lot won't come cheap, Mum. The spellbooks alone... </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> We'll manage. Right then. There's only one place to get all of this. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON #FRED #GEORGE"> Diagon Alley! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" LIVING ROOM - THE BURROW - DAY  LATER  "> Everyone has gathered in
      front of the large fireplace. </stage>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> You first, Harry dear. <stage>Mrs. Weasley offers Harry a FLOWERPOT. At
        the bottom is a layer of VERY SOFT DUST. Harry frowns in confusion.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Harry's never traveled by Floo Powder before, Mum. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Floo Powder? Just then, Ron's older brother PERCY enters. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Percy. Would you mind going first, so Harry can see how it's done? </sp>
    <sp who="#PERCY"> Certainly, Mother. Don't worry, Harry. It's simple enough. <stage>Percy takes
        a pinch from the pot, pitches it into the fireplace and BRIGHT GREEN FLAMES ROAR HIGH. To
        Harry's amazement, he calmly walks... straight into them.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#PERCY"> Diagon Alley. <stage>Percy VANISHES. Tentatively, Harry reaches into the
        pot.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Remember to speak clearly, dear! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> And mind you get out at the right grate! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>nodding, unsure</stage> D-Dia-gon Alley! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" SPIRALING TUNNEL "> The SOUND is DEAFENING as Harry hurtles forward,
      squinting against the sting of WHIRLING SOOT and the mad, flickering lights of passing
      fireplaces. He falls face forward... </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" BORGIN AND BURKES - STONE FIREPLACE - DAY "> ... onto a stone hearth.
      Dizzy and dirty, Harry reclaims his shattered glasses. He's tumbled into a wizard's shop, but
      a decidedly creepy one. He starts to exit, when a WITHERED HAND in a GLASS CASE catches his
      eye: The Hand of Glory. Nearby, an OPAL NECKLACE gleams: Caution: Do not touch. Cursed--Has
      Claimed the Lives of Nineteen Muggle Owners to Date. Oddly transfixed by it all, Harry drifts
      toward the exit, when... DRACO MALFOY and his father, LUCIUS MALFOY, appear beyond the front
      window, approaching the shop. Harry glances about, spies a LARGE BLACK CABINET and slips
      inside. As he pulls the doors closed, a TINY CARD swings INTO VIEW: Crushing Cabinet. Malfoy
      and his father enter. A stooped man (MR. BORGIN) emerges from the back room. IN THE CABINET,
      Harry watches, unaware that the walls around him are... SLOWLY CLOSING IN. </stage>
    <sp who="#MRBORGIN"> Mr. Malfoy! What a pleasure to see you again. If I may, just in today -- </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> I'm not buying today, Mr. Borgin. But selling. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRBORGIN"> Selling? </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> You have heard, of course, that the Ministry of Magic is conducting
      more raids. There are even rumors of a new Muggle Protection Act... <stage>Lucius unravels a
        roll of parchment, hands it to Borgin.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> I have a few... ah... items at home that might prove embarrassing if
      the Ministry were to call. Certain poisons and the like... </sp>
    <sp who="#MRBORGIN"> Hmmm... yes. I see... <stage>INSIDE THE CABINET, Harry realizes the walls
        are CLOSING IN. His eyes shift upward. The ceiling is DROPPING. Draco drifts to the Hand of
        Glory, reaches out, when... the HAND GRABS HIM. Draco shrieks, manages to slip free, then
        calms. He eyes the hand with malicious glee.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Can I have this? </sp>
    <sp who="#MRBORGIN"> Ah, the Hand of Glory. Insert a candle and it gives light only to the
      holder. Best friend of thieves and plunderers. Your son has fine taste, sir. </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Hopefully my son will amount to more than a thief, Mr. Borgin. Though
      if his marks don't pick up -- </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> It's not my fault the teachers have favorites. That Hermione Granger -- </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> I would have thought you'd be ashamed that a girl of no wizarding
      family beat you in every exam. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRBORGIN"> It's the same all over. Wizard blood is counting for less everywhere. </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY">
      <stage>deadly</stage> Not with me. <stage>INSIDE THE CABINET, Harry's knees are up under his
        chin... Borgin checks off one last time, then returns the parchment to Lucius. Satisfied,
        Malfoy nods.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Very good. I'll expect you at the manor tomorrow. Come, Draco.
        <stage>They exit. As Borgin slips into the back room, the Crushing Cabinet's doors FLY OPEN
        and Harry leaps free. Inside, the walls, floor, and ceiling SNAP SHUT! Borgin reappears,
        blinks curiously at Harry, then watches him RACE out the door.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" KNOCKTURN ALLEY - DAY  MOMENTS LATER  "> Once outside, Harry fits his
      broken glasses to his face, eyes a STREET SIGN: "KNOCKTURN ALLEY." The vendors here clearly
      cater to the Dark Arts: SHRUNKEN HEADS, POISONOUS CANDLES. One window teems with SPIDERS. </stage>
    <sp who="#AGEDWITCH">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> Not lost are you, my dear? <stage>Harry wheels, looking into the mossy
        teeth of a decrepit WITCH. She holds a tray of HUMAN FINGERNAILS.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I'm fine, thanks. I'm just -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> HARRY! What d'yer think yer doin' down 'ere? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hagrid! <stage>Hagrid knocks the tray from the cursing Witch's hands, then
        seizes Harry by the scruff of the neck and steers him away.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" DIAGON ALLEY - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAY "> Hagrid swats at Harry's sooty
      clothes. </stage>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Yer a mess! Skulkin' 'round Knockturn Alley. Dodgy place, Harry. Don't want
      no one ter see yeh down there. People'll be thinkin' yer up ter no good. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I was lost, I -- Hang on. What were you doing down there? </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> I was lookin' fer a Flesh Eatin' Slug Repellent. They're ruinin' the school
      cabbages. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> Harry! <stage>Harry looks up, sees HERMIONE GRANGER standing at the top of
        Gringotts' white steps. She runs down to meet them.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Hello, Hagrid. Oh, it's wonderful to see you two again. <stage>She stops
        then, cocks her head curiously at Harry, then takes out her wand and points it directly
        between his eyes.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Oculus Reparo. Instantly, Harry's glasses are mended. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I need to remember that one. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> C'mon. Everyone's been so worried. <stage>Hermione leads them to Gringotts,
        where Hermione's rather nervous-looking Muggle parents stand with the Weasleys.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> So you're dentists! Fascinating! I understand other Muggles quite fear
      you? Why is that? </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Oh, Harry. Thank goodness. We hoped you'd only gone one grate too far.
      Come now. We're off to Flourish and Blotts. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Isn't it thrilling! Gilderoy Lockhart's going to be there! We can actually
      meet him! I mean, he's written almost the whole booklist! <stage>As Mrs. Weasley and Hermione
        dash off, Harry frowns.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Who? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" FLOURISH AND BLOTTS - DAY "> CLOSE-UP: GILDEROY LOCKHART. A handsome,
      golden-haired wizard with stunning pearl-white teeth. He miles, winks at the camera. DOLLY
      BACK to reveal that the image of Lockhart is actually a MOVING PHOTOGRAPH propped in the
      window. A PLACARD declares: HERE TODAY! SIGNING COPIES OF HIS AUTOBIOGRAPHY, MAGICAL ME...
      GILDEROY LOCKHART! </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" FLOURISH AND BLOTTS - DAY "> Harry and the others thread their way
      through a CHATTERING THRONG of MIDDLE-AGED LADIES, all craning their necks for a view of
      Lockhart, who sits signing books at the rear of the shop. At the sight of him, Mrs. Weasley
      pats her hair. </stage>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> There he is! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Mum fancies him. <stage>For this, Mrs. Weasley gives Ron a jab in the
        shoulder.</stage>
      <stage>A SHORT MAN WITH A CAMERA bumps past.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#SHORTMAN"> Out of the way! This is for The Daily Prophet! <stage>Instantly, Lockhart
        looks up, flashes a smile, when...</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> It can't be Harry Potter? <stage>The crowd WHISPERS excitedly as
        Lockhart dives forward, seizes Harry's hand and turns him toward the photographer.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART">
      <stage>under his breath</stage> Nice big smile, Harry. Together, you and I rate the front
      page. <stage>as the CAMERA FLASHES</stage> Ladies and gentlemen! What an extraordinary moment
      this is! When young Harry here stepped into Flourish and Blotts this morning to purchase my
      autobiography, Magical Me -- which, incidentally is celebrating its twenty-seventh week atop
      The Daily Prophet's Bestseller List -- he had no idea that he would, in fact, be leaving with
      my entire collected works! Free of charge! <stage>As the crowd CLAPS, Lockhart catches the eye
        of a FLUNKY and, before Harry knows it, a towering stack of books is shoved into his arms.
        Mortified, Harry mumbles quietly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Thank you. <stage>Slipping free, Harry drifts back into the crowd and, red
        with embarrassment, drops the books into Ginny's cauldron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You have these. I'll buy my own -- </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO">
      <stage>appearing, sneers</stage> Bet you loved that, didn't you, Potter? Famous Harry Potter.
      Can't even go into a bookshop without making the front page. </sp>
    <sp who="#GINNY"> Leave him alone! He didn't want all that! </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Look, Potter. You've got yourself a girlfriend! </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Silence, Draco! Ah... Mr. Potter. I don't believe we've met.
        <stage>Lucius Malfoy extends his hand, as if offering to shake Harry's, but instead gently
        plays his fingers over the fringe of Harry's scalp, revealing Harry's LIGHTNING BOLT SCAR.
        At his touch, Harry withdraws, ever so slightly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Forgive me, Mr. Potter. But your scar is legend. As, of course, is the
      wizard who gave it to you. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> He was a murderer. </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Yes, a pity about your parents. Curious that you yourself should escape
      with a mere flesh wound. Curious, too, that you speak of him in the past. Surely, you don't
      think He-Who-Must-Not-Be- Named is gone forever. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> His name is Voldemort. <stage>Those within earshot gasp as Harry utters the
        word.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> You must be very brave, Mr. Potter, to dare speak his name. Or foolish. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Fear of a name only increases fear of the thing itself. <stage>Lucius
        Malfoy's eyes slide, find Hermione staring defiantly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> You must be Miss Granger. Draco's told me all about you... and your
      parents. Muggles, aren't you? <stage>Mr. and Mrs. Granger nod nervously. Lucius Malfoy can
        barely disguise his distaste for them. Arthur Weasley hurries over.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Ron! Harry! It's mad in here. Let's go outside. </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Well, well, well -- Arthur Weasley. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY">
      <stage>stiffly</stage> Lucius. </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Busy time at the Ministry. All those raids. I hope they're paying you
      overtime. <stage>Malfoy reaches into Ginny's cauldron, removes a very old, battered copy of A
        Beginner's Guide to Transfiguration.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Obviously not. Dear me. What's the use of being a disgrace to the name
      of wizard if they don't even pay you well for it. </sp>
    <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> We have a very different idea about what disgraces the name of wizard,
      Lucius. </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY">
      <stage>glancing at the Grangers</stage> Clearly. The company you keep, Weasley. And I thought
      your family could sink no lower. <stage>Mr. Weasley moves to hit Lucius Malfoy. Hagrid steps
        forward, puts a firm hand on Mr. Weasley's shoulder.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Ignore 'im, Arthur. <stage>Mr. Weasley backs away. Lucius Malfoy tosses
        Ginny's BATTERED TEXTBOOK back into her cauldron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Here, girl. Take your book. It's the best your father can give you.
        <stage>Lucius and Draco exit. Hagrid looks at the Weasleys.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> No Malfoy's worth listenin' ter. Rotten ter the core, the whole family...
        <stage>As Harry watches Draco and his father go, we -- DISSOLVE TO:</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" KING'S CROSS - MORNING "> Amid a neat line of cars, the Anglia sits at
      a decidedly odd angle, as if its driver were not the most skilled motorist. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" KING'S CROSS - DAY "> The Weasleys and Harry -- pushing large TROLLEYS
      -- dash under the LARGE CLOCK which reads two minutes to eleven. </stage>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Oh dear! The train'll be leaving any moment! All together now!
        <stage>Hurrying, they race to PLATFORMS NINE AND TEN. Quickly, Percy, Fred and George stride
        briskly toward the stone barrier that divides the platforms -- and simply DISAPPEAR.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Go on, Ginny. You know what to do. <stage>Ginny, looking a bit nervous,
        rushes toward the barrier, closes her eyes, and sleds...</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" PLATFORM NINE AND THREE QUARTERS - DAY "> ... out onto the other side.
      As she gazes at the HOGWARTS EXPRESS, Mr. and Mrs. Weasley materialize at her side. </stage>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> Come, Ginny. We'll get you a seat. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" KING'S CROSS "> Ron glances at the clock. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> We better hurry. <stage>Harry nods, leans into his trolley and -- CRASH! -- hits
        the barrier and bounces back into Ron. A GUARD glowers.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GUARD"> What in blazes d'you two think you're doing? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Sorry. Lost control of the trolley. <stage>to Ron</stage> Why can't we get
      through? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> I dunno. The gateway's sealed itself for some reason. <stage>As Ron presses his
        ear to the barrier, the CLOCK CHIMES.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> The train leaves at exactly eleven o'clock. We've missed it. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Can't hear a thing. <stage>a sudden thought</stage> Harry. If we can't get
      through, maybe Mum and Dad can't get back. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Maybe we should go wait by the car. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> The car! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" PARKING LOT  KING'S CROSS  - MOMENTS LATER "> Pushing their trolleys
      madly before them, Harry and Ron dash to the car, load their belongings into the Anglia's
      boot. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> This is mad. We can't drive to Hogwarts. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Who says we're driving? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You don't mean -- Ron, no. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Look, who knows when Mum and Dad will get back. And we've got to get to school,
      haven't we? And even underage wizards are allowed to use magic if it's an absolute emergency.
      Least that's what Fred and George always say... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Something tells me we're going to regret this. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" ANGLIA - DAY "> Ron TAPS his WAND on the dash and the Anglia burbles to
      life. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> No offense, Ron, but are you sure you know how to fly this. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> No problem. <stage>Ron SHIFTS. With a GREAT JOLT, the car lifts from the
        ground.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> There. See. Now I reckon all we have to do is find the Hogwarts Express and
      follow it. Simple. <stage>Harry nods, not entirely convinced. He peers out the window. Down
        below, TWO PEDESTRIANS stare in disbelief.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Uh, Ron. I should tell you. Most Muggles aren't accustomed to seeing a flying
      car. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Right. <stage>Ron presses a TINY SILVER BUTTON on the dashboard and they...
        DISAPPEAR. Down below, the baffled pedestrians blink.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" FLYING CAR  SCOTLAND  - DAY LATER "> CAMERA STARTS IN the clouds,
      passes through, finds Scotland's stunning green. The Anglia's ENGINE PUTTERS softly, when
      -POP! - the car reappears. Ron jabs at the silver button. </stage>


    <sp who="#RON"> Uh oh. The Invisibility Booster must be faulty. <stage>CAMERA ZOOMS ALONG the
        ridge of a cliff. The car reappears from above, gliding away FROM CAMERA.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Any sign of the train? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> There! Up ahead! Look... <stage>Along a STEEP BRIDGE, a single line of TRAIN
        TRACKS appear.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Brilliant. <stage>Ron SHIFTS, GLIDES DOWN, until the Anglia is only a few feet
        above the tracks. The boys peer ahead, looking for the train.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> It must be around here someplace. <stage>Behind them, through the Anglia's rear
        window, the Hogwarts Express APPEARS, closing fast. Harry and Ron perk up. Smile.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Do you hear that? <stage>Then, at precisely the same moment, Harry and Ron
        register the DIRECTION of the sound. They glance at each other, turn as one and see the
        train GROWING HUGE in the rear window.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> Aaaahhhhh! <stage>Ron SPINS THE WHEEL, puts his foot to the gas and -- at
        the last possible second -- whips the Anglia out of the train's path. The car WAFFLES,
        TOPPLES upside down briefly, before... TILTING onto its side. As it jets under the bridge,
        Harry goes SLIDING DOWN ACROSS HIS SEAT, into the door, and... OUT. Dangling upside-down
        from the open door, he watches the Hogwarts Express ZIP PAST and, in one window, glimpses
        NEVILLE and SEAMUS, mouths open in astonishment.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Take my hand! <stage>Harry's grips Ron's hand, eyes the train steaming far
        below. It's quite a drop. Harry's fingers begin to LOSE THEIR GRIP.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hold on! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I'm trying! Your hand's all sweaty! <stage>Straining, Ron yanks him inside,
        levels off the car. As Harry falls heavily into his seat, he BUCKLES his safety
        belt.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I think we found the train. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS CASTLE - FLYING CAR - NIGHT "> As HOGWARTS CASTLE comes INTO
      VIEW, the Anglia ENTERS FRAME. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Welcome home, Harry. <stage>Harry smiles at the sight of it, when... the Anglia
        GROANS.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Just out of interest, Ron. Have you ever landed a car before? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Well... no. but, until a few hours ago, I'd never taken off in one either.
        <stage>With that, the car LURCHES, the nose DROPS, and...</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Uh oh. <stage>... Harry, Ron and car go pitching through the night. As Ron rakes
        the GEARS, they hurtle madly toward the CASTLE WALL.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> IT'S NOT WORKING! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> UP! UP! <stage>Ron SHIFTS desperately. The Anglia LURCHES up, barely clears
        the castle wall. Harry and Ron exchange a look of relief, when... the car GROANS again,
        LURCHES... downward.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> MIND THAT TREE! <stage>Down below a GIANT WILLOW TREE looms. Ron SHIFTS.
        Nothing.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> TURN! TURN! <stage>Harry reaches over and, together, he and Ron SPIN THE
        WHEEL. It's useless. The car is heading straight for the tree. Desperately, Ron WHIPS OUT
        his wand and WHACKS THE DASHBOARD.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> STOP! STOP! STOP! <stage>The wand SNAPS IN TWO and -- CRUNCH! -- car meets tree.
        Harry blinks. They hang dreamily, BALANCED on the HIGHEST LIMB.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> My wand! Look at my wand! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Be thankful it's not your neck. <stage>THWUNMP! Something HEAVY HITS Harry's
        door, sends a SHUDDER through the car.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What's happening? <stage>Slowly, they look up and, in disbelief, watch one of
        the tree's branches PULL BACK, CURL INTO ITSELF, and come LASHING FORWARD like a MASSIVE
        FIST. THWUMP!</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> Aaaaahhhhh! <stage>The Anglia tilts crazily, slides backwards and
        FREE-FALLS through the air and... LANDS on lower grid of branches.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What kind of tree is this? <stage>Before Harry can respond, the tree begins to
        PUMMEL THE CAR from all sides, tossing Henry and Ron about like popcorn. WINDOW SHATTER.
        Heavy DENTS appear on the roof above Ron and Harry's heads. Then the car FALLS again...
        SLAMMING HEAVILY TO THE GROUND. Instantly, the tree's lower branches shoot through the front
        and rear windscreens and, gaining purchase, begin to SHAKE THE CAR BACK AND FORTH.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> Aaaaahhhhh! <stage>The tree PITCHES the car into the air. As the Anglia
        SLAMS DOWN again, bobbing on its SQUEALING SHOCKS, the ENGINE BURBLES BACK TO LIFE. Harry
        LOOKS UP, peering through the shattered windscreen. The willow's branches, as one, rear
        back, ready for one last punishing blow.</stage>
      <stage>Harry CRIES OUT.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Reverse! Reverse! <stage>Ron SHIFTS, the CAR SHOOTS BACKWARDS, and the willow
        PUMMELS THE TREAD-MARKED GROUND they just vacated. Safely clear, the doors fly open, the
        seats tip sideways, and Ron and Harry are ejected. As they hit the ground, their trunks fly
        from the boot, Hedwig's cage rockets out the back window, and Hedwig herself flaps into the
        night. Taillights blazing angrily, the BATTERED car speeds off, fishtailing into the Dark
        Forest.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Dad's going to kill me. <stage>They hear a TREMENDOUS GROAN, turn back, and see
        the Whomping Willow assume its natural form, waiting for its next victim.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" STONE STEPS/ENTRANCE HALL - NIGHT "> Filthy and bruised, Harry and Ron
      drag themselves up the steps. Behind them we see the mountain of student trunks and caged pets
      already brought up from the train. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> A house elf shows up in my bedroom, we can't get through the barrier to
      Platform Nine and Three Quarters, we almost get killed by a tree... clearly someone doesn't
      want me here this year. </sp>
    <sp who="#FILCH"> Well, take a good look, lads... <stage>They stop. ARGUS FILCH stands at the
        top of the landing, his cat -- MRS. NORRIS -- twitching her tail at his feet.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#FILCH"> This night might well be the last you spend in this castle. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" SNAPE'S OFFICE - MOMENTS LATER "> CLOSEUP: The Evening Prophet ENTERS
      FRAME. The HEADLINE reads: FLYING FORD ANGLIA MYSTIFIES MUGGLES. Below the fold a PHOTO shows
      Harry and Lockhart at Flourish and Blotts. CAMERA PULLS BACK, PROFESSOR SEVERUS SNAPE stands
      at his desk, newspaper in hand as Harry and Ron stare with dread. Filch lurks in the doorway,
      eying them with pleasure. </stage>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> You were seen! By no less then seven Muggles. Do you have any idea how serious
      this is? You have risked the exposure of our world. Not to mention the damage you inflicted on
      a Whomping Willow that has been on these grounds for hundreds of years. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Honestly, Professor Snape, I think it did more damage to us. </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Silence! I assure you, were you in Slytherin and your fate rested with me, the
      both of you would be on the train home tonight. As it is -- </sp>
    <sp who="#ALBUSDUMBLEDORE"> They are not. <stage>Harry and Ron turn. ALBUS DUMBLEDORE stands in
        the doorway. Alongside him is a distinctly annoyed PROFESSOR McGONAGALL.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Professor Dumbledore. Professor McGonagall... </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Headmaster, these boys have flouted the Decree for the Restriction of Underage
      Wizardry. As such... </sp>
    <sp who="#ALBUSDUMBLEDORE"> I'm well aware of our bylaws, Severus, having written more than a
      few myself. However, as Head of Gryffindor House, it is for Professor McGonagall to determine
      the appropriate action. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>rising gloomily</stage> We'll go and get our stuff. </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> What are you talking about, Mr. Weasley? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Well, you're going to expel us, aren't you? </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Not today, Mr. Weasley. But I must impress upon both of you the
      seriousness of what you have done. I will be sending owls to both of your families tonight.
      And you will each get a detention. <stage>Snape casts a look of pure venom at Harry and
        Ron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Splendid. Now, I suggest we return to the feast. There's a
      delicious-looking custard tart I want to sample. <stage>Rising, Harry spies an ENVELOPE on the
        floor. Taking it, he reads the back: "KWIKSPELL. A CORRESPONDENCE COURSE IN BEGINNER'S
        MAGIC." It's addressed to "MR. ARGUS FILCH."</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Mr. Filch. You dropped this... <stage>Filch turns, eyes the envelope with
        embarrassment, then snatches it from Harry's hand and stuffs it into his pocket.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS CASTLE - MORNING "> The Whomping Willow sulks in the
      courtyard, SLINGS strung about its injured branches. CAMERA CRANES OVER the castle walls,
      REVEALING the exterior of GREENHOUSE THREE, where students hurry inside for the beginning of
      class. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GREENHOUSE THREE - MORNING "> As Harry and Ron enter, SEAMUS, NEVILLE
      and some of the other Gryffindors hover nearby. </stage>
    <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Detention. On the first day? </sp>
    <sp who="#SEAMUS"> That must be some kind of record. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I should think you'd count yourself lucky that's all you got. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> I should think you'd mind your own business. <stage>They glare at each other.
        PROFESSOR SPROUT, a squat little witch, TAPS her wand on a stack of POTS.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#SPROUT"> Welcome to Greenhouse Three, Second Years. Today, we will be re-potting
      Mandrakes. Now, who here can tell me the properties of the Mandrake? Yes, Miss Granger. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Mandrake, or Mandragora, is used to return those who have been transfigured
      to their original state. It's also quite dangerous. The Mandrake's cry is fatal to anyone who
      hears it. </sp>
    <sp who="#SPROUT"> Excellent. Ten points to Gryffindor. As our Mandrakes are only seedlings,
      their cries won't kill yet. However, they will knock you out for several hours. That is why I
      have provided each of you with a pair of earmuffs. If you would then... <stage>Ron frowns.
        He's gotten a BRIGHT PINK FLUFFY pair. When the class is ready, Professor Sprout leads them
        to the GARDEN AREA. She grasps one of the TUFTY PLANTS before her... and pulls. Harry gasps.
        Instead of roots, a small, muddy, extremely ugly BABY pops out of the earth, leaves growing
        right out of its head. Neville's eyes ROLL BACK. He FAINTS. Professor Sprout plunges the
        BAWLING CREATURE deep into a POT, removes her earmuffs, and the others follow suit. Everyone
        save Neville, who lies stretched on the ground.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#SPROUT"> Hm. Looks as though Mr. Longbottom neglected his muffs. </sp>
    <sp who="#SEAMUS"> No, ma'am. He's just fainted. </sp>
    <sp who="#SPROUT"> Very well. We'll just leave him then. Come now. Four to a tray, plenty of
      pots to go round... </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - LUNCH - DAY "> Percy enters in the company of PENELOPE
      CLEARWATER, just as NEARLY HEADLESS NICK glides by. </stage>
    <sp who="#PENELOPECLEARWATER"> There's Nearly Headless Nick. </sp>
    <sp who="#PERCY"> Hello, Sir Nicolas. </sp>
    <sp who="#NEARLYHEADLESS"> NICK Hello, Percy. Miss Clearwater. <stage>At the Gryffindor table,
        Hermione has her nose buried in Gilderoy Lockhart's Travels with Trolls. Ron runs gobs of
        Spellotape over his BROKEN WAND, shakes his head grimly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Say it. I'm doomed. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You're doomed. <stage>FLASH! -- a LIGHT BLINDS Harry. He blinks, finds a small
        boy (COLIN CREEVEY) standing before him with a CAMERA.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#COLIN"> Hiya, Harry. I'm Colin Creevey. I'm in Gryffindor too. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hello, Colin. Nice to meet -- </sp>
    <sp who="#COLIN"> They're for my dad -- the pictures. He's a milkman, you know, a Muggle, like
      all our family's been until me. No one knew all the odd stuff I could do was magic till we got
      my letter from Hogwarts. Everyone just thought I was mental. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Imagine that. </sp>
    <sp who="#COLIN"> Say, Harry. D'you think your friend could take a photo of me and you standing
      together? Ya' know, to prove I've met you? <stage>Harry glances at Ron. He looks positively
        homicidal. Mercifully, just then, OWLS STREAM into the Hall.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DEANTHOMAS"> Post is here! <stage>One after another, the birds swoop gracefully down,
        clutching letters from home. All except one, who plops beak-first into Ron's soup.
        Errol.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Bloody bird's a menace -- Oh... no. </sp>
    <sp who="#SEAMUS"> Heads up, everyone. Weasley's gotten himself a Howler. </sp>
    <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Go on, Ron. I ignored one from my Gran once... and it was horrible.
        <stage>Ron looks pale. Clutched in Errol's beak is a DAMP RED ENVELOPE. Hands shaking, he
        takes it, opens it, and... MRS. WEASLEY'S VOICE THUNDERS, sending plates and spoons
        rattling.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY">
      <stage>V.O.</stage> RONALD WEASLEY! HOW DARE YOU STEAL THAT CAR! I AM ABSOLUTELY DISGUSTED!
      YOUR FATHER'S NOW FACING AN INQUIRY AT WORK AND IT'S ENTIRELY YOUR FAULT! IF YOU PUT ANOTHER
      TOE OUT OF LINE WE'LL BRING YOU STRAIGHT HOME! <stage>softening suddenly</stage> Oh, and Ginny
      dear. Congratulations on making Gryffindor. Your father and I are so proud. <stage>Ginny,
        sitting a bit apart from the others, looks up shyly, then returns to the SMALL BLACK BOOK
        she's scribbling in. Ron watches the envelope RIP ITSELF TO PIECES, then endures HOWLS of
        LAUGHTER from the other House tables. Colin Creevey snaps a few photos. Harry looks
        sympathetically at Ron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Look at it this way. How much worse can things get? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GILDEROY LOCKHART'S CLASSROOM - DAY "> Gilderoy Lockhart paces before
      the class. Hermione and the girls hang on his every word, while Harry and Ron eye the LARGE,
      COVERED CAGE RATTLING mysteriously on his desk. </stage>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Let me introduce you to your new Defense Against the Dark Arts
      Teacher. Me. Gilderoy Lockhart, Order of Merlin, Third Class, Honorary Member of the Dark
      Force Defense League and five times winner of Witch Weekly's Most- Charming-Smile Award -- But
      I don't talk about that. I didn't get rid of the Bandon Banshee by smiling at her!
        <stage>Lockhart awaits laughter. A few students smile weakly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> I see you've all bought a complete set of my books. Well done. I
      thought we'd start today with a little quiz. Nothing to worry about. Just to check how well
      you've read them, how much you've taken in... <stage>Lockhart begins to circulate papers.
        Harry and Ron examine the questions. Ron WHISPERS to Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Look at these questions. They're all about him. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> 'What is Gilderoy Lockhart's favorite color?' </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> 'What is Gilderoy Lockhart's greatest achievement to date?' </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> 'When is Gilderoy Lockhart's birthday and what would his ideal gift be?' </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> You have thirty minutes. Start -- now! <stage>As quills begin to
        dart across pages, we -- DISSOLVE TO:</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" SAME SCENE - LATER "> Lockhart rifles through the completed exams. </stage>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Tut, tut. Hardly any of you remembered my favorite color is lilac.
      But Miss Hermione Granger knew that my secret ambition is to rid the world of evil and market
      my own range of hair care potions. Good girl. <stage>Hermione beams. Lockhart's expression
        suddenly darkens.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Now... be warned! It is my job to arm you against the foulest
      creatures known to wizardkind! You may find yourself facing your own worst fears in this room.
      Know only that no harm can befall you whilst I am here... <stage>With a showman's flair,
        Lockhart turns slowly to the cage.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> I must ask you not to scream. It might provoke them. <stage>A pale
        Neville draws back. Harry and Ron lean forward. Lockhart lets the tension build, then WHIPS
        off the cover. Inside the cage are several electric blue CREATURES. Eight inches tall, with
        pointed faces and wings, they rattle the bars and pull bizarre faces at the
        students.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#SEAMUS"> Cornish pixies? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Freshly caught Cornish pixies. <stage>Unable to control himself,
        Seamus SNORTS with laughter.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Laugh if you will, Mr. Finnegan, but pixies can be devilishly
      tricky little blighters. Let's see what you make of them now! <stage>Lockhart flings open the
        cage. Instantly, the pixies rocket about, spraying the students with ink bottles, BREAKING
        BEAKERS and shredding books. Two SEIZE Neville by the ears, lift him into the air, and begin
        to circle the ceiling.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Come on now, round them up, round them up. They're only pixies.
        <stage>brandishing his wand</stage> Peskipiski Pesternomi! <stage>The spell has absolutely
        no effect. A particularly obnoxious pixie makes a face, seizes Lockhart's wand and tosses it
        out the window. Lockhart joins the stampede to the door.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> I'll ask you three to just nip the rest of them back into their
      cage. <stage>SLAMMING the door, he's gone. Harry, Ron and Hermione stand blinking. Ron swats a
        pixie gnawing his ear.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What do we do now? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE">
      <stage>raising her wand</stage> Immobilus! <stage>The pixies FREEZE IN MIDAIR. Neville falls,
        PLOPS onto Lockhart's desk, shaken but unhurt. He looks at Hermione.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Why is it always me? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" SEVENTH FLOOR - CORRIDOR - LATER "> Fresh from the pixies, Hermione,
      Ron, Harry and Neville walk. Hair askew. Robes shredded. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Can you believe him? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I'm sure Professor Lockhart just wanted to give us some hands-on
      experience. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hands on? Hermione, he didn't have a clue what he was doing. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Rubbish. Read his books. You'll see all the amazing things he's done. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> He says he's done. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS - COURTYARD - DAY "> The Gryffindor Quidditch team -- Harry,
      Fred, George, ALICIA SPINNET, KATIE BELL, and ANGELINA JOHNSON -- trail Oliver Wood through
      the courtyard, toward the distant Quidditch pitch. Several students are outside, studying. </stage>
    <sp who="#WOOD"> I spent the summer devising a whole new Quidditch program. We're going to train
      earlier, harder, and longer! <stage>squinting</stage> What the... I don't believe it!
        <stage>Crossing the courtyard from the other side are SEVEN BOYS in GREEN ROBES, also
        carrying broomsticks. At their lead is MARCUS FLINT, trollish Slytherin Captain. Ron,
        sitting at a table with Hermione, looks up.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Uh-oh. I smell trouble. </sp>
    <sp who="#WOOD"> Clear out, Flint! I booked the pitch for Gryffindor today. </sp>
    <sp who="#FLINT"> Easy, Wood. I've got a note. <stage>As Wood snatches the PARCHMENT from
        Flint's hand, Ron and Hermione come up to join the others.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#WOOD"> 'I, Professor Severus Snape, do hereby give the Slytherin team permission to
      practice today, owing to the need to train their new Seeker.' <stage>looking up</stage> You've
      got a new Seeker? Who? <stage>A pasty-faced boy pushes to the front. It's... Malfoy.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Draco? </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> That's right. And that's not all that's new this year... <stage>As one, the
        seven Slytherins hold out seven brand-new GLEAMING BROOMSTICKS. The Gryffindors look
        stunned.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Those are Nimbus Two Thousand Ones. </sp>
    <sp who="#FLINT"> A generous gift from Draco's father. </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> That's right, Weasley. You see, unlike some, my father can afford to buy the
      best. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> At least no one on the Gryffindor team had to buy their way in. They got in
      on pure talent. </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> No one asked your opinion, you filthy little Mudblood. <stage>Everyone reacts
        as if Malfoy has said something horrific -- everyone save Harry, who looks puzzled.
        Instantly, Fred and George fly for Draco's throat. Oliver Wood holds them back.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#WOOD"> Save it for the match. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> You'll pay for that one, Malfoy! <stage>whips out his wand</stage> Eat slugs!
        <stage>Ron points his cracked wand at Malfoy. PFFT! -- a BOLT of GREEN LIGHT scissors out
        the wrong end, hitting Ron himself in the stomach. As he drops to the grass, Hermione runs
        to him.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron! Say something! <stage>Ron opens his mouth and... BELCHES. Hermione
        draws back, and watches a TRIO of SLUGS dribble out his mouth. The Slytherins CROW with
        LAUGHTER. Angrily, Ron rises, only to BELCH again. Fascinated, Colin Creevey runs up with
        his camera.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#COLIN"> Wow! Can you hold him still, Harry?! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Get out of the way, Colin! <stage>to Hermione</stage> Let's take him to
      Hagrid. He'll know what to do. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HAGRID'S HUT - DAY "> Hagrid rummages about, looking for something. </stage>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Got jus' the thing. Set 'im down on that chair o'er there. <stage>As Ron
        sits, Hagrid pitches a BUCKET between his knees. Harry and Hermione glance up questioningly.
        Hagrid shrugs.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Better out than in. Who was he tryin' ter curse anyway? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Malfoy. He called Hermione, well, I don't know exactly what it means... </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE">
      <stage>quietly</stage> He called me a Mudblood. </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> He didn'! <stage>Harry looks confused. Hermione glances at him, then away,
        obviously pained by this.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It means dirty blood. Mudblood's a really foul name for someone who was
      Muggle-born. Someone with non-magic parents. Someone...like me. It's not a term one usually
      hears in civilized conversation. </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Yeh see, Harry. There are some wizards -- like Malfoy's family -- who think
      they're better than everyone else 'cause they're what people call pureblood. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> That's horrible. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>BELCHES forth a slug</stage> It's disgusting! </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> An' it's codswallop ter boot. Dirty blood. There's 'ardly a wizard today
      that's not half-blood or less. If we 'adn't married Muggles we'd've died out long ago.
      Besides, they haven't invented a spell our Hermione can't do... <stage>taking her
        shoulder</stage> Don' you think on it, Hermione. Don' you think on it fer a minute. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GILDEROY LOCKHART'S OFFICE - EVENING  HOURS LATER  "> CAMERA PANS the
      walls of Lockhart's office, lined with FRAMED PHOTOGRAPHS of... Gilderoy Lockhart. Harry and
      Lockhart work by candlelight at an ornate desk. Bleary-eyed, Harry addresses envelopes, while
      a cheery Lockhart puts his signature to the stack of GLOSSY PHOTOS bearing his image. </stage>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Harry, Harry, Harry... Can you possibly imagine a better way to
      serve detention than by helping me answer my fan mail? <stage>Harry forces a smile.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Fame's a fickle friend, Harry. Celebrity is as celebrity does.
      Remember that. <stage>Harry nods, glancing gloomily at the towering stack of envelopes that
        remain. Dipping his quill, he starts to write, when... a CHILLY VOICE fills the
        room.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#VOICE"> Come... come to me... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> What? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> I was saying, six solid months at the top of the bestseller list!
      Broke all records! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> No... not you, that... voice. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Voice? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> That... voice. Didn't you hear it? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> What are you talking about, Harry? I think we're getting a bit
      drowsy. Great Scott -- and no wonder -- look at the time! We've been here nearly four hours!
      Dinner's nearly done! If you hurry you might make pudding. Spooky how the time flies when
      one's having fun! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Spooky. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry passes quickly through the
      lengthening shadows of the empty corridor, when... </stage>
    <sp who="#VOICE"> Blood... I smell blood... <stage>Harry stops cold, looking around for the
        source of the voice.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#VOICE"> Let me rip you... let me kill you... <stage>Harry steps to the wall, playing
        his fingers along the stone, then begins walk, slowly at first, then more quickly, as if
        following something, moving faster and faster, rounding the corner and coming face to face
        with... Hermione and Ron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Did you hear it? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hear what? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> That... voice. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Voice? What voice? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>eyes darting around</stage> I heard it first in Lockhart's office and then again, just
      -- </sp>
    <sp who="#VOICE"> Kill... Time to kill... <stage>As Harry stiffens, Hermione and Ron study him
        curiously.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> It's moving. I think it's going to... kill. <stage>Harry runs off. Hermione
        and Ron exchange a glance, follow. </stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" MARBLE STAIRCASE - MOMENTS LATER "> Harry dashes madly, taking the
      steps three at a time. He makes the landing, rushes through the archway, and... </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" SECOND FLOOR CORRIDOR - SECOND FLOOR - NIGHT "> ... sleds to a stop,
      listening: Nothing. Slowly, he peers down. WATER is oozing over the stone floor, surrounding
      his shoes. His own REFLECTION appears and, behind it, undulating like a dream... WORDS. Ron
      and Hermione come huffing up. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Harry, what are you doing? <stage>He points. SHIMMERING on the wall are the
        words he saw reflected in water. THE CHAMBER OF SECRETS HAS BEEN OPENED ENEMIES OF THE
        HEIR... BEWARE.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> 'The Chamber of Secrets has been opened...?' </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What's that? Hanging underneath? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> That's Filch's cat. Mrs. Norris. <stage>The cat hangs stiffly by her tail from
        a torch bracket, eyes open and blank. Harry's eyes shift to the adjacent WINDOW: near the
        topmost pane, SPIDERS scuttle up a silvery thread, fight to get through a crack in the
        glass.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Look at that. Have you ever seen spiders act like that? Ron...? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>backing away</stage> I... don't... like... spiders. <stage>Suddenly, the stairwell is
        alive with VOICES and, seconds later, dozens of students stream forth, CHATTERING...when
        they stop, seeing the wall and, standing before it, Harry, Ron and Hermione. A thudding
        SILENCE falls. Then Draco pushes forward, eyes the wall, and grins nastily.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Enemies of the heir, beware! You'll be next, Mudbloods! <stage>Draco's eyes
        find Hermione, just as Filch appears.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#FILCH"> What's going on here? Go on now! Make way...<stage>stopping dead</stage> Mrs.
      Norris! <stage>rounding on Harry</stage> You! You've murdered my cat! I'll kill you! I'll -- </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Argus! <stage>Dumbledore marches forward, trailed by a phalanx of
        teachers. Seeing the wall, Dumbledore's face darkens.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Everyone will proceed to their dormitories immediately. <stage>to Harry,
        Ron, Hermione</stage> Everyone except you three. <stage>As the corridor empties, Dumbledore
        steps to the wall and, with extreme gentleness, removes Mrs. Norris.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> It was definitely a curse that killed her -- probably the
      Transmogrifian Torture. Encountered it myself once, in Ouagadougou. The full story's in my
      autobiography... </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> She's not dead, Argus. She's been Petrified. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Precisely! So unlucky I wasn't there. I know the very countercurse
      that could have spared her... </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> But how she's been Petrified... I cannot say. </sp>
    <sp who="#FILCH">
      <stage>pointing at Harry</stage> Ask him! It's him that's done it. You saw what he wrote on
      the wall! Besides, he knows I'm -- I'm a Squib. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> It's not true, sir! I swear! I never touched Mrs. Norris -- And I don't even
      know what a Squib is. </sp>
    <sp who="#FILCH"> Rubbish! He saw my Kwikspell letter! </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> If I might, Headmaster...The others turn, watch Snape separate from the
      shadows. </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Perhaps Potter and his friends were simply in the wrong place at the wrong
      time... <stage>Harry and the others blink. Could Snape be defending them?</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> However, the circumstances are suspicious. I, for one, don't recall seeing
      Potter at dinner. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> I'm afraid that's my doing, Severus. You see, Harry was helping me
      answer my fan mail... <stage>As Snape's lip curls in disgust, Hermione leaps in.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> That's why Ron and I went looking for him, Professor. We'd just found him
      when Harry said... </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE">
      <stage>raising an eyebrow</stage> Yes, Miss Granger? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> When I said I wasn't hungry. We were heading back to the Common Room and...
      found Mrs. Norris. <stage>Snape eyes Harry coldly, knowing he's lying. Harry looks away... and
        finds Dumbledore studying him as well.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Innocent until proven guilty. </sp>
    <sp who="#FILCH"> My cat has been Petrified! I want to see some punishment! </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> We will be able to cure her, Argus. As I understand it, Madam Sprout has
      a very healthy growth of Mandrakes. When they have matured, a potion will be made which will
      revive Mrs. Norris. In the meantime, I advise caution. To all. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - NIGHT  A BIT LATER  "> Harry, Ron and Hermione walk down the
      corridor. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> A Squib's someone who's born into a wizarding family but hasn't got any powers
      of their own. It's why Filch is trying to learn magic from a Kwikspell course. It's also why
      he hates students so much. He's bitter. <stage>Hermione, who's only been half-listening -- as
        if trying to unravel something in her mind -- speaks then.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry. This voice. You said you heard it first in Lockhart's office? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> And did he hear it? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> He said he didn't. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Maybe he was lying. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I hardly think someone with Gilderoy Lockhart's credentials would lie to
      one of his students, Ronald. Besides, if you recall, we didn't hear anything either. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You do believe me, don't you? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> 'Course we do. It's just... it's a bit weird, isn't it? You hear this voice
      and then... Mrs. Norris turns up Petrified. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I can't explain it -- it was... scary. <stage>frowning</stage> D'you think I
      should've told them -- Dumbledore and the others, I mean. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Are you mad! </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No, Harry. Even in the wizarding world, hearing voices isn't a good sign.
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" PROFESSOR McGONAGALL'S CLASSROOM - MORNING "> McGonagall stands before
      the class. Resting on the desk in front of each student, is a different animal. </stage>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Today, we will be turning animals into water goblets. <stage>She taps the
        bird in front of her, three times, with the tip of her wand. It transfigures into a
        beautiful crystal water goblet.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Now, who would like to go first... Mr. Weasley? <stage>Ron nods. He TAPS
        his rat, Scabbers, who turns into a goblet with a tail.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> You must replace that wand, Mr. Weasley. <stage>Ron nods sheepishly,
        looks at his broken wand. McGonagall sees Hermione's raised hand. Her untouched
        animal.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Yes, Miss Granger? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Professor, I was wondering if you could tell us about the Chamber of
      Secrets? <stage>A HUSH falls over the class.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> My subject is Transfiguration, Miss Granger. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Yes, Professor. But there seems to be very little written about the Chamber
      of Secrets. For those of us with a personal interest in the subject, that is... disturbing.
        <stage>Malfoy regards Hermione with chilly amusement. McGonagall considers Hermione's
        question for a long moment, then nods.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Very well. You all know, of course, that Hogwarts was founded over a
      thousand years ago by the four greatest witches and wizards of the age: Godric Gryffindor,
      Helga Hufflepuff, Rowena Ravenclaw, and Salazar Slytherin. Three of the founders co-existed
      quite harmoniously. One did not. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Three glasses who? </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Salazar Slytherin wished to be more selective about the students admitted
      to Hogwarts. He believed that magical learning should be kept within all-magic families. In
      other words, purebloods. Unable to sway the others, he decided to leave the school. <stage>a
        beat</stage> According to legend, Slytherin had built a hidden chamber in this castle, known
      as the Chamber of Secrets. Shortly before departing, he sealed it until that time when his own
      true heir returned to the school. The heir alone would be able to open the Chamber of Secrets
      and unleash the horror within, and by so doing, purge the school of all those who, in
      Slytherin's view, were unworthy to study magic. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Muggle-borns. </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Yes. Naturally, the school has been searched many times for such a
      chamber. It has never been found. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Professor, what exactly does legend tell us lies within the Chamber? </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> The Chamber is said to be home to something which the heir of Slytherin
      alone can control. It is said to be home... to a monster. <stage>Ron's eyes shift. Malfoy sits
        calmly, smiling to himself.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - DAY "> Harry, Hermione, and Ron thread their way through the
      teeming corridor. Up ahead, Malfoy walks with Crabbe and Goyle. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> D'you think it's true? D'you think there really is a Chamber of Secrets? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Yes. Couldn't you tell: McGonagall's worried. All the teachers are. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> But if there really is a Chamber of Secrets, and it's really been opened, that
      means... </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> The Heir of Slytherin has returned to Hogwarts. The question is, who is it? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>in mock puzzlement</stage> Let's think. Who do we know who thinks Muggle-borns are
      scum. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE">
      <stage>eyeing Malfoy ahead</stage> If you're talking about him -- </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Of course! You heard him: 'You'll be next, Mudbloods'! </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I heard him. But Malfoy? The Heir of Slytherin? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Maybe Ron's right, Hermione. I mean, look at his family. The whole lot of them
      have been in Slytherin for centuries. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Crabbe and Goyle must know. Maybe we could trick them into telling... </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No. Even they aren't that thick. But there might be another way. Mind you,
      it would be difficult. Not to mention we'd be breaking about fifty school rules. And it would
      be dangerous. Very dangerous. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> When do we start? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" LIBRARY - NIGHT "> In a dark nook, Harry, Ron and Hermione huddle round
      a book entitled Moste Potente Potions. The spotted pages are littered with DISTURBING
      ILLUSTRATIONS. </stage>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Here it is: 'The Polyjuice Potion. Properly brewed, the Polyjuice Potion
      allows the drinker to transform himself temporarily into the physical form of another...' </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> You mean, Harry and I drink some of this stuff and we turn into Crabbe and
      Goyle? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Yes. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Wicked! Malfoy'll tell us anything! </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Exactly. But it's tricky. I've never seen a more complicated potion.
      Lacewing flies, leeches, fluxweed. And, of course, we'll need a bit of whoever we want to
      change into too. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hang on now. I'm drinking nothing with Crabbe's toenails in it. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> How long will it take to make? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> A month. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> A month? But if Malfoy is the heir of Slytherin... he could attack half the
      Muggle-borns in the school by then. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You didn't have to tell me that. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" QUIDDITCH STADIUM - DAY "> We join the Quidditch match in mid-game. The
      CROWD ROARS, watching as Slytherin Chasers, bent low over their new brooms, jet past the
      overmatched Gryffindors. </stage>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Gallopin' Gorgons! Slytherin's flyin' like they got dragon fire in their
      brooms... <stage>Ron fumes, looking as though he takes Slytherin's dominance personally.
        Taking Hagrid's GIANT BINOCULARS, he trains them on the FACULTY BOX -- where Lucius Malfoy
        sits next to Snape.</stage>
      <stage>Harry circles high above the pitch, searching for the Golden Snitch. Suddenly, Malfoy
        streaks by overhead.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> All right there, Scarhead? <stage>Harry turns, eyes Malfoy malevolently.
        Behind him, a BLUDGER drops INTO FRAME, begins to streak toward his head.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GEORGE"> HARRY! WATCH OUT! <stage>Harry wheels and at the last possible moment, slips
        the WHISTLING Bludger. CRACK! George swoops down, BATS it away. Harry turns, watches it soar
        away, then blinks: the Bludger turns, streaks right back at him. Harry JETS OFF.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID">
      <stage>from the stands</stage> Blimey, Harry's got 'imself a Rogue Bludger! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Rogue Bludger? </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Look fer yerself! It's bin' tampered with! <stage>Harry executes a series of
        zigs, zags, loops and rolls, trying to shake the Bludger, but the Bludger is
        relentless.</stage>
      <stage>Ron instinctively draws his wand, begins to point it toward Harry and the Bludger,
        when... Hermione's hand intercedes. She glances knowingly at his fractured wand.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You're joking, right? Besides, even with a proper wand, it's too risky. You
      could hit Harry. <stage>As Harry frantically dips and dives, Malfoy cruises by.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Training for the ballet, Potter? <stage>Harry glances at Malfoy's sneering
        face. BUZZING inches above Malfoy's left ear is... the GOLDEN SNITCH. Harry CHARGES. Malfoy
        GULPS, swings clear, and watches Harry rocket past. As Harry chases the plummeting Snitch,
        Malfoy FOLLOWS IN HOT PURSUIT. They RACE DOWNWARD, trailing the HISSING SNITCH deep into the
        TRENCH circling the pitch. Shoulder to shoulder, they RACE MADLY, driving and dodging the
        wooden support beams that crisscross their path. Directly behind them, the Bludger FOLLOWS,
        SHATTERING the BEAMS as it dogs Harry. Malfoy KICKS Harry, forcing him to the edge of the
        trench. Harry BRUSHES the wall, battling for control. Malfoy turns, SNICKERS, then looks
        back... and finds himself heading smack into a wooden beam. Panicked, he tries to pull up.
        Too late. Broom meets beam and Malfoy spirals out of the trench and -- THWUMP! -- flat on
        his back in the middle of the pitch. Harry continues on, CLOSING on the Snitch, fingertips
        only inches from catching it... when... the Rogue Bludger SMASHES INTO Harry's arm. Harry
        cries out, steadies himself and with a brilliant, acrobatic move, SNATCHES the Snitch out of
        the air with his good hand. Unable to control his broom with his shattered arm, he hits the
        pitch with a SICKENING THUD. Wincing, Harry rolls onto his shoulders, SQUINTS UP: a BLACK
        DOT -- growing rapidly LARGER -- is plummeting from the sky, directly toward him. It's...
        the rogue Bludger. Instantly, Harry spins away, grimacing in agony, as the Bludger...hits
        the ground like a SLEDGE HAMMER, violently TATTOOING the pitch again and again, only inches
        from Harry. Calmly, Hermione strides forth, points her wand.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Finite Incantatem! <stage>The Bludger hangs briefly in the air. Slowly
        ceases spinning. Drops heavily to the pitch. Harry exhales, relieved, only to recall the
        searing pain in his arm. As CONCERNED FACES swim above him, one particular face pushes
        through the others: </stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Not to worry, Harry. I'll fix that arm of yours straight away. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> No... no... not you. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Poor boy doesn't know what he's saying. This won't hurt a bit...
        <stage>Lockhart TWIRLS his WAND, Harry braces himself, and... nothing. He blinks, looks up:
        the faces -- which now include Ron, Hermione, and Hagrid -- look horror- stricken. </stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Ah. Yes. Well, that can sometimes happen. The point is, the bones
      are no longer broken. </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Brok'n? He doesn't 'ave any bones at all! <stage>Harry looks: his arm looks
        like an empty rubber glove.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HOSPITAL WING - DAY "> A dazed Malfoy slumps out with Crabbe and Goyle.
      Ron, standing by Harry's bed with Hermione, grins, then watches MADAM POMFREY pour out a
      STEAMING BEAKERFUL OF LIQUID from a bottle of SKELE-GRO. A group of Gryffindors, including
      some of his teammates, stand nearby. </stage>
    <sp who="#MADAMPOMFREY"> He should have been brought straight to me! I can mend bones in a
      heartbeat -- but growing them back -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You will be able to, won't you? </sp>
    <sp who="#MADAMPOMFREY"> I'll be able to, certainly, but it will be painful. You're in for a
      rough night, Potter. Regrowing bones is nasty business. <stage>Harry takes the steaming cup
        and drinks. Grimaces.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MADAMPOMFREY"> Well, what did you expect -- pumpkin juice? <stage>FLASH! Harry blinks,
        sees Colin Creevey standing there.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#COLIN"> That was brilliant today, Harry! Brilliant! </sp>
    <sp who="#MADAMPOMFREY"> Out! All of you! This boy's got thirty-three bones to regrow! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HOSPITAL WING - NIGHT "> Harry fidgets in the darkness, half-asleep,
      then... his eyelids flutter slowly open... HARRY'S MOVING POV From the shadows that cling to
      the ceiling... to the lattice-work of moonlight that burns softly on the walls around him...
      BACK TO SCENE He SENSES something... a presence... when... Five BANDAGED FINGERS ENTER FRAME,
      begin to SPONGE his brow. Harry bolts upright, finds... </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Dobby! </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Harry Potter came back to school. Dobby warned him. Harry Potter should have
      listened to Dobby. Harry Potter should have gone back home when he missed the train. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>pushing the sponge away</stage> It was you! You stopped the barrier from letting Ron
      and me through! </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Indeed yes, sir. Dobby hid and watched for Harry Potter and sealed the
      gateway. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You nearly got Ron and me expelled! </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> At least you would be away from here. Harry Potter must go home! Dobby thought
      his Bludger would be enough to make Harry Potter see -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Your Bludger? You made that Bludger chase after me? </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby feels most aggrieved, sir. <stage>waggling his fingers</stage> Dobby had
      to iron his hands... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You'd better clear off before my bones come back, Dobby, or I might strangle
      you! </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY">
      <stage>smiling weakly</stage> Dobby is used to death threats, sir. Dobby gets them five times
      a day at home. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I don't suppose you could tell me why you're trying to kill me? </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Not kill you, sir, never kill you! Dobby remembers how it was before Harry
      Potter triumphed over He Who Must Not Be Named. We house elves were treated like vermin, sir.
      Of course, Dobby is still treated like vermin... <stage>Dobby HONKS his nose on the filthy
        pillowcase he wears.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Why do you wear that thing, Dobby? </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> This, sir? 'Tis a mark of the house elf's enslavement. Dobby can only be freed
      if his master presents him with clothes. The family is careful not to pass Dobby so much as a
      sock, sir, for then he would be free to leave their house forever. <stage>Dobby's ears QUIVER,
        detecting... FOOTSTEPS. He WHISPERS.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Terrible things are about to happen at Hogwarts! Harry Potter must not stay
      here now that history is to repeat itself! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Repeat itself? You mean, this has happened before? <stage>Dobby seizes the
        Skele-Gro, BEATS himself about the head.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Tell me, Dobby? When did this happen before? Who's doing it now? </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby cannot say, sir. Dobby only wants Harry Potter to be safe. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Who is it? No, Dobby! Tell me! <stage>CRACK! Dobby is gone. SHADOWS flicker
        beyond the CURTAIN encircling Harry's bed. Harry slumps down... peers through a slit in the
        curtains. Dumbledore, in a nightcap, and McGonagall, in a tartan robe, heave a SMALL STATUE
        onto an empty bed. Seconds later, Madam Pomfrey bustles in.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MADAMPOMFREY"> What's happened? </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> There's been another attack. <stage>Madam Pomfrey GASPS. It is not a
        statue lying there. It is Colin Creevey, CAMERA still clutched to his eye.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Perhaps he managed to get a picture of his attacker... <stage>Dumbledore
        opens the camera. A JET OF STEAM HISSES forth.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> What does this mean, Albus? </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> It means our students are in great danger, Minerva. Mr. Creevey was
      fortunate. If not for this... <stage>holding up the camera</stage> He would surely be dead. </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> What should I tell the staff, Albus? </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Tell them the truth. Tell them Hogwarts is no longer safe. Tell them it's
      as we feared. The Chamber of Secrets is indeed open again. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" GIRLS BATHROOM "> We PAN SLOWLY FROM the defiled wall to the bathroom
      door. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GIRLS BATHROOM - DAY "> A gloomy place. Cracked mirrors. Chipped sinks.
      Guttering candles. Harry and Ron huddle over a SMALL, BUBBLING CAULDRON, as Hermione adds
      STRANGE INGREDIENTS. </stage>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Again? You mean, the Chamber of Secrets has been opened before? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Of course! Don't you see? Lucius Malfoy must've opened it when he was at school
      here, and now he's told Draco how to do it. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Maybe. We'll have to wait for the Polyjuice Potion to know for sure. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Enlighten me. Why are we brewing this potion in broad daylight, in the middle of
      a girls' lavatory? Don't you think we'll get caught? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Never. No one over comes in here. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Why? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Moaning Myrtle. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Who's Moaning Myrtle? <stage>There is a LOUD, PIERCING SCREECH, and the GHOST OF
        A YOUNG GIRL COMES RACING OUT OF THE WALL. FACE TO FACE with Ron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> I'm Moaning Myrtle. I wouldn't expect you to know me. Who would ever
      talk about fat, ugly, miserable, moping, moaning Myrtle? <stage>Myrtle SOBS LOUDLY, DIVES head
        first into the toilet.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> She's a little sensitive. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - DAY "> NOTICE-BOARD: DUELING CLUB! First Meeting Tonight.
      A GOLDEN STAGE has been erected. Lockhart struts atop it. Harry, Ron, Hermione and good number
      of other students watch. </stage>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Gather round! Gather round! Can everyone see me? Can you all hear
      me? Excellent. In light of the dark events of recent weeks, Professor Dumbledore has granted
      me permission to start this little Dueling Club, to train you all up in case you ever need to
      defend yourselves as I myself have done on countless occasions -- for full details, see my
      published works. <stage>The boy next to Harry, JUSTIN-FINCH FLETCHLEY, turns to him.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#JUSTINFINCH">-FLETCHLEY That Lockhart's something, isn't he? Awfully brave chap.
        <stage>offering his hand</stage> Justin Finch-Fletchley. Hufflepuff. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Nice to meet you. I'm -- </sp>
    <sp who="#JUSTINFINCH">-FLETCHLEY I know who you are. We all do. Even us Muggle-borns.
        <stage>Justin grins agreeably, looks back to the stage, where Professor Snape has joined
        Lockhart.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Let me introduce my assistant Professor Snape. He has sportingly
      agreed to help me with a short demonstration. Now I don't want any of you youngsters to worry.
      You'll still have your Potions Master when I'm through with him, never fear! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What's the fun in that? <stage>Lockhart and Snape face each other and bow. They
        turn, walk ten paces, then... SPIN... wands poised like swords.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> As you can see, we are holding our wands in the accepted combative
      position. On the count of three, we will cast our first spells. Neither of us will be aiming
      to kill, of course. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>eyeing Snape</stage> I wouldn't bet on that. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> One-two-three -- </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Expelliarmus! <stage>A dazzling flash of SCARLET LIGHT bursts forth and BLASTS
        Lockhart off his feet and into the wall behind.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Do you think he's all right? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> Who cares? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART">
      <stage>rising unsteadily</stage> Well, there you have it. That was a Disarming Charm. As you
      see, I've lost my wand. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART">
      <stage>as Hermione returns it</stage> Ah, thank you, Miss Granger. Yes, an excellent idea to
      show them that, Professor Snape, but if you don't mind my saying so, it was very obvious what
      you were about to do. If I had wanted to stop you it would have been only too easy... </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Perhaps it would be prudent to first teach the students to block unfriendly
      spells, Professor. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> An excellent suggestion, Professor Snape. Let's have a volunteer
      pair. Potter, Weasley, how about you? </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Weasley's wand causes devastation with the simplest spells. We'll be sending
      Potter to the hospital wing in a matchbox. Might I suggest someone from my own house. Malfoy,
      perhaps. <stage>Malfoy and Harry eye each other malevolently as they take their places
        onstage. Grudgingly, they bow to each other.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Scared, Potter? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You wish. <stage>They turn, walk ten paces, then WHIRL, wands poised.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Wands at the ready! When I count to three, cast your charms to
      disarm your opponent -- only to disarm. We don't want any accidents. One, two -- <stage>Malfoy
        FIRES early, knocking Harry off his feet with a BLAST of WHITE LIGHT. He jumps up, points
        his wand.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Rictusempra! <stage>A jet of SILVER LIGHT hits Malfoy dead in the stomach. He
        doubles up, WHEEZING.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> I said disarm only! </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Serpensortia! <stage>To Harry's horror, the tip of Malfoy's wand EXPLODES and
        a LONG BLACK SNAKE SLITHERS forth. Snape smiles with amusement.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Don't move, Potter. I'll get rid of it for you. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Allow me! <stage>Lockhart flicks his wand. BANG! The SNAKE flies
        into the air, HISSES in rage, and slithers straight towards Justin Finch-Fletchley. As
        students SCREAM, Harry -- oddly calm -- approaches the snake. It rises, fangs exposed,
        poised to strike Justin.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>in Parseltongue</stage> Leave him! <stage>The snake looks into Harry's eyes, then turns
        for Justin.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>in Parseltongue</stage> LEAVE HIM! <stage>The snake hovers a moment more, then --
        miraculously -- slumps to the floor. Harry blinks, as if coming out of a trance, grins
        curiously at the snake, and offers his hand to Justin.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#JUSTIN">-FINCH-FLETCHLEY What are you playing at? <stage>Terrified, Justin backs away.
        Confused, Harry eyes the faces around him. Malfoy looks shocked. Seamus and Neville's eyes
        glitter with fear. Ginny bolts the room. Snape waves his wand and the snake VANISHES in PUFF
        OF BLACK SMOKE, then regards Harry with a look that is both shrewd and calculating.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>taking Harry's arm</stage> Come on. Move. Now. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GRYFFINDOR COMMON ROOM - DAY  LATER  "> Ron and Hermione usher Harry
      inside. Harry glances up, sees Ginny Weasley staring down at him from the top of the stairs.
      As their eyes meet, she turns for the girls' dormitory. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> You're a Parselmouth! Why didn't you tell us? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I'm a what? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You can talk to snakes. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I know. I mean, I accidentally set a python on my cousin Dudley at the zoo
      once. But so what? I bet loads of people here can do it. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No. They can't. It's not a very common gift, Harry. This is bad. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> What's bad? If I hadn't told that snake not to attack Justin -- </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Oh, that's what you said to it. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You were there! You heard me! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> I heard you speaking Parseltongue. Snake language. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I spoke a different language? But I didn't realize -- how can I speak a
      language without knowing I can? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I don't know, Harry. But it sounded like you were egging the snake on or
      something. It was... creepy. <stage>As Gryffindors stream into the room, they eye Harry
        warily. Even Seamus, Neville, and Dean Thomas walk by without a word.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, listen out me. There's a reason the symbol of Slytherin house is a
      serpent. Salazar Slytherin was a Parselmouth. He could talk to snakes too. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Exactly. And now the whole school's going to think you're his great-great-great
      grandson or something. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> But I'm not. I... can't be. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> He lived a thousand years ago. For all we know... you could be. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS' LANDSCAPE - DAY "> A heavy snow falls. Harry sits atop one of
      the towering hills facing Hogwarts. Hedwig sits beside him. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Who am I, Hedwig? What am I? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" LIBRARY - NIGHT "> The trio study. Harry, burdened by dark thoughts,
      looks up at Ron. He smiles at Harry, then, seconds later, Hermione does the same -- something
      forced about it all. Unable to bear it, Harry gathers his books, gets up from the table. As
      Harry walks, students glance up, meet his gaze, then look away. Even MADAM PINCE eyes him from
      her desk. Ginny Weasley, tired and pale, scribbles furiously in a SMALL BLACK BOOK. Harry
      exits, walks into the hallway and pauses. From inside a room, the VOICES of a group of
      Hufflepuffs can be heard. </stage>
    <sp who="#ERNIE"> So, anyway, I told Justin to hide up in our dormitory. I mean to say, if
      Potter's marked him down as his next victim, it's best he keep a low profile for a while. </sp>
    <sp who="#HANNAH"> But why would he want to attack Justin? </sp>
    <sp who="#ERNIE"> Justin let it slip to Potter that he was Muggle-born. </sp>
    <sp who="#HANNAH"> And you definitely think Potter's the Heir of Slytherin? </sp>
    <sp who="#ERNIE"> Hannah, he's a Parselmouth. Everyone knows that's the mark of a dark wizard.
      Have you ever heard of a decent one who could talk to snakes? They called Slytherin himself
      Serpent-tongue. <stage>whispering darkly</stage> Remember what was written on the wall:
      Enemies of the Heir Beware. Potter had some sort of run-in with Filch. Next thing we know,
      Filch's cat's attacked. That first-year Creevey's been annoying Potter. Then Creevey's
      attacked. </sp>
    <sp who="#HANNAH"> He always seems so nice, though. And, after all, he is the one who made You
      Know Who disappear. </sp>
    <sp who="#ERNIE"> That's probably why You Know Who wanted to kill him in the first place. Didn't
      want another Dark Lord competing with him. <stage>Harry doesn't need to hear anymore. He slips
        quietly away.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> MUTTERING, Harry storms straight
      into Hagrid, who stands covered in snow, a DEAD ROOSTER dangling from his hand. </stage>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> All righ', Harry? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hagrid... what're you doing here? </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID">
      <stage>holding up the rooster</stage> Second one killed this term. Reckon it's either foxes or
      a Blood-Suckin' Bugbear. Need Dumbledore's permission ter put a charm round the hen-coop. Yeh
      sure yeh're all righ', Harry? Yeh look all hot an' bothered. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> It's nothing. I'd better get going. I've got a lot of studying... </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" ANOTHER CORRIDOR - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry enters, slows. Up
      ahead, in the light of a FLICKERING TORCH, something DARK lies. A WINDOWPANE RATTLES in the
      WIND and the torch... goes out. Harry steps closer, finds... Justin-Finch-Fletchley. Lying
      rigid on the floor, a look of shock on his frozen face. Nearby, an inert Nearly Headless Nick
      floats, body teeming with BLACK SMOKE. Kneeling, Harry notices a TRAIL OF SPIDERS scuttling
      away from Justin's body and out the loose windowpane... when suddenly... ... Harry senses
      someone watching him, wheels: McGonagall. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Professor, I swear I didn't -- </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> This is out of my hands, Potter. Mr. Filch, will you take care of this,
      please? <stage>Harry's eyes shift. Filch lurks in the shadows beyond McGonagall. He steps
        forward, HISSES QUIETLY.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#FILCH"> Caught in the act. I'll have you out this time, Potter. Mark my words...
        <stage>As McGonagall leads Harry away, he looks back. Filch stares at Justin and Nick, then
        turns. CAMERA DOLLYS AWAY FROM HIM.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#FILCH"> Dark magic. That's what you've got, Potter. Even the air you breathe comes out
      poison. You're evil. Evil as they come... </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GARGOYLE CORRIDOR - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> McGonagall marches Harry
      down to an UGLY STONE GARGOYLE. </stage>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Sherbet lemon. <stage>The Gargoyle SPRINGS TO LIFE, its wings
        opening.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Professor Dumbledore will be waiting for you. <stage>McGonagall ushers
        Harry inside. It's an elevator. The Gargoyle's wings close. Harry rises to an upper
        floor.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" DUMBLEDORE'S OFFICE - NIGHT "> Harry steps out of the Gargoyle's
      embrace and enters a large, circular room. STRANGE SILVER INSTRUMENTS WHIR quietly. On a
      nearby shelf, the SORTING HAT sits. Harry casts a wary eye at the PAST HEADMASTERS snoozing in
      the PORTRAITS around him. In the last portrait, the Headmaster is awake, reading a book. He is
      PROFESSOR DIPPET. Harry approaches the Sorting Hat, glances around, then places it atop his
      head. </stage>
    <sp who="#SORTINGHAT"> Bee in your bonnet, Potter? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Well, you see, I was wondering... </sp>
    <sp who="#SORTINGHAT"> If I put you in the right house? Yes...you were particularly difficult to
      place. But I stand by what I said last year... you would have done well in Slytherin.
        <stage>Harry strips the hat off, tosses it back onto the shelf.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You're wrong! <stage>The hat sits motionless. Silent. Hearing a GAGGING SOUND,
        Harry wheels, finds an OLD, DECREPIT BIRD (FAWKES) sitting on a GOLDEN PERCH. It wobbles,
        then... BURSTS INTO FLAMES. As Dumbledore enters, Harry looks horror- struck.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Professor, your bird... I couldn't do anything... He just caught fire. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> About time too. He's been looking dreadful for days. Pity you had to see
      him on a Burning Day. He's really very handsome most of the time. <stage>off Harry's
        look</stage> Fawkes is a phoenix, Harry. Phoenixes burst into flame when it is time for them
      to die and are reborn from the ashes. <stage>Harry looks to the floor. The ASHES swirl. A baby
        Fawkes pokes out his wrinkled head, blinking through the dust.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Fascinating creatures, phoenixes. They can carry immensely heavy loads,
      their tears have healing powers, and they make highly faithful pets. <stage>Just then, Hagrid
        -- still clutching the dead rooster -- BURSTS through the door.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> It wasn't Harry, Professor Dumbledore! </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Hagrid -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> I was talkin' ter 'im jus' before that kid was found. It can't've bin 'im! </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Hagrid -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> I'll swear ter it in front o' the Ministry o' Magic -- </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> HAGRID! I do not think that Harry has attacked anyone. </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Oh. Right. I'll wait outside then. <stage>s Hagrid exits, Harry looks
        hopefully at Dumbledore.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You don't think it was me, Professor? </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> No, Harry. But I must ask you... is there anything you'd like to tell me.
      Anything at all? <stage>Dumbledore waits. Harry debates. Finally...</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> No, Professor. Nothing. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS CASTLE - DAY "> Students drift into the snow with their
      trunks, heading home for holiday. As Harry, Ron, and Hermione appear, Ernie and few others
      cast wary glances. </stage>
    <sp who="#FRED"> Make way for the Heir of Slytherin! Seriously evil wizard coming through!
        <stage>Ron grins, amused, then sees Harry -- anything but.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Oh, c'mon, Harry. Fred's just having a laugh. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> He's the only one. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Okay, so half the school thinks you're nipping off to the Chamber of Secrets
      every night. Who cares? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Maybe they're right. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE">
      <stage>reproachfully</stage> Harry! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>frustrated</stage> I didn't know I could speak Parseltongue. What else don't I know
      about myself? Maybe you can do something... even something horrible... and not know you did
      it. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You don't believe that, Harry, I know you don't. And if it makes you feel
      better, I just heard Malfoy's staying over for holiday, too. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Why would that make anyone feel better? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Because, in a few days, the Polyjuice Potion's will be ready. In a few
      days... we may truly know who is the Heir of Slytherin. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - NIGHT "> The Christmas Feast. The Hall glimmers grandly as
      snowflakes tumble from the ceiling. Harry and Ron sit with Hermione. </stage>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Everything's set. We just need a bit of who you're changing into. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Crabbe and Goyle. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> And we also need to make sure that the real Crabbe and Goyle can't burst in
      on us while we're interrogating Malfoy. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> How? <stage>Hermione holds up a pair of SMALL CAKES.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I've got it all worked out. I've filled these with a simple Sleeping
      Draught. Simple, but powerful. <stage>Ron glances at Malfoy, Crabbe, and Goyle, who presently
        are eating everything in front of them.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You know how greedy Crabbe and Goyle are. They won't leave the Christmas
      Feast until every last drop of trifle is gone. Now, once they're asleep, hide them in a broom
      cupboard and pull out a few of their hairs. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> And whose hair are you ripping out? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I've already got mine. <stage>She removes a SMALL VIAL. Inside is a TINY
        HAIR.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Millicent Bulstrode. She's in Slytherin. I got this off her robes.
        <stage>rising</stage> All right then... I'm going to check on the Polyjuice Potion.
        <stage>Hermione points to the cakes in front of her.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Remember. Just make sure Crabbe and Goyle find these. <stage>Hermione
        exits. Ron looks at Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Have you ever heard of a plan where so many things could go wrong? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" ENTRANCE HALL - NIGHT  A BIT LATER  "> Harry and Ron, lurking behind a
      SUIT OF ARMOR, watch Crabbe and Goyle exit the Great Hall. Goyle spies the cakes instantly,
      perched on the end of one of the banisters. Grabbing them, he reluctantly surrenders one to
      Crabbe and, in unison, they stuff them into their mouths. They pause. Look at each other. And
      keel flat onto their backs. Harry and Ron dash out, drag Crabbe and Goyle across the floor and
      into a cupboard. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GIRLS' BATHROOM - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Hermione, wearing a
      Slytherin robe, hovers over a smoking cauldron. Harry and Ron enter. </stage>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Did you get it? <stage>Harry and Ron hold up their hands. In each: a TUFT
        OF HAIR. Hermione points to a pair of SLYTHERIN ROBES.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I sneaked those out of the laundry. <stage>Harry and Ron nod, glance at the
        cauldron. The potion resembles a thick, dark, bubbling mud.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I'm sure I've done everything right. It looks like the book said it should.
      Once we've drunk it, we'll have exactly one hour before we change back into ourselves. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Now what? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We separate it into three glasses and add the hairs. <stage>Harry and Ron
        grimace.</stage>
    </sp>

    <stage>CUT TO: CLOSEUP - THE POTION being poured into three glasses. CAMERA PULLS BACK. Harry
      and Ron have changed into the Slytherin robes. All three raise their glasses. Drop the hairs.
      The potion turns shades of YELLOW, BROWN, and KHAKI. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Ugh. Essence of Crabbe... <stage>They nod. DRINK. Ron swallows grimly, doubles
        over.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Think I'm gonna be sick... <stage>He runs into a stall. Harry looks sick, steps
        to a CRACKED MIRROR. Hermione pauses. Looks worried. Something's wrong... INSIDE THE STALL:
        Ron bends over the toilet, watches his reflection morph into Crabbe. IN THE CRACKED MIRROR:
        Harry watches his face contort into the thick features of Goyle. Hermione looks at her arm.
        Patches of fur begin to spread across her wrist and hand. Terrified, she RUNS into a stall.
        Ron emerges from his stall, a dead ringer for Crabbe.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Harry? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> We still sound like ourselves. You need to sound more like Crabbe. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>adjusts voice</stage> Bloody hell. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Lower. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>lower still</stage> Bloody hell. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Less intelligent. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>dumbing it down</stage> Bloody hell. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Excellent. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hey... Where's Hermione? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE">
      <stage>O.S.</stage>
      <stage>from the stall</stage> I -- I don't think I'm going. You go on without me. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione, are you okay? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> Just go! You're wasting time! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" MARBLE STAIRCASE - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry and Ron hurry down
      the staircase. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Don't swing your arms like that. Crabbe holds them sort of stiff. <stage>Harry
        goes a bit more "Neanderthal."</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Yeah. That's better. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GLOOMY CORRIDOR/DUNGEONS - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry and Ron move
      quickly, when... FOOTSTEPS sound. Seconds later, Percy appears at the end of the corridor. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> What are you doing here? <stage>Percy squints, confused by Ron's voice. Harry
        elbows Ron, who clears his throat and speaks in a lower voice.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What are you doing here? </sp>
    <sp who="#PERCY"> I happen to be a prefect. You, on the other hand, have no business wandering
      the corridors at night. It's not safe these days. <stage>Harry and Ron NOD, afraid to speak.
        Percy squints again.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#PERCY"> What're your names again? </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Crabbe. Goyle. Where have you been? Pigging out in the Great Hall all this
      time? <stage>Draco is walking towards them, glances witheringly at Percy.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> And what are you doing down here, Weasley? </sp>
    <sp who="#PERCY"> Mind your attitude, Malfoy. You want to show a little bit more respect to a
      school Prefect! </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Come on, boys. Weasley thinks he's going to catch Slytherin's hair
      single-handed. <stage>Percy steams. Draco sneers, walks off with Harry and Ron.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" SLYTHERIN COMMON ROOM - NIGHT  LATER  "> Harry and Ron trail Draco
      inside, glance around warily. </stage>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Listen to this... <stage>Draco grabs The Daily Prophet, reads the front
        page.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> 'Arthur Weasley, Head of the Misuse of Muggle Artefacts Office, was today
      fined fifty Galleons for bewitching a Muggle car. "Weasley has brought the Ministry into
      disrepute," said Lucius Malfoy, a governor of Hogwarts. "He is clearly unfit to draw up our
      laws and his ridiculous Muggle Protection Act should be scrapped immediately."'
        <stage>Grinning, Malfoy glances over the paper at Harry and Ron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Arthur Weasley loves Muggle so much he should snap his wand in half and go
      join them. You'd never know the Weasleys were purebloods, the way they behave. Embarrassment
      to the wizarding world. All of them. <stage>Ron growls. Harry elbows him. Draco looks
        surprised.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> What's up with you, Crabbe? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>low voice</stage> Stomachache. </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Well, go to the hospital wing and give all those Mudbloods a kick in the arse
      for me! You know, I'm surprised The Daily Prophet hasn't reported all these attacks yet. I
      suppose Dumbledore's trying to hush it all up. He'll be sacked if it doesn't stop soon. Father
      always said Dumbledore's the worst thing that's ever happened to this place. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You're wrong! </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> What? Did you say that I was wrong? You think there's someone here who's worse
      than Dumbledore? <stage>Ron stiffens. Worried. Harry thinks, then:</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Harry Potter. </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO">
      <stage>grinning</stage> Good one, Goyle. You're absolutely right. Saint Potter. He's another
      one with no proper wizard feeling, or he wouldn't go around with that Mudblood Granger. And
      people actually think he's the Heir of Slytherin. <stage>Harry and Ron exchange a glance.
        Harry leans closer to Draco.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Then you must have some idea who's behind it all? </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> You know I haven't, Goyle. How many times do I have to tell you? But my father
      did say this much: It's been fifty years since the Chamber was opened. He wouldn't tell me who
      opened it -- only that they were expelled -- but I know this: the last time the Chamber of
      Secrets was opened, a Mudblood died. </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> So it's only a matter of time before one of them's killed this time. As for
      me... I hope it's Granger. <stage>As Malfoy grins, Ron's fist rises... when Harry stops
        him.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> What's the matter with you two? You're acting very... odd. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Ho! <stage>Harry turns, sees Ron staring wide-eyed: Harry's SCAR is beginning to
        surface beneath the skin of Goyle's thick forehead. And Crabbe's hair is... turning RED.
        They both JUMP to their feet, DASHING out of the room.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO"> Hey! Where are you going? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" ENTRANCE HALL - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> As Harry and Ron race toward
      the stairs, the BROOM CLOSET bursts open and a woozy Crabbe and Goyle stagger out. They freeze
      -- watch themselves run up the staircase. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" SECOND FLOOR CORRIDOR - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry and Ron sprint
      toward the desecrated wall, their bodies metamorphosing, until, finally, as they hit the
      door... </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GIRLS BATHROOM - NIGHT "> ... They are fully themselves once more. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> That was close! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione, come out. We've got loads to tell you! </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Go away! <stage>As Harry and Ron exchange a puzzled glance, Moaning Myrtle
        spirals INTO VIEW, looking disturbingly... happy.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> Ooh, wait till you see. It's awful! <stage>The stall's lock slides
        back. The door opens slowly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> Do you remember me telling you the Polyjuice Potion was only for human
      transformations...? <stage>Even in shadow, they can see: Hermione's face is covered in FUR,
        her eyes YELLOW, and POINTED EARS poke through her hair.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It was cat hair I plucked off Millicent Bulstrode's robes! Look at my face! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Look at your tail. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HOSPITAL WING - DAY  TWO WEEKS LATER  "> Staggering under the weight of
      the LIBRARY BOOKS in their arms, Harry and Ron make their way to Hermione's bed, which is
      covered in... BOOKS. </stage>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Oh, good. Put those anywhere. <stage>They look. There is no anywhere. So
        they just... drop them.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Madam Pince asked that we relay a message to you, Hermione: She'd appreciate it
      if you'd leave a few books for the rest of the school. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I've got to keep up, haven't I? <stage>Just then, Hermione's tail twitches
        INTO VIEW.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Is that thing ever going away? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Any day now, according to Madam Pomfrey. I'm just thankful I've stopped
      coughing up fur balls. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> We all are, believe me. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Now. What about the Chamber of Secrets? Any new leads? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Nothing. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> And has it gotten any better? I mean... is anyone speaking to you? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Neville asked to borrow a tubeworm in Potions yesterday. I suppose that's
      something. <stage>Ron takes a GET-WELL CARD from under Hermione's pillow.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> 'To Miss Granger. Wishing you a speedy recovery, from your concerned teacher
      Gilderoy Lockhart.' You sleep with this under your pillow? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Of course not. I don't know how that got there. Now go. I still have six
      hundred pages to read in Transformation Through the Ages. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" SECOND-FLOOR CORRIDOR - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry and Ron mount
      the stairs, emerge. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> I know Hermione's mental, but can you believe she falls for that smarmy nonsense
      of Lockhart's? <stage>They stop. Look down. A GREAT FLOOD OF WATER streams from the Girls'
        Bathroom. From within, MYRTLE can be heard MOANING.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Looks like Myrtle's flooded the bathroom. <stage>As Harry sploshes off toward
        the bathroom, Ron steps lightly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Yuck. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GIRLS BATHROOM - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> HUGE, WRACKING MOANS echo off
      the dreary tile. All the taps are running, streaming like tiny waterfalls. As Harry and Ron
      step to the last cubicle, Myrtle spins accusingly. </stage>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> Come to throw something else at me? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Why would I throw something at you? </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> Don't ask me. Here I am, minding my own business, and someone thinks
      it's funny to throw a book at me... </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> But it can't hurt if someone throws something at you. I mean, it'd just go right
      through you, wouldn't it? </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> Oh sure! Let's all throw books at Myrtle, because she can't feel it!
      Ten points if you can get it through her stomach. Fifty points if it goes through her head! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Who threw it at you anyway? </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> I don't know. I didn't see them. I was just sitting in the U-bend,
      thinking about death and it fell through the top of my head. <stage>Harry sees a SMALL BLACK
        BOOK on the floor. Picks it up.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Fifty points if you can get it through her nose. </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> I HEARD THAT! <stage>Harry and Ron dash out.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry examines the book as he and
      Ron walk. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> This is a diary. And it's old... </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> It's a diary, it's old... and was most recently in a toilet, Harry. <stage>Harry
        starts to open it... when Ron grabs his hand.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Are you mad? That could be cursed. Dad once told me about a book the Ministry
      confiscated that burned the eyes out of anyone who tried to read it. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I'll take my chances... <stage>opening it</stage> Ahhh! MY EYES! MY EYES!
        <stage>Ron freezes, terrified, when... Harry grins, ending the ruse. At the end of corridor,
        Ginny stands, looking from the diary to Harry -- utter terror on her face -- then dashes
        off.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Ginny! I was only joking -- Brilliant. Even your sister thinks I'm the monster
      now. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Who doesn't? <stage>Ron frowns suddenly. On the first page on the diary,
        EMBOSSED LETTERS spell out a name: TOM MARVOLO RIDDLE.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Tom Marvolo Riddle? Hang on. I know that name... <stage>thinking, then</stage>
      Of course! The night I had detention... My job was to polish the silver in the trophy room. I
      remember because I kept burping slugs all over Tom Riddle's trophy. I must have wiped slime
      off his name for an hour. <stage>Harry fans the pages. They're empty.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> That's odd. He never wrote in it. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HOSPITAL WING - LATER THAT NIGHT "> CLOSEUP: DIARY. A GOLD EMBOSSED
      ADDRESS on the back reads: WAXFLATTER'S BOOKSELLERS. 422 VAUXHALL ROAD. CAMERA PULLS BACK.
      Harry sits with Hermione in the moonlit room. Hermione studies the diary curiously. </stage>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Tom Riddle... Hm. And Ron said he won an award fifty years ago? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Special Services to the School or something -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Fifty years ago? You're sure? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. Why? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Don't you remember what Malfoy told you? The last time the Chamber of
      Secrets was opened was -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Fifty years ago! That means -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Tom Riddle was here, at Hogwarts, when it happened. What if he wrote about
      what he saw? It's possible he knew where the Chamber was, how to open it, even what sort of
      creature lives in it. If so, whoever's behind the attacks this time wouldn't want a diary like
      this lying around, would they? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> That's a brilliant theory, Hermione. With just one tiny little flaw. There's
      nothing written in this diary. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It might be invisible ink. <stage>pulls out her wand</stage> Aparecium!
        <stage>She taps the diary three times. Nothing happens. The pages remain BLANK. She frowns,
        passes the book back to Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I don't know, Harry. But I think you should be careful with this. Something
      tells me Ron might be right. It could be dangerous. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You don't think I'm dangerous, do you, Hermione? I mean, you're not scared. Of
      me. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I'm scared, Harry. But not of you. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GRYFFINDOR DORMITORY/COMMON ROOM - NIGHT  LATER  "> CAMERA STARTS
      OVERHEAD, looking down on the boys' dormitory. Seamus, Neville, Ron and Dean sleep. One bed is
      empty. CAMERA CRANES TO the Common Room, finds Harry sitting alone, flipping through the blank
      pages of the diary. Harry starts to set the diary aside, then notices a BOTTLE OF INK sitting
      on the desk. An idea flickers. Taking his QUILL, Harry dips it, and hesitates. As he does, a
      DROP of INK hangs, suspended like a tear, then... DROPS. The ink BLAZES briefly, then...
      VANISHES... as if it were sucked into the page. Excited, Harry dips his quill again, and, this
      time, writes: My name is Harry Potter. The words blaze, VANISH. Slowly, oozing out of the
      page, comes a response: Hello, Harry Potter. My name is Tom Riddle. Harry's mind races.
      Deciding, he MUTTERS the words he writes: </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Do... you... know... anything... about... the... Chamber... of... Secrets?
        <stage>Yes.</stage>
    </sp>

    <sp who="#HARRY"> Can... you... tell... me? <stage>No.</stage>
      <stage>Harry frowns. Then... slowly... new words ooze to the surface. But I can show
        you...</stage>
      <stage>Harry waits, intrigued. Then, suddenly... The pages FLUTTER WILDLY, stop on "June the
        13th." On the page, a TINY SQUARE SHIMMERS... like a WINDOW. Harry lifts the book, puts his
        eye close and... PITCHES FORWARD, spilling through the widening window, into a WHIRL of
        COLOR and SHADOW, tumbling onto his feet...</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR/ENTRANCE HALL - NIGHT  FIFTY YEARS AGO"> ... in torch-lit
      corridor. Everything is de-saturated, save for Harry, who retains the true, rich colors of the
      present. He glances about, disoriented, then spies a BOY (TOM RIDDLE) at the end
      of the corridor, peering around a corner. A FLURRY of SHADOWS dances on the wall beyond the
      boy, revealing the presence of others, unseen, in an adjoining room. As Harry advances, LOW
      VOICES emanate from the shadows. As he reaches the boy, Harry speaks in a WHISPER: </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Excuse me. Could you tell me where I am? Hello...? <stage>The boy doesn't
        respond, eyes staked to the activity in the adjoining room... which Harry sees now is the
        Entrance Hall. A group of ELDER WITCHES and WIZARDS -- Hogwarts Professors -- talk amongst
        themselves, then... abruptly go silent. Make way for two YOUNG WIZARDS, bearing a
        STRETCHER.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#VOICE">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> Riddle. <stage>The boy wheels... and looks right through Harry. Harry
        turns, too. It's Dumbledore... fifty years younger.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Professor Dumbledore. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> It's not wise to be wandering around this late, Tom. </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Yes, Professor. I suppose I -- I just had to see for myself, if...
        <stage>Riddle glances toward the young wizards, watches them carry the stretcher out of the
        Hall, into the night.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> ... the rumors were true. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I'm afraid they are, Tom. </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> About the school as well? They wouldn't really close Hogwarts, would they,
      Professor? </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Headmaster Dippet may have no choice, I'm afraid. </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Sir? If it all stopped. If the person responsible was caught... </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Is there something you wish to tell me, Tom? </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE">
      <stage>a long beat</stage> No, sir. Nothing. <stage>Dumbledore studies Riddle for a
        moment.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Very well then. Hurry along. <stage>Dumbledore strides directly past
        Harry, not seeing him. When he is gone, Riddle moves quickly, toward the dungeon
        steps.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - DUNGEONS - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Up ahead, a SPLINTER of
      LIGHT leaks through a DOOR. Riddle puts his eye to the crack. Inside, someone is SPEAKING. </stage>
    <sp who="#VOICE">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> C'mon, Aragog. Gotta get yeh outta here... C'mon now.. in the box...
        <stage>As Riddle pushes the door clear, Harry sees a second, smaller room. Crouched by a
        BOX, is a huge boy... YOUNG HAGRID. A STRANGE CLICKING comes from the BOX.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Evening, Hagrid. <stage>Hagrid SLAMS the door shut.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> I'm going to have to turn you in, Hagrid. I don't think you meant it to
      kill anyone -- </sp>
    <sp who="#YOUNGHAGRID"> No, yeh can't! Yeh don' understand! </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Hagrid. The dead girl's parents will be here tomorrow. The least Hogwarts
      can do is make sure the thing that killed their daughter is slaughtered. </sp>
    <sp who="#YOUNGHAGRID"> It wasn' him! Aragog never'd kill no one! Never! </sp>
    <sp who="#RIDDLE"> Monsters don't make good pets, Hagrid. Now... stand aside... <stage>Riddle
        draws his wand, BLASTS the closed DOOR off its hinges, extinguishing the torches within.
        Harry GASPS. A low-slung CREATURE with a tangle of black legs, a gleam of many eyes and a
        pair of razor-sharp pincers, scuttles out of the shadows. As Riddle points his wand at it,
        Hagrid LEAPS...</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#YOUNGHAGRID"> Noooooo! <stage>As they tumble to the floor, the entire ROOM WHIRLS off
        its axis, spinning, and Harry finds himself plummeting through color and shadow again,
        falling flat on his back to... the floor of the Gryffindor Common Room, the ceiling above
        spinning, slowly, to a stop. Harry rises, dashes upstairs.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" BOYS' DORMITORY - NIGHT "> Harry rushes to Ron, shakes him awake,
      WHISPERING INTENSELY. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron! Ron! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What? What's happened...? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> It was Hagrid. Hagrid opened the Chamber of Secrets fifty years ago. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS - ESTABLISHING SHOT - DAY "> CAMERA SOARS high over the
      castle, as below, students hurry to their classes. Finally, it FINDS: </stage>
  </scene>
    <scene>
      <stage cat="INT/EXT" where="HOGWARTS GROUNDS - DAY LATER"> Harry, Ron and Hermione walking
        together across the grounds.</stage>

    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It can't be Hagrid. It just can't be. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> We don't even know this Riddle. He sounds like a dirty, rotten snitch to me. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> The monster had killed someone, Ron. What would any of us done? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Look. Hagrid's our friend. Why don't we just go ask him about it? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> That'd be a cheerful visit. Hullo, Hagrid. Tell us, have you been setting
      anything mad and hairy loose in the castle lately? </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Mad an' hairy? Wouldn' be talkin' 'bou me, now would yeh? <stage>The trio
        wheels, spots Hagrid grinning at them. They instantly look guilty.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON #HERMIONE"> No! <stage>Hagrid looks at them curiously. Harry nods to the
        STRANGE CANISTER in his hand.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> What's that you've got, Hagrid? </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Flesh-Eatin' Slug Repellent. Fer the Mandrakes, yeh know. Accordin' ter
      Professor Sprout, they still got a bit o' growin' up ter do, but once their acne clears up,
      we'll be able to chop 'em up, stew 'em, an' get those people in the hospital un-Petrified.
      'Til then, you three best watch yerselves, all righ'? <stage>They nod, watch Hagrid lope away.
        Just then, Neville comes running up. He looks pale with fright.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Harry, I don't know who did it, but... you'd better come. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GRYFFINDOR TOWER DORMITORY - DAY "> Harry's space is a disaster: trunk
      riffled, drawers flung open, bedclothes strewn on the floor. </stage>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It had to be a Gryffindor. Nobody else knows our password. Unless, it
      wasn't a student... </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Well, whoever it was, they were looking for something. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> And they found it... Tom Riddle's diary is gone. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS GROUNDS - DAY "> Students stream into the Quidditch Stadium.
    </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" MARBLE STAIRCASE - DAY "> Harry, dressed in his Quidditch robes, dashes
      down the staircase with Ron and Hermione. Down below, Ron spies Ginny. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hey, Ginny! Going to the match? <stage>Ginny looks up, startled, then shakes her
        head and exits.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> I tell you, she gets weirder and weirder by the day... </sp>
    <sp who="#VOICE">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> Kill this time... Let me rip... Tear. <stage>Harry freezes. Ron and
        Hermione stop, knowing by his face...</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> No... don't tell me... <stage>Harry turns, as if following the SOUND, absently
        touching his fingers to the wall as he glances around. Hermione studies him with great
        interest -- STUDIES HIS FINGERS -- then, abruptly, Harry turns away, shakes his head: it's
        gone. Hermione looks up, eyes vaguely upon Harry, but her mind miles away.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry... I think I've just understood something! I've got to go to the
      library! <stage>As Hermione sprints back up the stairs, Harry YELLS.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> What do you understand! <stage>But she's gone. Harry turns to Ron in
        puzzlement.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> The library? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> That's Hermione. When in doubt, go to the library </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" REAR OF QUIDDITCH STADIUM - DAY  LATER  "> Harry and his teammates
      march toward the Quidditch tower. The CHEERS of the CROWD are heard. </stage>
    <sp who="#WOOD"> Listen up now. We play our game, Hufflepuff doesn't stand a chance. We're
      stronger, quicker, smarter. </sp>
    <sp who="#GEORGE"> Not to mention they're dead terrified Harry'll Petrify them if they fly
      anywhere near him. </sp>
    <sp who="#WOOD"> That, too. <stage>Just then, Professor McGonagall appears, barring their
        way.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#WOOD"> Professor McGonagall -- </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> This match has been cancelled. </sp>
    <sp who="#WOOD"> Cancelled! They can't cancel Quidditch -- </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Silence, Wood! You will return to Gryffindor Tower now. Potter, you and I
      will find Mr. Weasley. There's something the both of you need to see. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HOSPITAL WING - DAY "> McGonagall pauses outside the door, turns to
      Harry and Ron. </stage>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> I warn you. This will be a bit of a shock. <stage>She opens the door.
        Madam Pomfrey is leaning over a bed where a girl lies. As she straightens up, we see the
        girl is...</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hermione! </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> She was found near the library. Along with this. Does it mean anything to
      either of you? <stage>She holds up a SMALL CIRCULAR MIRROR. Harry shakes his head. McGonagall
        nods gravely, leads them out. As they go, the CAMERA DRIFTS to HERMIONE'S HAND. Clinched
        tight in her stiff knuckles, barely visible, is... a PIECE OF PAPER.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GRYFFINDOR COMMON ROOM - NIGHT "> McGonagall reads from a PARCHMENT to
      the somber Gryffindors. </stage>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> All students will return to their house common rooms by six o'clock in
      the evening. You will be escorted to each lesson by a teacher. No exceptions. <stage>rolling
        up the parchment</stage> I should tell you all this. Unless the culprit behind these attacks
      is caught, it is likely that the school will be closed. <stage>McGonagall turns, exits.
        Instantly, as one, the students begin to talk amongst themselves. Neville speaks up.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Haven't any of the teachers noticed that the Slytherins are all safe? Isn't
      it obvious all this stuff's coming from Slytherin? The Heir of Slytherin, the monster of
      Slytherin -- why don't they just chuck all the Slytherins out? </sp>
    <sp who="#SEAMUS"> They can't close Hogwarts. Where would we all go? </sp>
    <sp who="#DEANTHOMAS"> I don't care what anyone says. As long as Dumbledore's here, Hogwarts
      will be here. <stage>Harry WHISPERS to Ron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> We've got to talk to Hagrid, Ron. I can't believe it's him. But if he did set
      the monster loose last time -- even by accident -- he'll know how to get inside the Chamber of
      Secrets. And that's a start. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> But you heard McGonagall. We're not allowed to leave the tower except for class
      -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I think it's time to get my Dad's old Cloak out again. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" TOWER DORMITORY - NIGHT  LATER  "> CLOSEUP: A drawer opens, a HAND
      reaches in, takes the INVISIBILITY CLOAK. CAMERA PULLS BACK, REVEALS Ron and Harry. All around
      them, the other boys sleep. Harry pitches the cloak over himself and Ron. They're gone.
    </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" ENTRANCE HALL - NIGHT "> Harry and Ron, beneath the cloak, sneak by an
      unaware Snape. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HAGRID'S HUT - NIGHT "> A KNOCK. Hagrid swings open the door. Crossbow
      in hand. </stage>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Who's there? <stage>Harry and Ron drop the cloak. Hagrid lowers the
        crossbow.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HAGRID'S HUT - NIGHT "> FANG, Hagrid's enormous BOARHOUND, THUMPS HIS
      TAIL at the sight of Harry and Ron. Harry points to the crossbow. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> What's that for? </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Nothin', nothin'. I've been expectin'... Doesn't matter. Sit down... I'll
      make tea... <stage>Hagrid nervously takes the kettle, spills the water..</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Are you okay? Hagrid? Did you hear about Hermione? </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Oh, yea. I heard, all righ'. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Look... we have to ask you something. Do you know who's opened the Chamber of
      Secrets? <stage>Hagrid takes a fruit cake, stops, about to answer, when... there is a LOUD
        KNOCK. The fruitcake SMASHES to the floor. Panicked, Harry and Ron throw the cloak over
        themselves. Sweating, Hagrid grabs his crossbow, points it at the door.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> C-come in. <stage>The door opens. A grim Dumbledore enters, followed by a
        portly man in a pin-stripe suit and bowler: CORNELIUS FUDGE.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Good evening, Hagrid. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>whispering to Harry</stage> That's Dad's boss! Cornelius Fudge. The Minister of Magic!
        <stage>Harry elbows Ron to shut him up.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#FUDGE"> Bad business, Hagrid. Very bad business. Had to come. Four attacks on
      Muggle-borns. Things've gone far enough. Ministry's got to act. </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> I never... You know I never, Professor Dumbledore, sir... </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I want it understood, Cornelius, that Hagrid has my full confidence. </sp>
    <sp who="#FUDGE"> Look, Albus, Hagrid's record's against him. I've got to take him. </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Take me? Where? Not Azkaban prison. </sp>
    <sp who="#FUDGE"> For a short stretch only. Not a punishment, Hagrid. More a precaution. If
      someone else is caught, you'll be released with a full apology. <stage>Just then, there is a
        SHARP RAP on the door. As Dumbledore opens it, Harry slumps. It's Lucius Malfoy.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Already here, Fudge? Good, good... </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> What're you doin' here! Get outta my house! </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> My dear man, please believe me, I have no pleasure at all in being
      inside your -- do you call this a house? I simply called at the school and was told the
      Headmaster was here. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> And what exactly did you want with me, Lucius? </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Dreadful thing, Dumbledore, but the governors feel it's time for you to
      step aside. This is an Order of Suspension. You'll find all twelve signatures on it. I'm
      afraid we feel you're losing your touch. What with all these attacks, there'll be no Muggle-
      borns left at Hogwarts. And we all know what an awful loss that would be. <stage>Malfoy hands
        Fudge an OFFICIAL ROLL of PARCHMENT.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#FUDGE"> Now, see here, Lucius. Dumbledore suspended. No, no... last thing we want
      right now... If Dumbledore can't stop these attacks... I mean to say, who can? </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> That remains to be seen, but as all twelve governors have voted -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> An' how many did yeh have ter threaten before they agreed! </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> I would advise you not to shout at the Azkaban guards like that. </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Yeh can take Dumbledore! Take him away an' the Muggle-borns won' stand a
      chance! There'll be killin's next! </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Calm yourself, Hagrid! <stage>steely-eyed</stage> If the governors want
      my removal, Lucius, I shall of course step aside. However... you will find that I will only
      truly have left this school when none here are loyal to me. You will also find that help will
      always be given at Hogwarts to those who... ask for it. <stage>Dumbledore's eyes drift --
        unmistakably -- to Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Admirable sentiments. We shall all miss your highly individual way of
      running things, Albus, and only hope your successor will manage to prevent any more, um,
      killin's. <stage>Malfoy strides to the door and bows Dumbledore out. Fudge, fiddling with his
        bowler, waits for Hagrid. Instead, Hagrid stands his ground, takes a deep breath and says
        carefully..</stage>. </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> If anyone wanted ter find out some stuff, all they'd have ter do is follow
      the spiders. That'd lead 'em right! Tha's all I'm sayin'. <stage>Fudge stares at Hagrid in
        amazement, then follows him out. As the door SLAMS SHUT, FANG starts to HOWL, scratching at
        the closed door. Harry and Ron emerge from the cloak.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Hagrid's right. With Dumbledore gone, there'll be an attack a day. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Look... <stage>At the windowsill, a TRAIL OF SPIDERS escapes through a crack
        in the glass. Harry grabs Hagrid's LANTERN.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> C'mon. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HAGRID'S HUT - NIGHT "> Harry illuminates the TRAIL OF SPIDERS. They
      run from the window to the ground, to the dark trees in the near distance. As Harry moves to
      follow, Ron hesitates. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> What are you doing? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You heard Hagrid. Follow the spiders. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> They're heading into the Dark Forest. <stage>Harry sighs, heads off. Terrified,
        Ron grabs Fang, follows.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Why spiders. Why couldn't it be 'Follow the butterflies'? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" DARK FOREST - NIGHT "> Fang crashes through low-slung branches and
      sharp brambles as Harry follows. Ron gingerly picks his way, the JUMPS... as FANG HOWLS.
      BRANCHES SNAP. A RUMBLING NOISE sounds, then... SILENCE. Harry spies something, points O.S. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> There's something moving over there... something big. <stage>Just then a BLAZE
        of LIGHT splinters the trees, blinding them. They start to flee... when Ron stops.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Harry!... Harry, it's our car! <stage>Scratched and mud-smeared, with bits of
        earth and grass sprouting from its headlamps and hubcaps -- the Ford Anglia looks
        half-animal. Ron circles it in wonder.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> It's been here all the time! Look at it. The Forest has turned it wild.
        <stage>Harry nods, then glances back up the slope.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> C'mon, we don't want to lose the trail. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" SPIDERS' HOLLOW - NIGHT "> Harry and Ron enter a hollow ribboned with
      shadows. Enormous trees tower over them, strewn with strands of white webbing. Ron steps on a
      strand, kicks it off queasily. Harry peers up ahead: at the far end of the hollow, the spiders
      stream toward a DARK OPENING. As Harry and Ron approach the opening, a CLICKING SOUND emanates
      from within, ECHOING in the branches of the tall trees. GROWING LOUDER. Ron falters, glancing
      about nervously. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> I don't have a good feeling about this, Harry -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Don't panic. As Harry steps to the mouth of the cavern, the AIR suddenly
      CRACKLES with MOVEMENT. TWIGS SNAP. A HUGE SHADOW emerges, slowly engulfs Harry. He peers up.
      SEES: An ANCIENT SPIDER <stage>ARAGOG</stage>, the size of a small elephant. As it advances,
      Harry and Ron back slowly away. Then: its BLIND EYES catch the light, and it STOPS. As if...
      listening. </sp>
    <sp who="#ARAGOG"> You do not come from the forest. Your hearts beat like... men. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>breathing finally</stage> Yes. We're friends of Hagrid's. And you... you're...
        <stage>as it comes to him</stage> ... Aragog, aren't you? <stage>Hearing this, Aragog's head
        turns slightly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#ARAGOG"> Hagrid has never sent men into our hollow before. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> He's in trouble. Up at school, there've been attacks. They think it's Hagrid.
      They think he's opened the Chamber of Secrets. Like before. <stage>As Harry talks, Ron's eyes
        dart warily about, then... RON'S POV - a pair of long legs -- SPIDER'S LEGS -- curl slowly
        around the trunk of the tree to his left. Terrified, Ron NUDGES Harry, but Harry ignores
        him.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#ARAGOG"> That's a lie! Hagrid never opened the Chamber of Secrets! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> But if Hagrid never... that means... you're not the monster. </sp>
    <sp who="#ARAGOG"> The monster was born in the castle. I came from a distant land, in the pocket
      of a traveler. <stage>Ron turns. TWO CRAWLING SILHOUETTES inch forward. Pause. Waiting.
        Watching.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Harry... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Shhh! <stage>to Aragog</stage> But if you're not the monster, what did kill
      that girl fifty years ago? </sp>
    <sp who="#ARAGOG"> We do not speak of it! It is an ancient creature we spiders fear above all
      others. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> But have you seen it? <stage> A SCRABBLING SOUND ECHOES above Ron. He GLANCES
        UP: a SPIDER crouches on a branch above.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#ARAGOG"> I never saw any part of the castle but the cupboard in which Hagrid kept me.
      The girl was discovered in a bathroom. When I was accused, Hagrid brought me here. <stage>More
        SCRABBLING. Ron looks up. We PAN UP with him. SEE: SPIDERS -- in high and low branches --
        DROPPING DOWNWARD like paratroopers. Ron GRABS Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>annoyed</stage> What! <stage>Ron points. Harry looks. Pales. Turns slowly back to
        Aragog.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Well... thank you. We'll just go... </sp>
    <sp who="#ARAGOG"> Go? I think not. My sons and daughters do not harm Hagrid, on my command. But
      I cannot deny them fresh meat when it wanders so willingly into our midst. Goodbye, friend of
      Hagrid. <stage>Aragog turns, disappears into the shadows of the cavern.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Can we panic now? <stage> CLICK! CLICK! CLICK! Harry and Ron SPIN. A GANG of
        FIVE-FOOT SPIDERS bar the path ahead. Begin to move forward. Harry and Ron SPIN again:
        SPIDERS. Everywhere. CLOSING IN. Desperately, Harry swings the LANTERN in his hand. The
        spiders falter, then CREEP FORWARD again as the ARC of the LIGHT chases itself away. Around
        and around. Then: The LANTERN goes out. Harry pitches it aside. As one, he and Ron draw
        their wands.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Nice knowing you. <stage>They're done for. Fang WHIMPERS. The spiders draw
        closer, CLICKING FEVERISHLY, when... ... a LONG, LOUD HORN BLEATS. Seconds later, a BLAZE of
        LIGHT ignites the hollow and the FORD ANGLIA comes THUNDERING over the rim and down the
        slope, KNOCKING SPIDERS OUT OF ITS PATH. As it SCREECHES to a halt, the DOORS FLING
        OPEN.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Let's go! <stage>Harry, Ron and Fang LEAP INSIDE. Ron SHIFTS FRANTICALLY. A
        SPIDER appears at Harry's open window.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> THE WINDOWS! ROLL UP THE WINDOWS! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>trying</stage> I CAN'T! IT'S STUCK! <stage>Just then, a hairy leg reaches through Ron's
        window. Instantly, Ron HITS the gas, throws the car into REVERSE. Spiders scatter, but the
        TWO clinging to the side windows hold tight. As the CAR ZOOMS BACKWARDS out of the hollow,
        Harry rolls his window tight, SNAPPING OFF his SPIDER'S LEGS.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" ANOTHER PART OF THE FOREST - NIGHT "> The Anglia jets out of the
      hollow, lands with a THUD. Harry turns. The other spider is PULLING RON from the car. Harry
      points his wand, utters a spell and a BLINDING FLASH OF WHITE LIGHT BLASTS the spider into the
      shadows whipping past. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Thanks for that. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Don't mention it. <stage>They stop. Both hear it: a DISTANT CLICKING. As the
        car flies over a ridge, they see them: a SEA OF SPIDERS heading straight for them like a
        herd of raging wildebeest. Ron puts his foot to the floor, SPINS the wheel and sends the car
        sliding away. The spiders STAMPEDE after.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" ANOTHER PART OF THE FOREST - BLACK PARK - NIGHT "> The Anglia SLALOMS
      through the forest, skimming past trees as the spiders CHARGE after. Harry peers ahead, SEES
      an area of FALLEN TREES. There is an OPENING, one narrow escape route. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> That way! It's the only way out! <stage>looking back</stage> Hurry! They're
      catching up! <stage>Ron JAMS the accelerator... just as a GIANT TARANTULA drops in front of
        the escape route. Harry and Ron are as good as dead.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Can you get us in the air? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>jostling the gear stick</stage> Flying gear's jammed! <stage>The spiders behind DRAW
        CLOSER. The TARANTULA waits ahead. Harry claps his hand over Ron's on the gear shift,
        pushing. The tarantula's pincers open, ready to kill, when... the GEAR SHIFT GIVES, the
        Anglia's wheels LIFT and the CAR FLIES OVER CAMERA, leaving the furious spiders below. The
        car barely avoids the rearing tarantula, then sails over the trees.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" HAGRID'S HUT - NIGHT "> As they LAND, Fang bolts free. Harry and Ron
      exit the CAR wearily, then watch it turn and RUMBLE BACK INTO THE FOREST. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> 'Follow the spiders'! Follow the spiders'! If he ever gets out of Azkaban, I'll
      kill Hagrid. I mean, what was the point of sending us in there? What have we found out? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> We know one thing. Hagrid never opened the Chamber of Secrets. He was
      innocent. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" HOSPITAL WING - DAY "> Madam Pomfrey bars the door, frowns at Harry and
      Ron. </stage>
    <sp who="#MADAMPOMFREY"> There's no point in talking to a petrified person. She won't hear a
      word you're saying. <stage>Ron shifts uncomfortably.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> We know that, Madam Pomfrey. It's just, well, you see, we thought, maybe, we
      could... be with her for a bit. She's our... friend, you see, and... even if she can't hear
      us... I mean, it can't hurt, can it? <stage>A glint of sympathy flickers in Pomfrey's
        eyes.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MADAMPOMFREY"> Very well then. But be quick about it. <stage>As she exits, the boys
        step to her bed. Absently, Ron picks up the circular mirror that lies on the nightstand.
        Eyes Lockhart's Get Well card.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> You don't think Lockhart could be the heir of Slytherin, do you? <stage>off
        Harry's look</stage> Right. Forget I said it. <stage>Harry studies Hermione's face.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Wish you were here, Hermione. We need you. Now more than ever... <stage>Just
        then, the mirror in Ron's hand CATCHES the LATE AFTERNOON SUNLIGHT and casts a jagged FLAME
        across Hermione's hand. Harry watches the light dance over her fingers... then looks closer.
        Sees the paper clutched there.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - DUSK  LATER  "> Harry and Ron duck into an alcove, take out
      the CRINKLED paper, which, we see now, is TORN from a library book. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> 'Of the many fearsome beasts that roam our land, none is more deadly than the
      Basilisk. Capable of living for hundreds of years, instant death awaits any who meet this
      giant serpent's eye. Spiders flee before it and only the crowing of the rooster can kill it.'
        <stage>looking up</stage> Ron! This is it! The monster in the Chamber of Secrets is a
      Basilisk. That's why I can hear it speak. It's a snake. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> But it kills by looking people in the eye. Why is it no one's dead? <stage>Harry
        frowns, contemplating this, then catches he and Ron's REFLECTION in the window opposite. He
        mutters SOFTLY:</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Because no one did look it in the eye. Not directly at least... <stage>in a
        rush</stage> Colin saw it through his camera. Justin -- Justin must've seen the Basilisk
      through Nearly Headless Nick! Nick got the full blast of it, but he's a ghost -- he couldn't
      die again... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> ... And Hermione... had the mirror! I bet you anything she was using it to
      look round corners, in case it came along. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> And Mrs. Norris? I'm pretty sure she didn't have a camera or a mirror, Harry. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> The water... there was water on the floor that night. She only saw the
      Basilisk's reflection... <stage>scanning the page again</stage> The crowing of the rooster is
      fatal to it! That's why Hagrid's roosters were killed! Spiders flee before it! It all fits! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> But how's the Basilisk been getting around? A dirty great snake. Someone would
      have seen... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione answered that too. <stage>Harry points. Scribbled, in Hermione's
        hand, is: "Pipes."</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>aghast</stage> Pipes...? It's using the plumbing. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Remember what Aragog said? About that girl fifty years ago? She died in a
      bathroom. What if she never left. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Moaning Myrtle! <stage>Harry nods. Just then, McGonagall's VOICE ECHOES
        throughout the castle, magically magnified.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">
      <stage>V.O.</stage> All students are to return to their house dormitories at once. All
      teachers to the second floor corridor. Immediately. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" SECOND FLOOR - CORRIDOR - DUSK  MOMENTS LATER  "> McGonagall stands
      before the desecrated wall, surrounded by the rest of the staff. Harry and Ron creep up the
      stairwell. </stage>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> As you can see, the Heir of Slytherin has left another message. Our worst
      fear has been realized. A student has been taken by the monster. Into the Chamber itself.
        <stage>as the teachers react</stage> I'm afraid we shall have to send the students home. I'm
      afraid... this is the end of Hogwarts. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART">
      <stage>bursting in cheerily</stage> So sorry. Dozed off. What have I missed? </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Just the man. A girl has been snatched by the monster, Lockhart. Your moment
      has come at last. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> My m-moment? </sp>
    <sp who="#SNAPE"> Weren't you saying just last night that you've known all along where the
      entrance to the Chamber of Secrets is? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> D-did I? I don't recall... </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> That settles it. We'll leave it to you to deal with the monster,
      Gilderoy. Your skills, after all, are legend. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> V-very well. I'll -- I'll be in my office, getting -- getting
      ready. </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> The rest of us should go and inform the students what has happened. </sp>
    <sp who="#SPROUT"> Who is it the monster's taken, Minerva? </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Ginny Weasley. <stage>Ron's knees give way. As Harry catches him, the
        staff scatters, revealing what is written on the wall: Her skeleton will lie in the Chamber
        forever.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - NIGHT  MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry and a very upset Ron walk
      with desperate purpose. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> She knew something, Harry. She'd found out something about the Chamber of
      Secrets. That's why she was taken. I mean, she was -- is -- a pure-blood. There can't be any
      other reason. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>pulling him away</stage> C'mon. Let's go see Lockhart. He may be a brainless git, but
      he's going to try and get into the Chamber. We can tell him what we know... </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Harry. D'you think there's any chance at all she's not, you know -- <stage>Harry
        glances over, studies Ron's tortured eyes.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> We'll find her, Ron. Ginny's going to be fine. <stage>Ron nods, smiles
        shakily, and looks away. As he does, Harry's face changes, looks troubled. Even he doesn't
        believe what he's just said.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GILDEROY LOCKHART'S OFFICE - NIGHT "> Harry and Ron DASH inside. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Professor, we've got some information for you -- <stage>Harry and Ron stop
        dead. Lockhart's office is stripped to the shelves. Two LARGE TRUNKS stand open.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Are you going somewhere? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Um, well, yes. Urgent call. Unavoidable. Got to go... </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What about my sister? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Well, as to that -- most unfortunate. No one regrets more than I -- </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> You're the Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher! You can't go now! </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> I must say, when I took the job, nothing in the job description -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You're running away? After all that stuff you did in your books? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Books can be misleading. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You wrote them! </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> My dear boy, do use your common sense. My books wouldn't have sold
      half as well if people didn't think I'd done all those things. No one wants to read about some
      ugly old Armenian warlock, even if he did save a village from werewolves. He'd look dreadful
      on the front cover. No dress sense at all... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You're a fraud! You've just been taking credit for what a load of other
      wizards have done! </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Harry, Harry, Harry. There was work involved. I had to track these
      people down and ask them exactly how they managed to do what they did. No, it's not all book
      signings and publicity photos. You want fame, you have to be prepared for a long, hard slog. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Is there anything you can do? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Yes, now that you mention it. I'm rather gifted with Memory Charms.
      Otherwise, you see, all those wizards would've gone blabbing and I'd never have sold another
      book. I'm afraid I'll have to do the same to you both, lest you do the same. <stage>Lockhart
        lifts his wand, but Harry is quicker.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Expelliarmus! <stage>Lockhart BLASTS backwards, toppling into one of the open
        trunks, his wand flying across the floor.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Looks like those Dueling Lessons came in handy after all, Professor. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GIRLS' BATHROOM - NIGHT "> Lockhart walks ahead of Harry and Ron, their
      wands pointed at him. Moaning Myrtle floats above the cistern. </stage>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> Who's there? Oh... <stage>smiles, flirty</stage> Hello, Harry. What do
      you want? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> To ask you how you died. </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE">
      <stage>flattered</stage> Oooooh, it was dreadful. It happened right here. In this very
      cubicle. I'd hidden because Olive Hornby was teasing me about my glasses. I was crying, and
      then I heard somebody come in. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Who was it, Myrtle? </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> I don't know! I was distraught! But they said something funny. A kind
      of made-up language. And I realized it was a boy speaking. So I unlocked the door, to tell him
      to go away, and... I died. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Just like that? How? </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> No idea. I just remember seeing a pair of great big yellow eyes. Over
      there... <stage>Myrtle points to the bank of sinks. Harry and Ron hurry over, examining the
        pipes below, the tile above, then... Harry sees it: etched on one of the COPPER TAPS is a
        TINY SNAKE.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> This is it, Ron. This is the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Say something, Harry. Say something in Parseltongue. <stage>Harry stares off
        self-consciously at the tiny snake.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Open up. <stage>Ron shakes his head. Harry's spoken in his regular
        voice.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> English. <stage>Harry concentrates harder this time, staring so intensely that
        the snake almost looks alive. When, finally, he speaks, it is more like a HISS.
        Parseltongue. The circular group of sinks OPEN and a LARGE, OPEN PIPE is exposed.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Excellent, Harry. Good work. Well then. I'll just be going. There's
      no need for me... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Oh, yes there is. You first. <stage>Harry points his wand at Lockhart, then
        the opening.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Now, boys. What good will it do? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> A bloody lot of good if it's a two-hundred-foot drop onto jagged rocks.
        <stage>Lockhart steps grimly to the dark, gaping hole. Ron gives him a shove and he topples
        headfirst and out of sight. They wait. Finally...</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART">
      <stage>O.S.</stage> It's really quite filthy down here. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> All right. Let's go. </sp>
    <sp who="#MOANINGMYRTLE"> Oh, Harry... if you die down there, you're welcome to share my toilet. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Thanks, Myrtle. <stage>Harry turns. Jumps. Seconds later, Ron follows.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" PIPE - NIGHT "> Harry and Ron slide wicked fast, in a hair-raising
      vertical plummet, catching glimpses of other, smaller pipes branching off in all directions,
      twisting and turning until the pipe levels off, dumps them onto the damp floor of a stone
      tunnel. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" TUNNEL - NIGHT "> Lockhart stares miserably at the muck dripping from
      his robes. Harry takes a TORCH from the wall, poises his wand. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Lumos! <stage>The torch blooms with a BRIGHT ORANGE FLAME.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Remember. Any sign of movement, close your eyes straight away. <stage>Harry
        leads the way down the tunnel. CRUNCH! They look down: a rat's skull. All around them, the
        ground is littered with TINY SKELETONS. Ron squints, sees something HUGE and CURVED lying
        ahead. When he speaks, his voice is hollow with dread.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What's that? Up ahead? </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> That looks like a... snake. <stage>Terrified, Lockhart quickly
        HIDES HIS EYES.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Maybe it's asleep. <stage>Ron draws his wand as they approach, squinting.
        Harry shines his light, revealing... a gigantic COIL of EMPTY SKIN.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell. Whatever shed this must be twenty feet long. Or more. <stage>THUD!
        They turn. Lockhart has passed out.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Heart of a lion, this one. <stage>Ron kneels by him, when... Lockhart's eyes
        open and, quick as a fox... he snatches Ron's wand and scrambles to his feet.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> The adventure ends here, boys! But don't fret. The world will know
      our story. How I was too late to save the girl. How you two tragically lost your minds at the
      sight of her mangled body. I'll even bind a limited edition in this snake skin. Say goodbye to
      your memories. <stage>raising Ron's wand</stage> Obliviate! <stage>Ron's WAND EXPLODES like a
        small BOMB, BLASTING Lockhart OFF HIS FEET and SPITTING great JETS of FIRE into the rock
        above. As RUBBLE RAINS, Ron LEAPS one way and Harry the other. Harry sits up, squints
        through the settling dust. A SOLID WALL of BROKEN ROCK seals the tunnel between him and Ron.
        INTERCUT Harry and Ron.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron? Are you okay? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> I'm okay. This git's not, though. He got blasted by my wand. <stage>Lockhart
        sits up, dazed. Ron picks up a rock and CONKS him on the head. Lockhart PASSES OUT. Ron
        calls to Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What now? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Wait here. I'll go on. I'll go on and... find Ginny. If I'm not back in an
      hour... He leaves it there. </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> I'll try and shift some of this rock. So you can get back through. And, Harry -- </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> See you in a bit. <stage>Harry glances at the snake skin at his feet, moves
        off. He steps carefully through the shadows until he reaches a TOWERING STONE WALL, carved
        with TWIN SERPENTS.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>Parseltongue</stage> Open. <stage>The serpents part and the GIANT WALL SLIDES OPEN.
        Harry removes his wand and ENTERS.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CHAMBER OF SECRETS - NIGHT 
A vast chamber stretches ahead. Along the path are rows  of STONE SERPENTS. The serpents rest in pools of black  water. Ahead is an enormous STATUE of SALAZAR SLYTHERIN.  Several feet in front of the statue, Ginny Weasley lies  motionless. As Harry dashes and takes her into his arms,  her head lolls to one side, cheeks white as marble. A  pale hand clutches TOM RIDDLE'S DIARY to her chest.  Harry DROPS the torch, RACES to Ginny, places his wand on  the floor and kneels beside her.  BOLD ITALICS INDICATE  POSSIBLE FLASHBACKS.  "> </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Ginny! Please don't be dead. Wake up! Wake up! Ginny! </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> She won't wake. <stage>Harry spins. Tom Riddle stands nearby. He is
        strangely BLURRED around the edges, as though Harry was looking at him through a misted
        window.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Tom... Tom Riddle? What d'you mean, she won't wake? She's not... </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> She's still alive. But only just. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Are you a ghost? </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> A memory. Preserved in a diary for fifty years. <stage>Harry looks to the
        diary in Ginny's hand, then places his own hand on Ginny's arm.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> She's cold as ice. You've got to help me, Tom. There's a basilisk -- </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> It won't come until it's called. <stage>Harry looks up, sees Riddle
        twirling a wand in his fingers.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Give me my wand, Tom. </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> You won't be needing it. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Listen, we've got to go! We've got to save her! </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> I'm afraid I can't do that, Harry. You see, as poor Ginny grows weaker...
      I grow stronger. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> But she's dying! </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Yes. I'm afraid so. But then, she's been in so much pain, poor Ginny.
      She's been writing to me for months, telling me all her pitiful worries and woes. Ginny poured
      her soul out to me. I grew stronger on a diet of her deepest fears, her darkest secrets. I
      grew powerful enough to start feeding Ginny a few secrets, to start pouring a bit of my soul
      back into her... <stage>Riddle, growing less vaporous by the second, grins cruelly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Yes, Harry, it was Ginny Weasley who opened the Chamber of Secrets. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> No... she couldn't -- she wouldn't. </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> It was Ginny who set the Basilisk on the Mudbloods and the Squib's cat.
      Ginny who wrote threatening messages on the walls. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> But... Why?... </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Because I told her to. You'll find that I can be very persuasive. Not that
      she knew what she was doing. She was, shall we say, in a kind of trance. Still, the power of
      the diary began to scare her and she tried to dispose of it in the girls' bathroom. But then,
      who should find it... but you. The very person I was most anxious to meet. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>getting angry</stage> And why did you want to meet me? </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Ginny told me all about you. I knew I had to talk to you, meet you if I
      could. So I decided to show you my capture of that brainless oaf, Hagrid, to gain your trust. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Hagrid's my friend. And you framed him, didn't you? </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> It was my word against Hagrid's. Only Dumbledore seemed to think Hagrid
      was innocent. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I'll bet Dumbledore saw right through you. </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> I knew it wouldn't be safe to open the Chamber again while I was still at
      school. So I decided to leave behind a diary, preserving my sixteen-year-old self in its
      pages, so that one day... I would be able to lead another to finish Salazar Slytherin's noble
      work. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Well, you haven't finished it this time. In a few hours Mandrake Draught will
      be ready and everyone who was petrified will be all right again. </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Haven't I told you, that killing Mudbloods doesn't matter to me anymore?
      For many months now, my new target has been... you. <stage>grinning</stage> Imagine my
      disappointment when I learned Ginny had stolen the diary back from you. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Ginny stole the diary from my room? But why? </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> She was afraid. Afraid you'd learn how to work the diary. Afraid I'd tell
      you just who it was that had been strangling all those roosters. <stage>Horrified, Harry
        glances at Ginny, growing more PALE, then back to Riddle, who is growing more SOLID.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Come now, Harry. Don't look so disappointed. Had Ginny succeeded in
      destroying the diary, she would have destroyed me. And we couldn't be having this little talk.
      And I have so many questions for you. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Like what? </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Well, how is it that a baby with no extraordinary magical talent managed
      to defeat the greatest wizard of all time? How did you escape with nothing but a scar, while
      Lord Voldemort's powers were destroyed? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Why do you care how I escaped? Voldemort was after your time. </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Voldemort is my past, present and future. <stage>Riddle pulls Harry's wand
        from his pocket and begins to trace it through the air, writing three words: "TOM MARVOLO
        RIDDLE." Then, with a wave, he re-arranges them: "I AM LORD VOLDEMORT."</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You. You're the heir of Slytherin. You're Voldemort? </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Surely you didn't think I would keep my filthy Muggle father's name? </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> No, I fashioned myself a new name, a name I knew wizards everywhere would
      one day fear to speak, when I became the greatest sorcerer in the world. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Albus Dumbledore is the greatest sorcerer in the world! </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Dumbledore's been driven out of this castle by the mere memory of me. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> He'll never be gone! Not as long as those who remain are loyal to him!
        <stage>Suddenly, MUSIC... EERIE and UNEARTHLY... ECHOES deep within the chamber and a small,
        swift SHADOW ribbons over the rock. Flying from above is FAWKES, the Phoenix. The bird
        SWOOPS into the chamber, clutching a RAGGED BUNDLE in its golden talons.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Fawkes. <stage>Fawkes flies toward Harry, drops the ragged bundle, which is
        the SORTING HAT, at his feet. Riddle picks it up.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE">
      <stage>giggling</stage> This is what Dumbledore sends his defender! A songbird and an old hat!
        <stage>Riddle tosses aside the hat. He turns to the statue of Salazar Slytherin and speaks
        in Parseltongue.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE">
      <stage>Parseltongue</stage> Speak to me, Slytherin. <stage>Suddenly, the stone face's MOUTH
        OPENS. There is a RUMBLING SOUND, followed by the sound of SLITHERING. Harry turns away. The
        Basilisk, A GIANT SERPENT, spills out, uncoiling heavily to the floor. Harry turns to the
        wall. The shadow of the serpent is visible on the wall. PAN TO Tom Riddle, looking at
        Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Let's match the powers of Lord Voldemort, Heir of Salazar Slytherin,
      against the famous Harry Potter, shall we? <stage>Riddle turns, to serpent, speaking in
        Parseltongue.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE">
      <stage>Parseltongue</stage> Kill him! <stage>The HISSING SERPENT shoots forward. Harry turns,
        RUNS away.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Parseltongue won't save you now, Potter. The Basilisk only obeys me. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY">
      <stage>to himself</stage> Don't look. Don't look into its eyes. <stage>Harry RACES along the
        stone path, but the giant serpent is FASTER. Harry TRIPS. FALLS. The Basilisk RISES. Harry
        looks to the wall, sees the serpent about to strike. Suddenly FAWKES SCREECHES, soaring
        toward the Basilisk and circling its blunt head, confusing it. The SNAKE SNAPS furiously,
        when... Fawkes drops like a knife, driving its talons deep into the serpent's glittering
        eyes. As Harry watches the angry play of shadows on the wall, the BASILISK ROARS, HISSING in
        pain. Fawkes wings away, its talons dripping with blood and Harry turns, LOOKS: the
        Basilisk's eyes are a blind, bloody mess.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Fool! Think you're safe! It can still hear you! <stage>As Harry flees, the
        serpent thunders after, STRIKING BLINDLY as its whipping tail SHATTERS a Slytherin STATUE.
        Harry dodges and ducks, then, seeing the snake about to strike again... LEAPS CLEAR,
        stumbling toward a SIDE TUNNEL.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CHAMBER OF SECRETS - SIDE TUNNEL - NIGHT "> Harry RACES HEADLONG into
      the shadows, then looks back, sees the snake eclipse the light at the far end of the tunnel
      and SLITHER QUICKLY inside. Thinking, Harry DUCKS INTO AN ALCOVE, puts his hand over his mouth
      and waits, desperate to remain STILL and SILENT. The snake slides heavily by, then... SLOWS.
      TURNS BACK. The snake's head weaves inside, only INCHES from Harry's face. Harry trembles as
      the snake's head cocks to the side, then... finally... WITHDRAWS. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" CHAMBER OF SECRETS - NIGHT "> Harry DASHES back into the main chamber.
      Ginny looks frighteningly pale. Riddle GRINS cruelly, almost SOLID now. </stage>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Yes, Potter. The process is nearly complete. In a few minutes, Ginny
      Weasley will be dead. And I will cease to be a memory. Lord Voldemort will return. Very
      much... alive. <stage>Harry moves toward Ginny, then suddenly... the BASILISK SHOOTS OUT of
        the TUNNEL, HISSING directly in front of Harry. Trapped, Harry glances around, then --
        impulsively -- LEAPS upward, begins to scale the statue of Salazar Slytherin. The serpent
        strikes madly, but Harry continues on, CLIMBING BOLDLY until he reaches the top. He turns.
        Sees the Sorting Hat. Sees what glitters within: the RUBY HANDLE of a SWORD. Harry WHEELS,
        sword in hand, and fends off the slashing serpent like St. George and the dragon. In a mad
        rush of courage, he PITCHES HIMSELF onto the serpent, SLIDES DOWN its back and rolls up,
        SWORD RAISED. Too tired to flee, Harry simply waits. The serpent rises and, FANGS BARED...
        STRIKES. Marshalling every ounce of strength left to him, Harry drives the sword upward,
        deep into the roof of the SERPENT'S mouth. It HISSES in PAIN, thrashing MADLY as it drives a
        FANG into Harry's arm. Harry clutches his arm in agony, stumbles back and falls to the
        floor, watching as the serpent THRASHES briefly... then goes STILL. Harry peers down, sees
        the FANG that pierces his arm, the blood soaking slowly into his robe. As he yanks the fang
        free, Riddle steps forward, almost fully whole now. His eyes shine at the sight of Harry's
        wound.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Remarkable, isn't it? How quickly the venom of the Basilisk penetrates the
      body? If you have any final words, Potter, you'd best speak them now. I'd guess you have
      little more than a minute to live. <stage>Harry blinks heavily, watching as the skin of his
        forearm turns a troubling gray.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> So ends the famous Harry Potter. On his knees in the Chamber of Secrets.
      Defeated at last by the Dark Lord he so unwisely challenged. You'll be back with your dear
      Mudblood mother soon, Harry... <stage>As Riddle talks, Harry glances at Ginny, nearly white
        now, a small ghost, the only evidence of life the TREMBLING OF A SINGLE FINGER. Harry
        studies the finger and what lies beneath it: Tom Riddle's diary. Harry begins to crawl
        toward her.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> Funny, isn't it? The damage a silly little book can do? Especially in the
      hands of a silly little girl. <stage>As Harry reaches Ginny, he places his hand on hers,
        then... slips the diary free.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> What are you doing? No. Stop... <stage>Riddle's face creases in fear. He
        LUNGES FORWARD. But Harry is too quick. Raising his hand high... he PLUNGES THE FANG into
        the book. Instantly, BLACK INK SPURTS from the pages.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#TOMRIDDLE"> No! <stage>Riddle SHRIEKS, writhing in pain. His body begins to wither
        instantly, growing BLURRY once more. As the ink runs off Harry's fingers to the floor,
        Riddle VANISHES altogether. Harry sinks back, then... hears a FAINT MOAN. Ginny STIRS, color
        blooming in her cheeks. As she sees Harry, she SOBS.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GINNY"> Harry. It was me! But I swear, I didn't mean to... Riddle made me. He wrote to
      me... took me over... I didn't even know whose diary it was. I found it inside my cauldron.
      The day we all went to Diagon Alley and... Harry. You're hurt... </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Ginny. You need to get yourself out... Follow the chamber... You'll find
      Ron... <stage>There is a RUSH OF WINGS and Fawkes circles down, lays his head onto Harry's
        arm.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> You were brilliant, Fawkes. I just... wasn't quick enough. <stage>Then Harry
        blinks, looks down. Thick pearly TEARS are trickling down Fawkes' face and onto his arm.
        Almost instantly, his wound... begins to heal itself.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Of course. Dumbledore told me. Phoenix tears have healing powers.
        <stage>looking up at Ginny</stage> It's all right, Ginny. It's over. It's just a memory...
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" TUNNEL - NIGHT  LATER  "> With Fawkes gliding gracefully ahead of them,
      Harry and Ginny make their way back. Up ahead, SHIFTING ROCK can be heard and a jagged fissure
      of LIGHT GLIMMERS. Ron's face appears. </stage>
    <sp who="#RON"> Ginny! <stage>Ron wriggles through, rushes forward and hugs Ginny.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> You're alive. I can't believe it. </sp>
    <sp who="#GINNY"> I'm going to be expelled, I just know it! </sp>
    <sp who="#RON">
      <stage>to Harry</stage> Remind you of anyone? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Where's Lockhart? <stage>Harry eyes Lockhart, sitting by himself, HUMMING
        placidly.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> His Memory Charm backfired. Hasn't got a clue who he is. I keep having to stop
      him wandering off. He's a danger to himself. </sp>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Hello. Odd sort of place, this, isn't it? Do you live here? </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> No. <stage>Ron turns, raises his eyebrows at Harry. Harry looks upward. There is
        an opening, hundreds of feet up. Just then, Fawkes circles back, fluttering in front of
        Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> What's with the bird? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I think... I think he's telling me he can take us out of here. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" ROCKY TUNNEL - NIGHT  LATER  "> A CURIOUS, GLIDING SHADOW RIPPLES
      across the cavernous wall, and then Harry, Ron, Ginny and Lockhart soar out of the darkness,
      linked hand in hand. Fawkes is flying them home. </stage>
    <sp who="#GILDEROYLOCKHART"> Amazing! This is just like magic! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" DUMBLEDORE'S OFFICE - DAY "> Harry and Ron, covered in muck and slime
      -- stand in Dumbledore's office. Fawkes perches on a pedestal behind Dumbledore, who sits at
      his desk, examining the charred diary. He looks up, regarding Harry and Ron gravely. </stage>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Ingenious. Simply... ingenious. <stage>looking up</stage> Of course, Tom
      Riddle was probably the most brilliant student Hogwarts has ever seen. I taught him myself
      fifty years ago. After he left, I would occasionally hear stories of his activities -- dark
      rumors -- but after awhile, even the rumors stopped. When he finally resurfaced as Lord
      Voldemort, most people had completely forgotten the clever Head Boy he'd once been. </sp>
    <sp who="#GINNY"> I didn't know whose diary it was, sir. I swear. I found it inside my cauldron.
        <stage>to the others</stage> The day we all went to Diagon Alley. <stage>Hearing this, Harry
        frowns in thought, recollecting...</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#GINNY"> But I understand if... given all the trouble I've caused... if you -- </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Wiser wizards than you have been hoodwinked by Lord Voldemort, Miss
      Weasley. No, I think you've endured enough. I would suggest a bit of bed rest, however. And
      perhaps a large mug of hot chocolate. I always find that cheers me up. Minerva, will you show
      Arthur and Molly up to the hospital wing? </sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Certainly, Albus. <stage>As they exit, Harry and Ron watch them go. Mrs.
        Weasley's VOICE carries:</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> A diary that writes back to you! Honestly, Ginny! What were you thinking?
      Haven't I always told you? Never trust anything that can think for itself if you can't see
      where it keeps its brain! <stage>Harry and Ron turn back. See Dumbledore regarding them
        gravely.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You two realize, of course, that in the last few hours, you have broken
      perhaps a dozen school rules? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> Yes, sir. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> And that there is sufficient evidence to expel you both? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> Yes, sir. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Therefore, it seems only fitting... <stage>eyes twinkling</stage> That
      you both receive Special Awards for Services to the School. And -- let me see -- yes, I think
      two hundred points apiece, which, I believe, should be more than enough to secure Gryffindor
      the House Cup. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY #RON">
      <stage>grinning</stage> Thank you, sir. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Now, Mr. Weasley, if you would, have an owl deliver these release papers
      to Azkaban. We need our gamekeeper back. <stage>Ron nods, takes the envelope and
        exits.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> First, Harry, I want to thank you. You must have shown me real loyalty
      down in the Chamber. Nothing but that could have called Fawkes to you. Secondly, I sense
      you're troubled by something. Am I right? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> It's just, you see, sir, I couldn't help noticing certain things. Certain
      similarities. Between Tom Riddle and me. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You can speak Parseltongue, Harry, because Lord Voldemort can speak
      Parseltongue. Unless I'm much mistaken, he transformed some of his own powers to you the night
      he gave you that scar. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Voldemort put a bit of himself in me? </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Not intentionally, but... yes. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> So the Sorting Hat was right. I should be a Slytherin. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> It's true, Harry. You do possess many of the qualities Voldemort himself
      prizes. Resourcefulness. Determination. A certain disregard for the rules. Yet the Sorting Hat
      placed you in Gryffindor. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Only because I asked it to. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Exactly. Which makes you very different from Voldemort. It's not our
      abilities that show what we truly are, Harry. It's our choices. <stage>smiling at him</stage>
      If you want proof that you belong in Gryffindor, Harry, I suggest you look more closely at
      this. <stage>Dumbledore hands the bloodstained sword to Harry. An ENGRAVED NAME glimmers above
        the ruby-encrusted hilt.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> 'Godric Gryffindor.' </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Only a true Gryffindor could have pulled that out of the Hat.
        <stage>Suddenly, Lucius Malfoy enters, dragging... Dobby by the ear.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Dobby! This is your Master? The family you serve is the Malfoys! <stage>Dobby
        nods, chagrined. Lucius Malfoy brushes past Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Out of my way, Potter. <stage>to Dumbledore</stage> So! You've
      returned! </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Yes. When the governors heard that Arthur Weasley's daughter had been
      taken into the Chamber, they saw fit to summon me back. <stage>a wry smile</stage> Curiously,
      several of them seemed under the impression that you would curse their families if they didn't
      agree to suspend me in the first place, Lucius. </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> From the beginning, my only concern has been the welfare of this school
      and its students. I assume the culprit has been identified. </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Oh yes. It was Voldemort. Only this time, he chose to act through someone
      else. By means of... this. <stage>As Dumbledore nudges the diary toward Lucius Malfoy, Harry
        sees Dobby nod meaningfully from the diary to Lucius.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Fortunately, our young Mr. Potter discovered it. <stage>a chill to his
        voice</stage> One only hopes that no more of Lord Voldemort's old school things find their
      way into innocent hands. The consequences for the one responsible could be... severe.
        <stage>Lucius Malfoy stares icily at Dumbledore, then turns away.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Come, Dobby. We're leaving. <stage>As Dobby scuttles toward the door,
        Lucius Malfoy KICKS HIM through it, then exits himself. Harry stares at the empty doorway as
        DOBBY'S PAINFUL SQUEALS ECHO from the corridor.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir? I wonder if I could have that. <stage>Dumbledore looks up, follows
        Harry's eyes to the diary.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="EXT" where=" DUMBLEDORE'S OFFICE - DAY  MOMENTS LATER  "> As the elevator opens,
      Harry dashes out. </stage>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Mr. Malfoy! I have something of yours. <stage>Harry comes up running, thrusts
        the diary into Malfoy's hand.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Mine? I don't know what you're talking about. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> I think you do, sir. I think you slipped it into Ginny Weasley's cauldron that
      day in Diagon Alley. <stage>Malfoy shoves the diary into Dobby's face, then leans close to
        Harry and, with a nasty grin, WHISPERS:</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Prove it! <stage>He turns away. As Dobby looks sadly back, clutching
        the diary in his hand, Harry mouths the words: Open it. Dobby looks down curiously.
        Inside... is a SOCK. He GASPS.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Dobby! Dobby, come! </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY">
      <stage>in wonderment</stage> Master has given Dobby a sock. Master has presented Dobby with
      clothes. Dobby is... free! </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> What? I didn't -- <stage>He wheels, sees Harry standing with one leg
        crossed: His right ankle is bare. Instantly, Malfoy charges forth.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> You've lost me my servant! </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> You shall not harm Harry Potter! <stage>Dobby steps between and -- BANG!
        Malfoy flies backwards, lands in a crumpled heap. Rising, he stares murderously at
        Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Mark my words, Harry Potter. You'll meet the same sticky end as your
      parents one of these days. They were meddlesome fools too. <stage>With that, he turns, storms
        off.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Harry Potter freed Dobby! How can Dobby ever repay him? </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Just promise me something. </sp>
    <sp who="#DOBBY"> Anything, sir. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> Never try to save my life again. <stage>Dobby grins then and -- CRACK! -- is
        gone.</stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
    <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - NIGHT "> Fear and suspicion banished, the House tables
      abuzz with excitement and anticipation... all except the Slytherins, who do not share the
      general feeling. Seated at the tables, are the formerly petrified, revived students. Justin
      Finch-Fletchley joins his fellow Hufflepuffs. Colin Creevey SNAPS photos of the proceedings.
      At the rear of the hall, standing near the entrance, Filch is reunited with Mrs. Norris.
      Then... Hermione enters, searching the room for Harry and Ron. Finally, she sees them. Smiles.
      Runs forward and embraces Harry. </stage>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You solved it! You solved it! </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> With loads of help from you. <stage>She turns to embrace Ron. They pause, an
        awkward moment between them and... shake hands instead.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON"> Welcome back, Hermione. <stage>McGonagall taps her goblet. Dumbledore
        stands.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Before we begin our feast, let's give a round of applause to Professor
      Sprout and Madame Pomfrey, whose Mandrake Juice has been successfully administered to all
      those who had been petrified. <stage>Everyone applauds.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Also, in the wake of recent events, as a school treat, all exams have
      been cancelled. <stage>Everyone cheers, save for Hermione.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Oh, no! <stage>At the rear of the Hall, the great doors OPEN. It's Hagrid.
        He enters. Stops. Looks around. The room falls SILENT. All eyes upon him. He glances around.
        Nervous. Embarrassed.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> Sorry I'm late. The owl deliverin' my release papers got all lost 'n
      confused. Some ruddy bird named Errol. <stage>Ron exchanges a nervous glance with Dumbledore.
        Hagrid looks at all of the faces staring at him. He turns to Harry.</stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID"> I jus' want to say... that if it wasn't fer' you, Harry... you an' Ron... and
      Hermione... Well, I jus' want to say... Thanks. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY"> There's no Hogwarts without you, Hagrid. </sp>

    <stage>Just then... Dumbledore gets to his feet and... slowly... brings his hands together. The
      others join him. Soon, everyone is on their feet and the Hall ROARING. As the students
      surround Hagrid, he blinks, wipes at his eyes, and...CAMERA PULLS BACK, THROUGH the window,
      leaving the celebration. WE CONTINUE TO CRANE BACK... BACK... TO a WIDE SHOT OF HOGWARTS...
      glittering gloriously in the night. FADE TO BLACK. THE END</stage>
  </scene>
</script>
</xml>
