<?xml-model href="potterScripts.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
    <header>
        <!--metadata in here -->
        <title>HARRY POTTER AND THE DEATHLY HALLOWS - PART 1</title>
        <screenWriter>Steve Kloves</screenWriter>
        <productionStart date="2009-03-13"/>
        <!--Optional: if available. -->
        <release date="2010-06-11"/>
        <!--Look this up and verify -->
        <digitalProject>
            <editor who="#bca">Bianka Alexander</editor>
            <advisor who="#ebb">Elisa Beshero-Bondar</advisor>
            <span from="2020-10-01" to="2021-05-06"/>
            <desc>.....</desc>
            <sourceText>
                <siteName>.....</siteName>
                <link><!--Website URL --></link>
                <dateRetrieved>yyyy-mm-dd</dateRetrieved>
            </sourceText>
        </digitalProject>
    </header>
    <script>
        <scene>
            <stage>FADE IN: TITLE CARD - WARNER BROS. PRESENTS We PUSH THROUGH THE LOGO INTO a
                living, breathing DAILY PROPHET. GRIM HEADLINES SAIL PAST US: Death. Paranoia. A
                world at war. We ZOOM INTO a MOVING PHOTOGRAPH of the Minister of Magic, RUFUS
                SCRIMGEOUR, standing in the...</stage>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" MINISTRY OF MAGIC - ATRIUM - DAY  "> ... atrium of the Ministry
                of Magic, addressing a sea of MINISTRY EMPLOYEES as REPORTERS scribble intently. </stage>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> These are dark times, there is no denying. Our world has perhaps
                faced no greater threat than it does today. But I say this to our citizenry: we,
                ever your servants, continue to defend your liberty and repel the forces that would
                seek to take it from you. Your Ministry remains strong...</sp>

            <stage>CAMERA FAVORS a pair of wizards, YAXLEY and PIUS THICKNESSE, who turn away as we
                PULL OUT of thePHOTOGRAPH and SAIL once more THROUGH the turning pages, the
                headlines growing grimmer, the faces more HAUNTED, until, finally, we emerge from
                the Prophet and find it in the hands of... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" GRANGER HOME - HERMIONE’S BEDROOM - LATE AFTERNOON (RAINING) "
                >... HERMIONE. She stares stoically at a LURID HEADLINE --MUGGLE FAMILY MURDERED --
                VIOLENCE SPREADS.</stage>
            <sp who="#MRSGRANGER">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Hermione. Your tea is ready, dear.<stage> Hermione glances
                    through the doorway to the stairs beyond. Her MOTHER’S SHADOW clings to the
                    wall, trembling within another SHADOW, that of a WIND-TOSSED TREE. It is
                    strangely beautiful and Hermione seems transfixed... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Coming, Mum.<stage> Her mother’s SHADOW withdraws, leaving only the
                    trembling tree. Hermione glances once more at the Prophet’s troubling headline,
                    then slips it into a TINY BEADED BAG. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" PARLOR - LATE AFTERNOON (MOMENTS LATER, RAINING)  "> As
                Hermione descends the stairs, MRS. GRANGER exits the kitchen with a teapot. </stage>
            <sp who="#MRSGRANGER"> Don’t you look lovely. All packed? <stage> Hermione nods and
                    watches her mother set the teapot on the table in front of the television. Just
                    then, MR. GRANGER steps out holding a biscuit tin. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRGRANGER"> Are you sure these biscuits are sugar-free? </sp>
            <sp who="#MRSGRANGER"> Quite sure, dear. See the big bold letters that say ‘SugarFree’?
                Dead giveaway. </sp>
            <sp who="#MRGRANGER"> Mm. Yes. <stage>passing Hermione</stage> Hello, kitten. Don’t you
                look lovely. <stage> Hermione smiles wanly as her father gives her a peck on the
                    head, then joins her mother on the sofa opposite the television. An AUSTRALIAN
                    WILDLIFE PROGRAM PLAYS. TELEVISION (V.O.) ... the bandicoot has small pointed
                    ears and a long snout from which it emits a distinctive trumpet sound when
                    agitated... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRSGRANGER"> Darling, don’t be suspicious the biscuits taste so good, be
                grateful the company’s so clever... Hermione looks away from the screen, studies her
                mother and father. Slowly, she reaches into the tiny bag and withdraws her wand.
                Taking two steps forward, she points it toward the back of their heads. Hand
                trembling, sheSPEAKS, her VOICE barely a WHISPER: </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Obliviate.<stage> Mrs. Granger’s face goes briefly slack and she
                    reaches out, as if to break a fall, then, slowly, her hand drops, coming to rest
                    upon her husband’s. He blinks once, blankly, and then... enfolds her fingers in
                    his. Hermione lowers her arm and, eyes stinging with tears, watches the
                    PHOTOGRAPHS placed about the room begin to CHANGE. One by one, Hermione
                    DISAPPEARS from each. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Goodbye. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" STREET - LATE AFTERNOON (MOMENTS LATER, RAINING) "> Clutching
                the beaded bag, Hermione moves down the windswept street into the dying light. We
                BOOM UP TO the sky, HOLD briefly, then BOOM DOWN TO... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FRONT YARD (THE BURROW) - DUSK "> ... RON, staring at the
                stars. He drops his gaze to the house, studies GINNY and MRS. WEASLEY, aglow in the
                light of the kitchen, watching them with affection, as if committing them to memory.
                His gaze shifts to the adjacent SHED. Inside, ARTHUR WEASLEY is bent over hi
                sworkbench. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" SHED - DUSK (MOMENTS LATER) "> Mr. Weasley fiddles with a SMALL
                RADIO. Another half- dozen -- in various stages of repair -- stand in a line before
                him. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> What are those? </sp>
            <stage>Mr. Weasley turns, sees Ron standing in the doorway.</stage>

            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> Close the door. Ron eases inside and steps to the workbench.
                Mr. Weasley turns the knob on the radio before him. STATIC spits forth, then a VOICE
                comes clear: RADIO <stage>V.O.</stage> ...comes to us this evening from the north of
                England, where a wizard family by the name of Westinburgh were found dead in their
                cellar. While not a member of the Order, Mr. Westinburgh and his wife had, on
                numerous occasions, provided shelter for its members... <stage> Arthur switches off
                    the radio. Gestures to the others. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> These are for the Order. So many are on the run now, it helps
                them to stay connected with the rest of us. Know they’re not alone...<stage> Ron
                    studies his father’s weary face as the older mans tares at his handiwork. Places
                    his hand upon his shoulder. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> C’mon. Mum’s got dinner ready. <stage> Arthur nods, pushes away from the
                    bench and heads out the door. Ron lingers briefly, studying the radio, then
                    follows his father into the night. We FADE. The TITLE CARD appears... and we
                    -DISSOLVE TO: </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" NIGHT SKY  "> A scarlet moon. A speck -- a nightbird, or a bat
                -- framed in the moon’s surface, approaches rapidly, then --WHOOSH! -- passes
                beneath. Far below, a sea of treetops shift eerily. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" MALFOY MANOR - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER) "> We PLUMMET THROUGH the
                shifting trees TO a narrow moonlit lane. A SHADOW ripples across the ground like a
                kite made of water. A BOOT touches down upon the graveled lane, then another. A cape
                flutters slowly down upon the shoulders of a wizard, lank hair splayed across his
                windblown collar. His head turns. Moonlight strikes his pale face. SNAPE. Moving. Up
                a wide drive, to a pair of wrought iron gates. Beyond, a large manor that has seen
                better days. A RUSTLING sounds. Snape wheels, draws his wand. A PEACOCK, white as a
                ghost, emerges from the yew. Snape eyes it warily, then lifts his hand. The iron
                gates turn to smoke. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" MALFOY MANOR - ENTRYWAY - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Fractured
                in the prism of a diamond-paned window, Snape approaches. The front door glides
                open. As he enters, dark eyes in torch-lit portraits track him from above. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HALLWAY - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> A door looms at the end of
                a hallway. Reaching it, Snape hesitates for a heartbeat, then enters. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DRAWING ROOM - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Two dozen figures sit
                silently at a large ornate table, illuminated by the flickering light of a
                fireplace. Snape studies the scene, then his eyes rise. Revolving slowly near the
                ceiling, as if suspended by an invisible rope, is an unconscious WOMAN (CHARITY
                BURBAGE).</stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Severus. I was beginning to worry you’d lost your way. Come. I’ve
                saved you a seat. </sp>
            <stage> VOLDEMORT grins, silhouetted against the fire, and gestures to the seat nearest
                his own. All eyes follow Snape, all except DRACO MALFOY, who nervously stares at the
                body above and a haggard LUCIUS MALFOY, who merely stares vaguely at his wand while
                his wife NARCISSA looks straight ahead. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> You know our hosts, of course, Severus. Narcissa in particular has
                been most hospitable. Lucius, on the other hand, is, I fear, burdened by my
                presence. Are you, Lucius? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> My lord? </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Are you burdened? </sp>
            <sp who="#NARCISSA"> My lord is always welcome here. <stage> Voldemort smiles, his
                    eyes shifting to Snape, who watches the great snake NAGINI as she slopes slowly
                    over the feet of those present, unnerving all. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> You bring news I trust, Severus? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> It will happen Saturday next. At nightfall. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> And this information comes-- </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> --from the source we discussed. <stage> Yaxley, the wizard seen at the
                    Ministry, leans into the flickering light from the opposite end of the table.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#YAXLEY"> I have heard differently, my lord. Dawlish, the Auror, let slip that
                the Potter boy will not be moved until the thirtieth of this month, the night before
                he turns seventeen. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> This is a false trail. The Auror Office no longer plays any part in
                the protection of Harry Potter. Those closest to him believe we have infiltrated the
                Ministry. </sp>
            <sp who="#SQUATMAN"> Well, they’ve got that right, then, ‘aven’t they? <stage> As the
                    Squat Man cackles wheezily, others join in. Voldemort raises a hand. All goes
                    silent. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Pius, what say you? <stage> PIUS THICKNESSE looks up, his gaze
                    placid. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#THICKNESSE"> One hears many things, my lord. Whether the truth is among them
                is not clear. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Spoken like a true politician. You will, I think, prove most
                useful, Pius. Where will he be taken? The boy? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> To a safehouse. Likely the home of someone in the Order. I’m told it
                has been given every manner of protection possible. Once there, it will be
                impractical to attack him. We may have compromised the Ministry, but there are those
                who remain loyal to him. As long as the Ministry stands, his allies within will have
                the means at their disposal to insure his safety. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> My lord, if I might, I’d like to volunteer myself for this task.
                I’d like to kill the boy. <stage> Just then a WAIL rises from the floorboards.
                    Voldemort’s eyes flash briefly with RED. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Wormtail! Have I not spoken to you about keeping our guest quiet? </sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> Yes, m-my lord. Right away, my lord. <stage> As WORMTAIL scrambles
                    up, Voldemort returns his gaze to BELLATRIX. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> As inspiring as I find your bloodlust, Bellatrix, I must be the
                one to kill Harry Potter. But I face an unfortunate complication. It has recently
                come to my attention that my wand and Potter’s share the same core. They are, in
                some ways, twins. We can wound but not fatally harm one another. Which means, if I
                am to kill him... I will have to do it with another’s wand. <stage> The others at
                    the table stir nervously. Bellatrix stiffens. Voldemort’s narrow eyes rake the
                    room. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Come now. Surely one of you would like the honor? What
                about...you, Lucius? <stage> Lucius peers up, sallow and beaten. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> I require your wand. <stage> Lucius sits mute, paralyzed by the
                    request, scanning the faces of the others, who avoid his gaze, all but Snape,
                    who regards him with naked contempt and Draco, whose eyes meet his briefly, then
                    glance away. Finally Narcissa’s fingers lightly graze his wrist, summoning him
                    back to the moment. Turning, he watches as, almost imperceptibly, she nods.
                    Lowering his head, he ROLLS his wand slowly across the table, where it stops
                    atVoldemort’s skeletal hand. Voldemort holds the wand to the light.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Do I detect elm? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> Yes, my lord. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> And the core? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> Dragon -- dragon heartstring. <stage> Voldemort nods, getting a feel
                    for the wand’s heft, then his eyes shift, catch Lucius staring at the WAND on
                    the table -- Voldemort’s own. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> My wand? You can’t possibly thinkI would give you my wand. <stage>
                    Lucius’ eyes meet Voldemort’s. For a moment he is speechless. Finally his chin
                    drops. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> No, my lord. <stage> Voldemort studies Lucius’ bowed head, then
                    returns his attention to the wand in his hand. Raising it, he points it at the
                    body above. With a FLICK, the body awakens, TWITCHING against its invisible
                    bonds. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> For those of you who do not know, we are joined tonight by Miss
                Charity Burbage who until recently taught at Hogwarts School ofWitchcraft and
                Wizardry. Her specialty was Muggle studies. It is Miss Burbage’s belief that Muggles
                are not so different from us. She would, given her way, have us mate with them. To
                her, the mixture of magical and Muggle blood is not an abomination but something to
                be encouraged. I, of course, take a contrary view. But we’re all civilized here. All
                adults. We can agree to disagree. <stage> Charity’s tear-streaked face revolves once
                    more to face Snape, her voice hoarse with fear. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CHARITY"> Severus, please. We’re friends... <stage> Snape’s face remains
                    impassive. Voldemort’s eyes narrow to scarlet slits... his voice HISSES. Draco
                    watches a teardrop strike the table... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Avada Kedavra! <stage> GREEN LIGHT envelops the room. Charity
                    plummets to the table, body still. Voldemort ponders the wand, satisfied.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Nagini... Dinner. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" PRIVET DRIVE - DUSK  "> A blood-red sky hangs over the
                neighborhood. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DURSLEY HOUSE - HARRY’S BEDROOM - SAME TIME - DUSK  "> An EYE
                shimmers in a SHARD of SILVERED GLASS. HARRY POTTER’S eye. He tosses the mirror
                inside a LUMPY RUCKSACK, than adds a LOCKET, a Daily Prophet CLIPPING entitled
                “Dumbledore Remembered” (above which is a PHOTOGRAPH of its author, ELPHIAS DOGE
                with DUMBLEDORE) and a NOTEBOOK filled with scribblings on Horcruxes and, in large
                block letters, the initials “R.A.B.” He gives the rucksack a shake, then glances
                about to see if he’s forgotten anything. The room looks as if it’s been bottled up
                and shaken. Dresser drawers turned out, floor covered in detritus. </stage>
            <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Come now, Dudley. Hurry up! <stage> Harry steps to the window,
                    peers to the driveway below. UNCLE VERNON rolls a large STEAMER TRUNK towards
                    his car, followed by DUDLEY, who tugs an equally large TRUNK of his own. Harry
                    speaks to HEDWIG. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Time for the teary farewell. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" STAIRWELL/FRONT HALLWAY - DUSK (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry drops
                down the stairs. The house feels barren, desolate. Aunt Petunia stands at the mouth
                of the kitchen, looking around. Seeing her, Harry comes to as top. </stage>
            <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA"> I’ve lived in this house twenty years. And now -- in a single
                night -- I’m expected to leave. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> They’ll torture you. Even Dudley. If they think you know where I’m
                going, they’ll stop at noth- </sp>
            <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA"> You think I don’t know that? You think I don’t know what they’re
                capable of? <stage> Her eyes pierce Harry’s. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA"> You didn’t just lose a mother that night in Godric’s Hollow, you
                know. I lost a sister. <stage> Harry studies her, taken aback. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Do you have any? Magic? </sp>
            <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA"> What a cruel thing to ask. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" PRIVET DRIVE - DUSK (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Uncle Vernon tests the
                strap binding the trunks to as mall TRAILER hitched to the back of the Dursley car,
                then squints awkwardly at Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Well, this is goodbye then, boy. <stage> Harry, standing by the
                    front door, nods, eyes Petunia, who sits in the front passenger seat, a ghost
                    behind the glass. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUDLEY"> I don’t understand. Isn’t he coming with us? </sp>
            <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Who? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUDLEY"> Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Absolutely not. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUDLEY"> Why? </sp>
            <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Well, because -- he doesn’t want to, do you, boy? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Absolutely not. Besides, I’m just a waste of space. Isn’t that right,
                Vernon? Uncle Vernon stares hard at Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON"> Come on, Dudley, we’re off. <stage> Uncle Vernon starts for the
                    car. Dudley hesitates, then crosses the lawn to Harry, extends his hand.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUDLEY"> I don’t think you’re a waste of space. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well... thanks. Harry grips Dudley’s hand, then watches his cousin
                turn and lope back across the lawn. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>under his breath</stage> See you, Big D. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DURSLEY HOUSE - BOTTOM FLOOR - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry
                stands, rucksack over his shoulder, Hedwig’s cage in hand. Somewhere, nearby, a
                CLOCK TICKS. Otherwise, all is still. Utterly quiet. He glances about the house,
                full of shadows, like ghosts. His eyes burn with bitterness. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Good riddance. <stage> His eyes shift. The last rays of sunlight lay,
                    like as tain, upon a SMALL CUPBOARD DOOR below the stairs. He lets the rucksack
                    slip from his shoulder. Sets down the cage. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CUPBOARD UNDERNEATH THE STAIRS - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> The door
                opens. Harry’s face appears. Motes of dust dance before his eyes. He peers into the
                shadows, into his past. A DEAD SPIDER hangs within an ancient web. A REGIMENT of TOY
                SOLDIERS -- broken and draped with dust-- line a listing shelf. As the SUN withdraws
                from the hallway, a tremor passes through Harry’s face and then...A TREMENDOUS ROAR
                murders the silence, the roar of a MOTOR BIKE. Harry straightens -- half-believing
                he’s dreamed it into existence -- and STRIKES his head on the low door frame.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HALLWAY/KITCHEN - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Harry pelts down the
                dark hall as OPAQUE SHAPES race past the windows. He trips past Hedwig’s cage,
                sending itWOBBLING and flings open the front door. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FRONT DOOR - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> HERMIONE flings her
                arms around Harry. RON gives him a clap on the back. Others emerge from the shadows:
                FRED, GEORGE, BILL, FLEUR, TONKS, LUPIN, ARTHUR WEASLEY, MADEYE MOODY, KINGSLEY
                SHACKLEBOLT and a small, dirty, hangdog man, MUNDUNGUS FLETCHER. Lastly, HAGRID
                dismounts a MOTORBIKE, strips a pair of fly-specked goggles from his face and yanks
                a SMALL TWITTERING BIRD from his beard. </stage>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> All righ’, ‘arry? Yeh look fit. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Yeah, he’s ruddy gorgeous. What say we get undercover before someone
                murders him. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" SITTING ROOM/KITCHEN - NIGHT  "> Everyone spills down the
                hallway into the sitting room. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I thought you were looking after the Prime Minister, Kingsley. </sp>
            <sp who="#SHACKLEBOLT"> You’re more important. Harry grins, then a tall, red-headed man
                    <stage>BILL WEASLEY</stage> is before him, hand extended. His face is
                horriblySCARRED. </sp>
            <sp who="#BILL"> Hello, Harry. Bill Weasley. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Wasn’t always this handsome. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Dead ugly. </sp>
            <sp who="#BILL">
                <stage>smiling; to Harry</stage> True enough. Owe it all to a werewolf by name of
                Greyback. Hope to repay the favor one day. </sp>
            <sp who="#FLEUR">
                <stage>a kiss to the cheek</stage> You are still beautiful to me, William. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> Just remember, Fleur, once you’re married: Bill takes his steaks on
                the raw side now. </sp>
            <sp who="#TONKS"> My husband, the joker. By the way, wait until you hear the news! Remus
                and I are - </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> All right, all right! You’ll all have time for a cozy catch-up later!
                We’ve got to get the hell out of here and soon! <stage> Moody drops some SACKS at
                    his feet. Turns to Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Potter, you’re underage, which means you’ve still got the Trace on
                you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The Trace? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> You sneeze and the Ministry willk now who wipes your nose. Point is,
                we have to use those means of transport the Trace can’t detect: brooms, thestrals
                and the like. We’ll go in pairs. That way if anyone’s out there waiting for us-- and
                I reckon there will be -- they won’t know which Harry Potter is the real one. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The real one...? <stage> Moody draws a FLASK from his cloak.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> I believe you’re familiar with this particular brew. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No! Absolutely not! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>a sigh</stage> I told you he’d take it well. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> If you think I’m going to let people risk their lives for me - </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Never done that before, have we? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> This is different. Taking that. Becoming me -- no. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Well, none of us really fancy it, mate. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Yeah, imagine if something went wrong and we were stuck as scrawny,
                specky gits forever. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Everyone here’s of age, Potter, and they’ve all agreed to take the
                risk. </sp>
            <sp who="#MUNDUNGUS"> Technically, I’ve been coerced. <stage>turning to Harry and
                    extending his hand</stage> Mundungus Fletcher, Mr. Potter. I’ve always been a
                huge admirer. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Nip it, Mundungus! All right, Granger, as discussed. <stage> Hermione
                    grabs a tuft of Harry’s hair -- yanks. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Blimey, Hermione! </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Straight in here, if you please. <stage> Moody holds out the flask,
                    un-stoppered now. The potion inside begins to spit forth smoke. He hands it to
                    George. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> For those of you who haven’t taken Polyjuice Potion before, fair
                warning. It tastes like goblin piss. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Have a lot of experience with that, do you, Mad-Eye? <stage> Moody’s
                    eye rotates menacingly onto Fred. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Just trying to defuse the tension. <stage> Fred takes the flask from
                    George, followed by Ron, Hermione, Fleur and a less than overjoyed Mundungus. He
                    scowls as the potion trickles past his lips and seconds later, his features --
                    like those of the others -- begin to bubble like hot wax. As the transformation
                    completes, seven Harry Potters stand in the tiny kitchen. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FRED #GEORGE"> Wow -- we’re identical! </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Not yet you aren’t. <stage> Moody pulls the ties on the SACKS and
                    pulls out SEVEN IDENTICAL OUTFITS. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Don’t have something a bit more sporty, do you? </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Yes, don’t fancy this color at all. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Fancy this: You’re not you, so shut it and strip. <stage>to
                    Harry</stage> You’ll need to change too, Potter. <stage> Harry, a bit
                    self-consciously, begins to strip down. The others, meanwhile, appear
                    unconcerned to be exposingHarry’s body. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FLEUR"> Bill, look away -- I’m ‘ideous. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>smirking</stage> I knew Ginny was lying about that tattoo. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>wobbling a bit</stage> Harry, your eyesight really is awful. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Blimey. I almost forgot. <stage> Mad-Eye rummages in his pocket, pulls
                    out a fistful of EYE-GLASSES. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Right then. We’ll be pairing off. Each Potter will have a protector.
                As for you, Harry... </sp>
            <sp who="#ALL"> Yes? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> The real Harry! Where the devil are you, anyway? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Here. <stage> Moody’s eye rotates onto the real Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> You’ll ride with Hagrid. </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Brought yeh here sixteen years ago when you were barely bigger than a
                Bowtruckle. Seems only righ’ I should be the one ter take yeh away. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Yeah, it’s all very touching. Let’s go. <stage> As they file out,
                    grabs his rucksack and ponders Hedwig in her cage. He snaps open the wire door
                    and she flutters out, swoops down the hallway and soars out the open door. Harry
                    glances once more down the hall, at the cupboard under the stairs, then exits.
                    He HOLD ON Hedwig’s empty cage. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" PRIVET DRIVE - NIGHT  "> The other six Harrys sit upon
                thestrals and brooms. Hagrid sits astride a motorbike, goggles on. As the real Harry
                appears, Hagrid taps the sidecar and Harry drops in. </stage>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Good luck, everyone. On the count of three. One... two --<stage>
                    Hagrid kicks the motorbike to life, lurches forward. Hedwig swoops upward and
                    beats toward the greasy moon. As Hagrid roars into the sky, Harry twists round,
                    watching one Harry Potter after another whip past, watching Privet Drive grow
                    smaller, his eyes stinging in the wind, briefly lost in the moment, when...
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" SKY - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> ... a DISTURBANCE FILLS THE AIR.
                Harry turns away, looks up. DEATH EATERS drop from the clouds, surround the others.
                FLASHES of GREEN LIGHT splinter the darkness. Sparks explode on the bike’s chassis
                and Hagrid HOWLS in fury. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hagrid! We’ve got to help the others! </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Can’t do it, ‘arry. My job’s ter get you where we’re goin’ safe ‘n
                sound -- Mad-Eye’s orders! <stage> Before Harry can reply, FOUR DEATH EATERS jet out
                    of the darkness, robes snapping in the wind. As one, their wands rise. Hagrid
                    slams his hand onto a PURPLE BUTTON. With an EAR-SHATTERING BLAST, the motorbike
                    quivers andFLAMES BELCH from the exhaust pipe. The Death Eaters SCREAM, robes
                    afire, and pinwheel away, freefalling towards the earth. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What was that? </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Dragon fire! <stage> More DEATH EATERS SWOOP from the sky, give
                    chase. Hagrid DIVES, plummeting for the ground, trying desperately to shake
                    them. Harry watches the earth rushing towards them, grimacing as the bike...
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" MOTORWAY - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> ... SLAMS onto the
                asphalt and slaloms wildly as Hagrid... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TUNNEL - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> ...roars into a tunnel,
                the Death Eaters still in pursuit. Hagrid leans wildly from side to side, eluding
                the flashes of light from the Death Eaters’ wands. Sparks skitter off the tunnel and
                shower down as the sidecar rides up into the air repeatedly, then slams down onto
                the roadway. Harry glances back, sees the DeathEaters closing when LIGHT FILLS THE
                TUNNEL and HAGRID ROARS. Turning back, Harry sees a HUGE LORRY rushing towards them.
                As the HEADLIGHTS GROW LARGE, Hagrid steers the motorbike directly into them -- then
                past -- and up the rounded side of the tunnel. The motorbike loops-the-loop and
                Harry dangles briefly, watching -- upside down -- as two Death Eaters fly smack into
                the lorry -- before the motorbike comes round right side up, shoots out... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" SKY - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> ... of the tunnel and soars
                back into the starry sky. Hagrid and Harry soar higher, the air CRACKLING
                withELECTRICITY as... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" PYLONS - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> ... MASSIVE ELECTRICAL
                PYLONS appear in the darkness. As Hagrid weaves through the towers, a gang of Death
                Eaters jet INTO VIEW. Harry fires a volley of Stunning Spells, sending a pair of
                Death Eaters into the SIZZLING wires where they dangle briefly, spasming, before
                plummeting into the darkness. Harry fires again and watches two others take evasive
                measures... unaware of the Death Eater closing in from behind. Finally he turns. The
                Death Eater grins, wand twitching, when...Hedwig swoops down, flaying the Death
                Eater’s wand hand. Harry grins triumphantly when... a mad volley of WAND BLASTS
                ricochet off the motorbike and Hedwig is gone. Harry glances about desperately,
                when: </stage>
            <sp who="#DEATHEATER"> That’s him! The real one! <stage> The remaining Death Eaters fall
                    back and disappear. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Hol’ tight, ‘arry! We’ve got ter get yeh out of here! <stage> Hagrid
                    hits the purple button again and the motorbike rockets forth. Harry gazes
                    bleakly behind... then winces, eyes rolling back in his head. Gripping his scar,
                    he squints toward the horizon and sees something closing on them. It looks like
                    smoke, then begins to take shape. Voldemort. Flying. Slowly, Harry raises his
                    wand. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hagrid... HAGRID...! <stage> Harry lets out a primal scream, his eyes
                    clenched shut in pain, his wand hand trembling as he points it blindly.
                    Voldemort’s snake-like face draws near, his wand trained on Harry. Harry’s arm
                    goes slack, his wand dropping... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Avada... </sp>
            <stage>Abruptly, Harry’s arm rises as if on a string, drawn up by the wand trembling in
                his hand. GOLD FIRE spits forth and -- Crack! -- SPARKS skitter up the chassis of
                the motorbike. Harry wheels and -- for a split second -- is face to face with
                Voldemort, whose eyes drift, staring -- with something like fear -- at Harry’s wand.
                Then -- whoosh! -- Voldemort peels backward and away, evaporating like smoke. Just
                then... ... the motorbike’s engine HICCUPS and Hagrid and Harry begin to drop.
                PUTT... PUTT... PUTT... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" THE BURROW - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> The motorbike splashes down
                into the reeds, sputters, then cuts out altogether in a SMOKING HISSSSS. Harry
                glances about. A door opens in a crooked house. TWO SILHOUETTES appear, dash forward
                -- MRS. WEASLEY andGINNY. </stage>
            <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Harry! Hagrid! What happened?! Have you seen the others? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Is no one back yet? <stage> He looks from Mrs. Weasley to Ginny. Ginny
                    shakes her head. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> They were on us from the star’, Molly -- the Death Eaters. And
                You-Know-Who as well. <stage> Molly Weasley’s face betrays panic, but she fights it
                    back. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Well, thank goodness you two are all right. </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Haven’t go’ any brandy, have yeh, Molly? Fer medicinal purposes?
                    <stage> She nods, leads him toward the house. Once out of earshot, Harry turns
                    expectantly to Ginny. She looks frightened. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Ron and Tonks should’ve already been back. Dad and Fred as well.
                    <stage> Suddenly, several yards away, a BLUE LIGHT burns in the darkness. Harry
                    and Ginny rush towards it just as Lupin materializes, cradling an unconscious
                    “Harry,” clothes torn, head awash in BLOOD. Harry takes in the surreal tableau,
                    then watches “himself” transform into George, who bears the true damage. Ginny’s
                    hands fly to her face. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Oh my God! George! </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> The house! Quickly! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" WEASLEY HOUSE - SITTING ROOM - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Lupin
                and Harry drop George onto the sofa, where his head rolls into the lamplight, the
                blood more shocking here. Molly Weasley screams. George’s ear is gone. </stage>
            <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> My boy! My darling boy! What’ve they done to you?! <stage> Harry
                    looks on miserably -- anger and guilt clashing within him -- when Lupin grabs a
                    fistful of his shirt and hurls him against the wall. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Remus! What’re you doing! </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> What creature sat in the corner the first time that Harry Potter
                visited my office at Hogwarts! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Are you mad...? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> WHAT CREATURE! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> A grindylow! <stage> Lupin releases Harry, turns back to the others.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> We’ve been betrayed. Voldemort knew you were being moved tonight. I
                had to make sure you weren’t an imposter. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who did this to him? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> Snape. <stage>nodding to George</stage> He’ll be fine, Molly. But
                that’s Dark Magic. The damage is done. <stage> She simply nods, weeping, dabbing at
                    George’s face. blue glow glimmers against the window, where Hagrid stands. A
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Someone else is back. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" YARD (THE BURROW) - NIGHT (SECONDS LATER)  "> Hermione and
                Kingsley stand together, looking shaken. As the others rush forward, Kingsley points
                his wand at Lupin. </stage>
            <sp who="#SHACKLEBOLT"> The last words Albus Dumbledore spoke to the pair of us? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> ‘Harry is the best hope we have. Trust him.’ Shacklebolt lowers his
                wand, wheels on Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#SHACKLEBOLT"> What gave you away? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hedwig -- I think. She was trying to protect me --<stage> Just then,
                    the yard glows with BLUE LIGHT and one pair after another materialize: Fred
                    &amp; Mr. Weasley, Bill &amp; Fleur, Ron &amp; Tonks. Ron is still “Harry,” but
                    Hermione doesn’t hesitate, enveloping him in a fierce hug. As he transforms back
                    into his own battle-weary self, he looks mildly abashed to be in such close
                    proximity to Hermione. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Hey ya -- Well... thanks. </sp>
            <sp who="#TONKS"> Deserves that. Brilliant, he was. Wouldn’t be standing here without
                him. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Really? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>breaking free ofher</stage> Always the tone of surprise. </sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> Are we the last? Where’s George? <stage> Suddenly... silence.
                    Mr. Weasley eyes all, turns toLupin. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> Remus. Where’s my son? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" WEASLEY HOUSE - SITTING ROOM - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Arthur
                Weasley, trailed by the others, stops dead. Molly looks up, her face saying it all.
                Fred comes up on his father’s shoulder, eyes stinging with tears as he sees his
                brother. As if sensing them, George stirs. </stage>
            <sp who="#FRED"> How do you feel, Georgie? </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Saint-like. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Come again? <stage> George opens his eyes, lifts a blood-crusted
                    finger, and points to the dark cavity in the side of his skull. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Saint-like... You see, I’m holy. Holey, Fred, geddit? </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> With the whole wide world of ear- related humor at your disposal, you
                go for holey? Pathetic. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Reckon I’m still better-looking than you. Better-looking thanBill,
                that’s for sure. <stage> Bill doesn’t smile. Next to him, Fleur looks equally grim.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BILL"> Mad-Eye’s dead. <stage> The room goes still. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BILL"> Mundungus took one look atVoldemort and Disapparated. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> Mad-Eye reckoned You-Know-Who would expect the real Harry to be with
                the most skilled Auror. He knew he’d be in the most danger. </sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> It doesn’t explain how they knew we were moving Harry tonight.
                    <stage> The room grows quiet. Eyes shift. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Wha’? One of us? Tha’s mad. I’d wager me life it wasn’ none of you
                lot. An’ if it was me I’d kno’, wouldn’ I? Talk in me sleep on occasion, I’ll admit,
                but there’s only Fang aroun’ ter hear an’ mostly it’s gibberish an’ besides I’d cut
                me tongue out ‘fore ‘d betray ‘arry e’en in me dreams--<stage> Hagrid stops,
                    blinking miserably. Suddenly, all smile. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Wha’s so funny! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I trust you with my life, Hagrid. I trust everyone in this room.
                Understood? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> Understood. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> ’Ear, ’ear. <stage> Fred nods approvingly to his brother.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Better. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" RON’S ROOM - NIGHT (LATER)  "> Shadows cling to the ceiling.
                Harry tosses fitfully, something bedeviling his sleep. Suddenly, his SCAR CONTRACTS.
                He GRIMACES. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> You lied to me, Ollivander! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" MALFOY MANOR - CELLAR - NIGHT  "> At the bottom of a run of
                rotting wooden stairs, Wormtail props up an emaciated OLLIVANDER. In the cracked
                surface of a TALL MIRROR, we see Voldemort reflected at the top of the stairs -- an
                angry silhouette. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> No! No! I believed a different wand would work, I swear! </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Then explain this! <stage> Voldemort extends his skeletal fingers.
                    Lucius Malfoy’s wand lies shattered upon his ghostly skin. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> But it makes no sense... </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Perhaps our friend’s loyalties lie elsewhere, Wormtail. </sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> No! There must be a way! I’ll think of something else! </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> I hope so, Ollivander, for your sake. I won’t be so forgiving next
                time... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" RON’S ROOM - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> Harry awakens with a
                GASP, eyes flashing in the darkness. He eyes the shadows above him, then looks down
                at his hand where his wand glimmers in the moonlight. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" STAIRCASE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER) "> Rucksack slung over his
                shoulder, Harry picks his way softly down the spiraling steps, past silent doorways,
                slipping in and out of shadow. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" YARD - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER) "> Harry emerges into the night,
                shifting the rucksack as he eyes the reeds shifting eerily in the darkness. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Going somewhere? </sp>
            <stage>Harry stiffens, turns to meet Ron’s accusatory gaze, then continues on.</stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No one else is going to die. Not for me. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> For you? You think Mad-eye died for you? You think George took that
                curse for you? You may be the Chosen One, mate, but this is a whole lot bigger than
                that. <stage> Harry stares at Ron. The air is tense. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Come with me. Now. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> And leave Hermione? Are you mad? We wouldn’t last two days without her.
                    <stage>glancing around</stage> Don’t tell her I said that. (back to Harry)
                Besides, you’ve still got theTrace on you. And there’s the wedding... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Wedding? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bill and Fleur. Mum’s been planning it for months. Only thing that’s
                kept her sane, Ir eckon. She’ll kill me if I miss it. Kill you too. Rather go face
                to face with You-Know-Who if I’m honest. <stage> Ron tries a smile, but Harry looks
                    foul. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I don’t care about a bloody wedding -- no matter whose it is. I have
                to start searching for the Horcruxes. It’s the only chance we have to beat him. And
                the longer we wait the stronger he gets. <stage> Ron just stares at Harry, calm,
                    poised. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Tonight’s not the night, mate. You’d only be doing him a favor. <stage>
                    Harry stares at Ron -- incensed by his cool demeanor and common sense. Finally,
                    he turns away, tosses the rucksack in frustration. For a moment they stand like
                    this, Harry’s back to Ron. Silent. Finally Ron speaks. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Do you think he knows? <stage> Harry turns his head halfway, but doesn’t
                    speak. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I mean, they’re bits of his soul, the Horcruxes. Bits of him. When
                Dumbledore destroyed the ring and you destroyed Tom Riddle’s diary all those years
                ago -- he must’ve felt something right? <stage> Harry ponders this, but remains
                    silent. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What I’m saying is, if we do this thing right, if we find the Horcruxes
                and begin to destroy them one by one... <stage> Harry waits. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Won’t he know he’s being hunted? <stage> Still Harry says nothing.
                    Silence descends once more, then: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> All together now! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" WEASLEY HOUSE - ORCHARD - MORNING  "> Bird’s-eye view: An
                ENORMOUS CIRCLE of SILK lies flat upon the ground. As Hagrid looks on, Arthur, Bill,
                Ron and Fred stand on its periphery, wands poised. </stage>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> One. Two. Three! <stage> The silk rises, pitching itself into
                    a perfect wedding marquee, trembling wondrously in the morning breeze... then
                    collapses. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" KITCHEN - MORNING (SECONDS LATER)  "> The DAILY PROPHET lies in
                f.g., HEADLINE SCREAMING: “DUMBLEDORE’S DARK SECRETS.” We HEAR FOOTSTEPS descend the
                stairs... then Harry’s blurry figure steps INTO FOCUS and takes the paper for a
                closer inspection. RITA SKEETER grins up at him, holding a BOOK entitled The Life
                and Lies of Albus Dumbledore. A bit further down, another headline: “Think You Know
                Dumbledore? Think Again!” </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Were you going to tell me? <stage> Harry turns, finds Ginny in
                    the doorway in a beautiful dress. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> And Ron and Hermione. They’ll not be going back to Hogwarts either?
                    <stage> Harry stares at her. She looks excruciatingly beautiful in the light
                    streaming through the window. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> I see. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dumbledore didn’t want anyone to know what it is we’re doing. If I
                tell you, I’d be betraying him. </sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Zip me up, will you. <stage> She turns. The dress is open to the small
                    of her back. Harry steps forward and takes the zipper. As the panels close,
                    concealing her skin, his fingers linger at the top, lightly brushing the nape of
                    her neck. They stand like this, utterly still, the moment fraught. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Seems silly, doesn’t it? A wedding. Given everything that’s going on. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Maybe that’s the best reason to have it. Because of everything that’s
                going on. <stage> Her chin turns, coming into profile, her face very close. Then she
                    folds into him and they are kissing. Long. Deep. George wanders in brushing his
                    teeth, pours himself a cup of tea and, sticking the toothbrush in his ear-hole,
                    leans back against the stove for a sip. Ginny -- sensing something -- opens her
                    eyes and JUMPS. Harry wheels. George winks, tips his cup in their direction.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Morning. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ORCHARD - SAME TIME - MORNING  "> Arthur stands looking at the
                marquee from his POV: perfect. </stage>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> How’s it look on your end, boys? <stage> Ron and Fred look:
                    bent, mangled. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Brilliant! <stage> Just then, the silk snaps and the trees in the
                    surrounding orchard shiver in a rush of wind. Everyone steps clear of the
                    marquee and watches a TALL WIZARD withGRIZZLED HAIR and SCARRED CHEEK
                    materialize. RUFUS SCRIMGEOUR. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Bloody hell, what’s the Minister of Magic doing here? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Dunno. But something tells me he didn’t come to give away the bride.
            </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" WEASLEY HOUSE - SITTING ROOM - MOMENTS LATER  "> Harry enters,
                trailed by Ron and Hermione. Scrimgeour gestures the trio to the sofa. Harry eyes
                Scrimgeour with thinly concealed contempt. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> To what do we owe the pleasure, Minister? </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> I think we both know the answer to that question, Mr. Potter.
                    <stage> Scrimgeour pitches a CLOTH BAG onto the table before them. The trio
                    regard it curiously, exchange glances. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And this would be...? </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> Don’t be coy, Mr. Potter. Mr. Weasley. Would you say you were
                close to your former Headmaster? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Dumbledore? And me? I dunno. I reckon I was just another Weasley to him.
                He was always polite -- </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> And you, Miss Granger? How would you characterize your
                relationship? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We were friendly, not close like Harry, but -- </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What’s this all about? </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> This. Despite the fact that neither of your friends appear to
                have been particularly close to their recently deceasedHeadmaster, he saw fit to
                remember them in his will. Now why do you suppose that would be? <stage> Harry, Ron
                    and Hermione exchange glances again. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No idea. </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> Come now, you don’t expect me to believe... <stage> Scrimgeour
                    reaches into his cloak, removes a SCROLL OF PARCHMENT. READS: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> ‘Herein is set forth the Last Will and Testament of Albus
                Percival Wulfric Brian Dumbledore. First, to Ronald Bilius Weasley, I leave my
                Deluminator, a device of my own making, in the hope that -- when things seem most
                dark -- it will show him the light.’ <stage> Scrimgeour removes a SMALL SILVER
                    OBJECT from the bag. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Dumbledore left this? For me? Brilliant. Er -- what is it? <stage> Ron
                    CLICKS it and all the light rushes from the lamps into the Deluminator, throwing
                    the room into total darkness. He CLICKS it again and light flies back to the
                    lamps. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Wicked. </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> ‘To Miss Hermione Jean Granger, I leave my copy of The Tales of
                Beedle the Bard, in the hope that she will find it entertaining and instructive.’
                    <stage> Scrimgeour reaches into the bag once again and retrieves a SMALL BOOK,
                    its binding stained and peeling in places. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Mum used to read me those! The Wizard and the Hopping Pot, Babbitty
                Rabbity and her Cackling Stump... <stage> Harry and Hermione stare blankly at him.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Oh, c’mon! Beedle’s stories are famous! Babbity Rabbitty? No...? <stage>
                    Scrimgeour eyes Ron with mild annoyance, continues. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> ‘To Harry James Potter, I leave the Snitch he caught in his first
                Quidditch match at Hogwarts, as a reminder of the rewards of perseverance and skill.
                    <stage> Scrimgeour places the tiny golden orb onto Harry’s palm, where it
                    glimmers dully. Harry studies it, then looks up. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> That’s it then? </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> Not quite. Dumbledore left you a second bequest: The Sword of
                Godric Gryffindor. Unfortunately, the Sword of Gryffindor was not Dumbledore’s to
                give away. As an important historical artifact, it belongs... </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> To Harry! It belongs to Harry! It chose him! It came to him in the
                Chamber of Secrets when he most needed it! </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> The sword may present itself to any worthy Gryffindor, Miss
                Granger. That does not make it that wizard’s property. And in any event the current
                whereabouts of the sword are unknown. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Excuse me? </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> The sword is missing. <stage>before Harry can pursue</stage> I
                won’t pretend to be your friend, Mr. Potter. But I assure you I’m not your enemy. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’ll forgive me, Minister. But <stage> it’s a little hard to tell
                    the difference these days. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> Dumbledore said something very<stage> similar the last time we
                    spoke. Scrimgeour gazes out the window, eyes haunted. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Where is your guard, sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#SCRIMGEOUR"> I came alone. I don’t really need<stage> them anymore... He turns
                    then, exits. MUSIC IS HEARD and LAUGHTER... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="/EXT. MARQUEE - NIGHT (HOURS LATER)  "> The wedding party is in
                full swing. Harry, in dress robes, stands on the periphery, absently FINGERING THE
                SNITCH as Bill and Fleur twirl madly within a clapping circle of well-wishers.
                Harry’s gaze drifts: to Ginny, laughing as Fred and George rush the dance floor,
                briefly sweep Fleur away from Bill, then begin to dance with each other; to
                Hermione, stunning in black silk: to Ron, who ignores all, his eyes focused entirely
                on Hermione. Far across the garden, Hagrid wends through the tables in his horrible
                hairy suit and presents a SLICE OF CAKE to a pleased OLYMPE MAXIME. Nearby, Tonks,
                hand to her belly, leans forward and WHISPERS something to Mrs. Weasley, who reacts
                with happy surprise. Harry studies Tonks’ belly... </stage>
            <sp who="#LUPIN">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> We want you to be the godfather. <stage> Harry turns, sees Lupin
                    standing behind, staring at Tonks with affection. As his eyes shift to Harry,
                    Harry sputters: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You mean -- But that’s brilliant -- I... don’t know what to say. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> Say yes. Lupin grins, claps Harry on the shoulder and hikes off into
                the darkness, joining the WIZARDS STANDING GUARD in the garden’s deepest shadows.
                Harry looks back to Tonks, then notices a slight, TUFTY-HAIRED WIZARD <stage>ELPHIAS
                    DOGE</stage> sitting alone at a table just beyond her. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Hello, Harry! LUNA LOVEGOOD approaches in the company of a cross-eyed
                wizard <stage>XENOPHILIUS LOVEGOOD</stage> with shoulder-length white hair the
                texture of candy floss. Both wear robes the color of egg yolk. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Oh, I’ve interrupted a deep thought, haven’t I? I can see it growing
                smaller in your eyes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No, ’course not. How are you, Luna? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Very well. I was bitten by a garden gnome only moments ago. <stage> She
                    holds up her finger, which is sheathed in blood. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Gnome saliva is enormously beneficial! Xenophilius
                Lovegood. We live just over the hill! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Nice to meet you, sir. <stage> Lovegood suddenly leans close, WHISPERS
                    FIERCELY: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> I trust you know, Mr. Potter, that we at The Quibbler,
                unlike those toadies at the Daily Prophet, fully supported Dumbledore during his
                lifetime and in his death support you just as fully. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Come, Daddy. Harry doesn’t want to talk to us right now. He’s just too
                nice to say so. <stage> Lovegood’s eyes burn with righteousness, a TRIANGULAR EYE
                    dangling from a chain around his neck. As Luna pulls him away, Harry glances
                    once again across the garden. </stage></sp>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - MOMENTS LATER ELPHIAS DOGE sits alone, smiling absently as he
                observes the happy goings-on. Then: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir? May I sit down? </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> Mr. Potter! By all means! <stage> In a nervous flutter, Doge
                    pours Harry a goblet of champagne. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I found what you wrote in theDaily Prophet very moving, sir. I take it
                you knew Professor Dumbledore well? </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> I certainly knew him the longest, if you don’t count his brother
                Aberforth -- and somehow, people never do seem to count Aberforth. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I never even knew he had a brother, sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> Yes, well, Dumbledore was always very private. Even as a boy. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir, I was wondering if you’d had much contact with him before he
                died. </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> The occasional owl. Though it was strange... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Strange, sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> It was the owls themselves. They often arrived in distress. It
                was clear they’d traveled great distances in some cases. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Could you tell me from where they’d come, sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> I’m afraid not. Albus’ messages mostly referenced our days
                together as schoolboys. They were surprisingly intimate. When he did speak of his
                current activities his words would turn elliptical. Still, I sensed he was under
                great stress. Why do you ask? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Just curious. I was... close to Professor Dumbledore. </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> Well, he treasured you, Mr. Potter, I can attest to that. I can
                also tell you that when a person passes, it’s only natural to rue the things left
                unsaid, to regret the question never asked. I knew Albus nigh on 100 years, but in
                many ways he will always remain a riddle even to me. </sp>
            <sp who="#WOMAN">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Don’t despair, Elphias. I’m told he’s been thoroughly unriddled
                byRita Skeeter. In 800 pages no less. <stage> Harry and Doge turn, study the profile
                    of an ANCIENT WITCH (MURIEL) sitting at an adjacent table, a glass of champagne
                    cradled in the bony fingers of one hand. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> That woman is a vulture, Muriel, and you well know it. </sp>
            <sp who="#MURIEL"> Someone has to pick the bones to get at the truth. I read your
                obituary, Elphias. Lovely. But you did skate over some of the sticky patches in
                Dumbledore’s life. </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> I’m sorry you think so, Muriel. I assure you I was writing from
                the heart. </sp>
            <sp who="#MURIEL"> Yes, well, Rita Skeeter hasn’t made that mistake, I’m sure. Word has
                it someone talked to her, someone who knew the Dumbledore family well. You and I
                both know who that is, Elphias. </sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> A monstrous betrayal. I can only conclude the rumors are true
                and that she has become untethered. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who are you talking about? </sp>
            <sp who="#MURIEL"> Well, I don’t suppose it’ll be a secret once the book comes out.
                    <stage>relishing the moment</stage> Bathilda Bagshot. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who? </sp>
            <sp who="#MURIEL"> Who? Bathilda Bagshot! My god, boy, she’s only the most celebrated
                magical historian of the last century. Don’t they read History of Magic at Hogwarts
                anymore? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Oh, right. Slipped my mind... </sp>
            <sp who="#MURIEL"> She knew the Dumbledores as well as anyone. She’d have letters,
                perhaps an interesting photograph or two. I’m sure Rita Skeeter would have thought
                it well worth a trip to Godric’s Hollow to take a peek into that old bird’s rattled
                cage. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Godric’s Hollow? Bathilda Bagshot lives in Godric’s Hollow? </sp>
            <sp who="#MURIEL"> For years now. That’s where she first met Dumbledore. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Excuse me? You don’t mean to say Dumbledore lived there too? </sp>
            <sp who="#MURIEL"> Of course. The family moved thereafter his father killed those three
                Muggles. It was quite the scandal. <stage>eyeing him</stage> Honestly, my boy, are
                you sure you knew him at all? <stage> Harry sits, speechless, then his eye catches a
                    shooting star -- or what appears to be. As it plummets, it grows, gaining speed
                    until it slices through the canopy, exploding in a burst of light. All goes
                    SILENT as a SILVER LYNX -- graceful and gleaming -- MATERIALIZES amid the crowd.
                    When it speaks, the Patronus has Shacklebolt’s sonorous voice. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PATRONUS"> The Ministry has fallen. The Minister of Magic is dead. They are
                coming... <stage> The lynx vanishes. A SCREAM shreds the silence. Then: chaos.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#ELPHIASDOGE"> Nice meeting you, Mr. Potter! <stage> Doge extends his hand
                    toward Harry when -- CRACK! -- he DISAPPARATES. Seconds later, the ancient witch
                    has done the same. Harry scans the scattering crowd and meets Ginny’s eyes, as
                    she gets buffeted about. He pelts toward her, bouncing between bodies, losing
                    sight of her. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron! Ron! <stage> Harry turns, sees Hermione glancing about
                    frantically. As she turns, Ron comes INTO VIEW, pushes toward her. Suddenly the
                    canopy above turns to ribbons as DEATH EATERS -- in dark cloaks and masks --
                    descend into the crowd. Arthur, Fred and George wield their wands. Harry sees a
                    flower fall from Fleur’s hair, watches it crushed underfoot, then catches sight
                    of Ginny through the madness as she draws her own wand, copper hair gleaming,
                    eyes flashing. He starts toward her, when... Lupin crashes in, spinning him
                    roughly round. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> Harry! Go! Go! <stage> A HAND REACHES OUT AND GRABS HIS. He looks.
                    It’s Hermione, clutching Ron’s hand with her other. She closes her eyes and a
                    great WHOOSHING SOUND fills Harry’s ears. He takes one last desperate look at
                    Ginny as he is thrown up and back in a WHIRLWIND and all goes BLACK. A HORN
                    BLARES as... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" SHAFTESBURY AVENUE (PICCADILLY) - NIGHT  "> ...a DOUBLE-DECKER
                BUS careens within inches of Harry, Ron and Hermione as they stumble INTO VIEW, the
                streets teeming with drunken pub crawlers. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Where are we? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Shaftesbury Avenue. I used to come here to the theater with my mum
                and dad. Just popped into my head. I don’t know why... <stage> They hurry on,
                    glancing over their shoulders at the DARK SHAPES that move within the crowd
                    behind them, STRANGERS bumping by, FACES passing in a paranoiac BLUR: a DRUNKEN
                    MAN, a CACKLING WOMAN with BLOOD-RED LIPSTICK... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> This way! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ALLEYWAY - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> As they take refuge in
                the shadows, Hermione begins to rummage through her TINY BEADED PURSE. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We need to change. <stage> Ron and Harry look at each other’s dress
                    robes. From the purse, Hermione extracts -- in quick succession -- two pairs of
                    jeans, T-shirts, and a pair of light overcoats. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> How the ruddy - </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Undetectable Extension Charm. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You’re amazing, you are. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Always the tone of surprise. <stage> As she gives the bag a shake,
                    there is LOUD echoing of heavy objects, as if something has fallen.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> That’ll be the books. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ALL-NITE CAFE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Shabby. Greasy.
                Empty. The trio slide into a booth. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Do you reckon everyone’s alright at the wedding? Maybe we should - </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> They were after you, mate. We’d just put everyone in danger going back. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron’s right. Cappuccino, please. <stage> A gum-chewing WAITRESS
                    stands behind Harry. Ron, clueless when it comes to cappuccinos, nods to
                    Hermione. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What she said. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Same. </sp>
            <sp who="#WAITRESS"> Wicked scar. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>as she exits</stage> So where do we go from here? The Leaky Cauldron? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Too dangerous. If Voldemort’s taken over the Ministry, none of the
                old places are safe. <stage> The front door SQUEALS and TWO WORKMEN enter, glance
                    idly at the trio and step to the counter. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> My rucksack. With all my things. I left it back at the Burrow -<stage>
                    Hermione is shaking her head. Harry eyes the beaded purse. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’re joking. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I’ve had the essentials packed for days. Just in case. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> By the way -- these jeans? Not my favorite. Bit tight. <stage> Hermione
                    gives him a withering glance. Harry can’t help but smile. Then his eyes shift to
                    the SMALL SECURITY MIRROR near the ceiling, see the two workmen turning.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> DOWN! <stage> The tile EXPLODES on the wall where Ron’s head had been
                    only seconds before. A rope of green light singes Hermione’s hair. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Stupefy! <stage> The JET of RED LIGHT hits the biggest Death Eater
                    straight in the face and he crumples instantly. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DEATHEATER#2"> Expulsio! <stage> The table behind Harry explodes and the spell
                    ricochets, shattering the security mirror -- sending shards raining everywhere,
                    including one that laces Hermione’s cheek -- then striking the cappuccino
                    machine, which sprays hot liquid all over the Death Eater. He BELLOWS in pain
                    and Hermione and Ron hit him with TWIN STUNNING SPELLS. As he spasms on the
                    ground, Hermione adds another for good measure: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Petrificus Totalus! <stage> He goes still. The Waitress steps from
                    the backroom. Sees the trio. The wands. Her gum bubble... POPS. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Go. <stage> She doesn’t argue. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Lock the door, get the lights. <stage> Hermione throws the bolt. Ron
                    clicks the Deluminator, pitching the cafe into shadow. Harry eyes the
                    unconscious Death Eater. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> This one’s name is Rowle. He was on the Astronomy Tower the night
                Snape killed Dumbledore. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> This is Dolohov. I recognize him from the wanted posters. <stage> Ron
                    rolls him over with his foot. Dolohov’s eyes shift in fear from Harry to
                    Hermione, then back to Ron. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> So what do we do with you, huh? Kill us if it was turned round, wouldn’t
                you? <stage> Ron’s face is hard. Hermione eyes him uneasily. He notices.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Suppose it’s him that did Mad-Eye. How would you feel then? <stage>
                    Hermione looks at Dolohov. The moment hangs, then: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s better we wipe their memories. We kill them, they’ll know we were
                here. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You’re the boss. <stage>turning to Hermione</stage> Hermione? <stage>
                    She turns, looks at him. He reaches out, wipes a trickle of blood from her
                    cheek. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You’re the best with spells. <stage> Shakily, she points her wand at
                    Dolohov. Her arm trembles. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Obliviate. </sp>
            <stage>There is a FLASH OF LIGHT and we -CUT TO: </stage>

        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" LONDON STREET -NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> The trio move quickly,
                glancing about, paranoid. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How is it they knew we were there? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Maybe you still have the Trace on you. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Can’t be. The Trace breaks at seventeen. It’s Wizarding law. <stage>
                    Hermione stops. Harry and Ron turn, look back. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We didn’t celebrate your birthday, Harry. Ginny and I -- we’d
                prepared a cake. We were going to bring it out at the end of the wedding... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione. I appreciate the thought -- honestly. But given that we were
                almost killed by a couple of Death Eaters a few minutes ago... </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Right. Perspective. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> We’ve got to get off the streets, get somewhere safe. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I have an idea. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" 12 GRIMMAULD PLACE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> A DOOR marked by
                the number 12. Harry TAPS his wand on the weathered surface and a series of METALLIC
                CLICKS are heard. The door swings open with a CREAK. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ENTRYWAY (12 GRIMMAULD PLACE) - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> 
            The GAS LAMPS spring to life, illuminating a narrow cobwebbed hallway.
            The trio glance about, then Harry takes a step forward. </stage>
            <sp who="#MOODY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Severus Snape? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Mad-Eye...? <stage> Just then a great RUSH OF COLD AIR sweeps through
                    the hallway and the trio’s tongues curl back in their mouths. Some THING shifts
                    in the shadows at the end of the hall, rising from the carpet -- tall,
                    dust-colored and terrible- looking -- then rushes toward them. It’s Dumbledore,
                    but a ghostly, worm-eaten Dumbledore, a corpse come to life, with empty eye
                    sockets and sunken face. It raises its wand and then... EXPLODES in a great
                    cloud of dust, swirling like mist in the corridor, drifting back to the carpet.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What was that about? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Mad-eye’s doing, I’d guess. In case Snape decided to come snooping.
                    <stage> Just then, a FLOORBOARD CREAKS. The trio stiffen. Slowly, Hermione draws
                    her wand, peers into the shadows. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Homenum revelio. <stage> Nothing. Hermione lowers her wand.
                    Explains. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s a spell to reveal human presence. <stage> She extends her
                    hand, watches the settling dust stream through her fingers. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We’re alone. </sp>
            <stage>DISSOLVE TO: </stage>

        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" SKY AT DAWN... "> </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" MOUNTAIN ROAD - DAWN  "> The view expands and a SMALL VILLAGE
                is revealed, swathed in mist. This has the feel of a POV. The IMAGE JUMPS and...
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" VILLAGE STREET - DAWN  "> ... the POV is MOVING now, THROUGH
                streets teeming with cloaked figures. The TONGUE that is spoken here is foreign,
                Germanic. We TURN DOWN an alleyway and the path narrows, the shadows growing more
                dense. Scratched into a wall is the SYMBOL Xenophilius Lovegood wore around his
                neck, but the POV LINGERS upon it only briefly. A SIGN comes INTO VIEW, hanging
                outside a small shop at the very end of a dark cul de sac: “GREGOROVITCH,
                WANDMAKER.” We CLOSE QUICKLY ON the shop’s door, catch a glimpse ofVOLDEMORT’S
                REFLECTION IN THE GLASS, when... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DRAWING ROOM - MORNING  "> ... Harry awakens, peering at the
                cobwebbed chandelier overhead. He sits up, looks at Hermione, asleep upon the sofa,
                her arm dangling down to where Ron lies upon the floor, her fingers only inches from
                his. Nearby, theRADIO HISSES SOFTLY, distant VOICES struggling to be heard. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Lumos. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" UPSTAIRS LANDING/CORRIDOR - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry’s
                wand BLOOMS in the darkness as he scales the stairs and reaches the landing. He
                peers into a bedroom. The drawers have been turned out. The bedsheets stripped. He
                moves on, painting the wall with wand light, illuminating an EMPTY PORTRAIT of a
                MUDDY LANDSCAPE. He studies it -- long enough that we’ll remember it -- then a
                FLOORBOARD SQUEAKS -- like the night before. Harry wheels, points his wand down the
                dark corridor adjacent. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DARK CORRIDOR - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry moves down
                the narrow corridor to its end, to a DOORWAY. He eyes the nameplate: “SIRIUS.”
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" SIRIUS’ ROOM - CONTINUOUS ACTION  "> We watch Harry enter from
                an UNSETTLINGLY LOW POV(Kreacher’s). This room, like the others, has been ransacked.
                Harry lingers by a PHOTOGRAPH. In it, FOUR YOUNG HOGWARTS STUDENTS -- JAMES POTTER,
                SIRIUS BLACK, PETER PETTIGREW and Lupin -- stand GRINNING before theWHOMPING WILLOW.
                Harry traces the thin cone of light of his wand across their faces. Books and papers
                carpet the floor. A WOMAN’S FACE, striking and wise, peers out from a dust jacket.
                Harry crouches, turns the book over to read its TITLE: A History of Magic by
                Bathilda Bagshot. Harry turns it BACK over, studies the woman's face again. He
                begins to rise when he notices a CRUMPLED PIECE OF PAPER embossed at the top with a
                name: Lily Potter. As Harry begins to read, we hear HER VOICE: </stage>
            <sp who="#LILYPOTTER">
                <stage>LETTER (LILY) V.O.</stage> Dear Sirius. Thank you for Harry’s birthday
                present. You’d think he’d been born on a broom. James says he’s got the look of
                aSeeker, but then James would. We had a very quiet birthday tea, just us and old
                Bathilda, who dotes on Harry. Wormy dropped by late in the day, but seemed down and
                didn’t stay long. James is frustrated being shut up here, but Dumbledore’s still got
                hisInvisibility Cloak, so he doesn’t have much choice. By the way, Bathilda tells
                the most amazing stories about our old Headmaster. I don’t know how much to believe.
                Can it really be true that Dumbledore -</sp>

            <stage>Harry turns the letter over, but there is no more.</stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Harry! Harry! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" SECOND FLOOR LANDING - MORNING  "> Harry steps out, finds
                Hermione dashing up the stairs. Seeing him, she exhales in relief. CALLS OUT: </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron! I’ve found him! Good! git! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Tell him from me he’s a </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, you can’t just disappear. We thought -<stage> She stops as
                    Harry hands her the letter. She reads. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s from your Mum. To Sirius. Bathilda Bagshot...? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah. They knew her. She wrote A History of Magic, you know. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>with irony</stage> Did she now? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’m thinking maybe we should go talk to her. She still lives in
                Godric’s Hollow. I’m thinking maybe she could help us. <stage> Hermione looks up,
                    regards Harry closely. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry. I can imagine why you’d want to go there, but... I don’t
                think Bathilda Bagshot is going to know where Voldemort hid his Horcruxes. <stage>
                    Harry starts to respond, frowns. Hermione reaches out, touches his face lightly.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Hey! I think you two better comedown here. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" FIRST FLOOR - MORNING (SECONDS LATER)  "> Ron peers out a
                curtain as Hermione and Harry join him. In the courtyard outside, TWO DARK figures
                stand near a tree. ANOTHER sits on a bench. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> The two clinging to the tree areDeath Eaters for sure. Dunno ‘bout the
                bloke on the bench. <stage>dropping the curtain</stage> Can’t see us, of course. But
                we’ll have to be careful coming and going. C’mon. There’s something else you need to
                see. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR/REGULUS’ ROOM - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry and
                Hermione trail Ron to a narrow doorway. Beyond is a cramped bedroom, walls covered
                with EERIE scrawlings and symbols of Dark Magic. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Lovely. <stage> Ron pulls the door shut. Affixed to the outside is
                    a SMALL SIGN, hand-lettered in a spidery crawl: Do Not Enter Without the Express
                    Permission of Regulus Arcturus Black </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Regulus Arcturus Black...? <stage> Hermione GASPS. Ron nods,
                    extends his hand and taps the first letter of each name on the sign.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> R... A... B. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" KITCHEN - CLOSE ON THE LOCKET - MORNING (MOMENTS   LATER) "> AS
                HARRY REMOVES THE NOTE. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> To the Dark Lord. I know I will be dead long before you read this... I
                have stolen the real Horcrux and intend to destroy it... </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> R.A.B. was Sirius’ brother? We see the trio from the strange LOW POV
                again, sitting round the kitchen table. SLOPPY STACKS of OLD DAILY PROPHETS surround
                them. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Yes. Question is, did he actually destroy the real Horcrux? <stage>
                    Harry nods... then spots a SHADOW trembling on the wall just outside the
                    kitchen. He scrambles up and out of sight. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Stop! I order you! <stage> Seconds later, Harry reappears...
                    dragging KREACHER the house-elf by one ear. Kreacher MUMBLES FOUL OATHS.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Kreacher... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Been spying on us, have you? </sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER"> Kreacher has been... watching. Kreacher always watches. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Maybe he knows. <stage> Harry glances at her, realizes what she
                    means, takes the locket and dangles it before Kreacher’s massive eyes like a
                    hypnotist. Kreacher watches it sway back and forth. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ever seen this before? <stage> Kreacher GRUMBLES incoherently.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Kreacher, I own this place. Sirius left it to me. Which means I own
                you too. <stage> Kreacher grimaces mightily, then gives in. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER"> That was Master Regulus’ locket. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> That’s right. But there were two, weren’t there? <stage> Kreacher’s
                    eyes widen in surprise. He nods again. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Where’s the other one? </sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER"> Kreacher doesn’t know where the other locket is. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> But was it here? Did you ever see it? <stage> Kreacher spins, his
                    face ugly and vicious: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER"> Filthy Mudblood -- The Death Eaters will soon be coming for you!
                    <stage> Ron snatches Kreacher by the neck, shakes him. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER">
                <stage>gargling the words</stage> Blood-traitor Weasley - </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron! RON! <stage> Reluctantly, Ron releases the elf. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Answer her. </sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER"> Yes. It was here, in this house. A most evil object... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How do you mean? </sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER"> Before he died, Master Regulus ordered Kreacher to destroy it. It
                was the last thing he asked of Kreacher. But no matter how Kreacher tried, he could
                not.. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Where is it now? Did someone take it, Kreacher? </sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER">
                <stage>nodding</stage> He came in the night. He took many things, including the
                locket. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who, Kreacher? Who was it? </sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER"> Mundungus. Mundungus Fletcher. <stage> The trio glance at one
                    another, then Harry turns back to Kreacher, looks him in the eye. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Find him. <stage> Crack! -- Kreacher VANISHES. BEGIN MONTAGE:
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" MINISTRY OF MAGIC - ATRIUM - DAY  "> PIUS THICKNESSE, the new
                Minister For Magic, stands just where his predecessor did, addressing his EMPLOYEES.
                In the b.g. we see Yaxley again and DOLORES UMBRIDGE. </stage>
            <sp who="#THICKNESSE"> As your new Minister for Magic, I promise to restore this temple
                of tolerance to its former glory. Therefore, beginning today, each employee will be
                required to submit themselves for evaluation. But know this: You have nothing to
                fear... as long as you have nothing to hide... As Thicknesse smiles, a GANG of DARK
                WIZARDS <stage>SNATCHERS</stage> emerge into the atrium, pushing a BLOODIED MAN
                before them. The crowd STIRS uneasily and we... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ATRIUM - AFTERNOON  "> ...watch a FLURRY of LEAFLETS flutter
                from the sky and land in a NEAT pile next to a stack of Daily Prophets. Instantly,
                the NEWSPAPER BOY begins to insert the leaflets into the paper. Each leaflet is
                imprinted withHARRY’S FACE and emblazoned with “UNDESIRABLE #1”... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" COUNTRYSIDE - DUSK  "> The HOGWARTS EXPRESS stands still upon
                the cracks as DARK WIZARDS board the train... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HOGWARTS EXPRESS - SAME TIME - DUSK  "> Dark wizards move down
                the aisle, flinging open cabin doors, in search of Harry. They pass Ginny and
                SEAMUS, KATIE BELL, LAVENDER, ROMILDA VANE and CORMAC. </stage>
            <sp who="#CORMAC"> My father will hear about this. </sp>
            <stage>Finally NEVILLE bars their way, smiles defiantly.</stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> He’s not here, you fools. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" GRANGER HOUSE - PARLOR - DUSK  "> Dark wizards smash through
                the front door, enter the parlor. The photographs still sit upon the mantle, showing
                only Hermione’s parents, the tea they’d been drinking still sitting on the table,
                dried up, but unwashed... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" DIAGON ALLEY - DUSK (RAINING)  "> POSTERS of HARRY pattern
                alley walls and street posts, trembling in a bitter wind. In the shadows, Mundungus
                Fletcher concludes a transaction with a desperate-looking witch, then begins to
                count his money with a cruel smile. Seconds later, a Snatcher squad appears and he
                withdraws into an alley, into the safety of the darkness when suddenly a loud CRACK!
                is head and... MONTAGE ENDS. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" 12 GRIMMAULD PLACE - NIGHT (LATER, RAINING)  "> DARK FIGURES
                continue to loom in the square. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DRAWING ROOM - SAME TIME - NIGHT (RAINING)  "> Ron fiddles with
                the RADIO, which WHISTLES EERILY as he attempts to find a signal. Harry lies on his
                side, studying the Snitch in his palm, its wings flapping slowly. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> They have flesh memories. <stage>Harry turns, sees that Hermione is
                    eyeing the Snitch.</stage>
            </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Snitches. They’re never touched by bare skin until the Seeker
                captures it. Even the wizard who fabricates it wears gloves. That way, if there’s a
                dispute, the Snitch can identify who first touched it. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You mean... it remembers me? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>nodding</stage> When Scrimgeour first gave it to you, I thought it might open
                at your touch -- that Dumbledore had hidden something in it. </sp>
            <stage>Harry ponders this, eyeing the wings flapping slowly, then... Crack! A SOUND
                ECHOES down the hall.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" KITCHEN - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER) (RAINING)  "> Harry and
                Hermione race into the kitchen. CRAZY SHADOWS spill from a far door and POTS CRASH.
                Suddenly, a TINY FIGURE, WET AND RAGGED, tumbles INTO VIEW, bangs into the wall
                opposite, and scrambles up. As he starts back for the kitchen, he stops. Sees Harry.
                Smiles. DOBBY. </stage>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Harry Potter! So long it’s been -<stage> Just then, a HAND --
                    Kreacher’s -- reaches out, grabs Dobby by the neck and pulls him away.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" KITCHEN - SAME TIME - NIGHT (RAINING)  "> Kreacher, Dobby and
                Mundungus Fletcher TUMBLE from one side of the kitchen to the other. As they fly
                apart, Mundungus rolls to his feet, dripping wet, wand flashing. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Expelliarmus! <stage> Mundungus’ wand soars into the air... into
                    Hermione’s hand. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#KREACHER"> As requested, Kreacher has returned with the thief Mundungus
                Fletcher! </sp>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby has also returned with the thief Mundungus Fletcher! </sp>
            <sp who="#MUNDUNGUS"> What are you playing at -- setting a pair of bleedin’ ‘ouse-elves
                on me! </sp>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby was only trying to help! Dobby saw Kreacher in Diagon Alley,
                which Dobby thought was curious. And then Dobby heard Kreacher mention Harry
                Potter’s name, which Dobby thought was very curious. And then Dobby saw that
                Kreacher was talking to the thief Mundungus Fletcher, which Dobby thought was very,
                very - </sp>
            <sp who="#MUNDUNGUS"> I’m no thief, you foul little git. I’m a purveyer of rare and
                wondrous objects - </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You’re a thief, Dung. Everyone knows it. <stage> Everyone turns. Ron
                    stands in the doorway. Dobby smiles. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Master Weasley! So good to see you again! <stage> Ron nods, eyes the
                    BRIGHT RED SHOES on Dobby’s feet. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Wicked trainers. </sp>
            <sp who="#MUNDUNGUS"> Listen, I panicked that night, all right? I never volunteered to
                die for you, mate. Can I help it ifMad-Eye fell off his broom - </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Stop lying! <stage> Hermione begins to move toward Mundungus. Ron
                    reaches out, takes her by the shoulders, eyes Mundungus warningly. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Piece of advice. Let’s not rehash old times. Got it... mate? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> When you turned this place over -- don’t deny it! --you found a
                locket, am I right? </sp>
            <sp who="#MUNDUNGUS"> Why? Was it valuable? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You’ve still got it. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No. He’s worried he should have got more money for it. </sp>
            <sp who="#MUNDUNGUS"> Wouldn’t be difficult, would it? Bleedin’ gave it away, din’ I?
                There I was, pitching me wares in Diagon Alley when some ministry hag comes up and
                asks to see my license. Says she’s of a mind to lock me up and would’ve, too, she
                hadn’ taken a fancy to that locket. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who was she? This witch? </sp>
            <sp who="#MUNDUNGUS"> Well, she’s right there, in’t she? Bleedin’ bow an’ all. <stage>
                    He points to a yellowed Prophet on top of a nearby stack, where a SQUAT WOMAN
                    with the face of a toad blinks from the front page: DOLORES UMBRIDGE.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" WHITEHALL STREET - MORNING  "> An empty street corner. Then...
                Ron peers round a building. A few yards off, a WITCH (MAFALDA HOPKIRK) approaches.
                Ron begins to walk, preceding her down the street, then kneels, fiddling with his
                shoelace. Zap! The witch stiffens and falls... into the arms of Harry. Ron hurries
                back, takes her feet and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" STORAGE AREA - CONTINUOUS ACTION - MORNING  "> ...helps Harry
                hustle her OUT OF VIEW. They prop her up between TWO WIZARDS, one tall, one short,
                both UNCONSCIOUS. Hermione is pouring POLYJUICE POTION into THREE CUPS. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Right.So let’s do it. Who gets who? * </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Well, unless one of you fancies wearing a skirt... <stage> Hermione
                    leans down, PLUCKS a HAIR from the witch. frowns as he surveys the two remaining
                    wizards. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Remember what we said. Keep your eyes down. Don’t speak to anyone
                unless absolutely necessary. Act as normal as possible. Just do what you see
                everyone else doing. We do that -- and with a bit of luck -- we get ourselves
                inside. And then... Ron </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It gets really tricky. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Correct. <stage> Harry and Hermione look once more at the STUNNED
                    TRIO before them. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> This is completely mental. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Completely, utterly, without question. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> The world’s mental. Come on, drink up. We’ve got a Horcrux to find.
            </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" WHITEHALL STREET - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER) "> The trio -- in
                their new identifies -- emerge. Ron (in the quise of REG CATTERMOLE) takes out an ID
                CARD. </stage>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> In case you’re interested, I’m Reg Cattermole, Magical
                Maintenance Department. </sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE"> Mafalda Hopkirk, assistant in the Improper Use of
                Magic Office. </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"><stage>patting his pockets</stage> I’m nobody. </sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE"> You’re somebody. Be careful. <stage> Just then a
                    SKINNY WIZARD strides by. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SKINNYWIZARD"> Morning, Reg! Good luck today. </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Oh... yeah. Thanks. <stage> Ron glances to Harry and
                    Hermione, jerks his head toward the skinny wizard and they follow. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" PUBLIC TOILETS - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER)  "> As the skinny
                wizard drops down the stairs into a public toilet, the trio appear. </stage>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> What do you reckon he meant by ‘Good luck.’? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" GENTLEMEN’S TOILET - MORNING (SECONDS LATER)  "> Harry and Ron
                enter, glance around, then, seeing as everyone else is doing so, slip into cubicles.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CUBICLE  "> Harry enters. FLUSHING sounds all around him. He
                looks to his left, sees a PAIR OF BOOTED FEET climb into the next toilet, then looks
                to his right, sees Ron -- as Reg Cattermole -- peering in. </stage>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> We flush ourselves in? </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> Apparently so. </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> That’s bloody disgusting. <stage> As Reg/Ron’s face
                    disappears, Harry steps up onto his toilet, dips his shoe in gingerly, then
                    withdraws it. Completely dry. Stepping in fully, he reaches up, pulls the chain
                    and is instantly sucked down. Seconds later... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" MINISTRY OF MAGIC - ATRIUM - MORNING (SECONDS LATER)  "> ... he
                comes shooting out of a FIREPLACE into the grand atrium of the Ministry of Magic. He
                sees Hermione’s already arrived and standing before a MASSIVE STATUE ofBLACK STONE
                depicting a witch and wizard sitting upon hundreds of naked bodies twisted in pain.
                Harry joins her. </stage>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> Are those...? </sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE">
                <stage>nodding; with disgust</stage> Muggles. In their rightful place. <stage> Harry
                    glances at the base of the statue, where the words MAGIC IS MIGHT are engraved.
                    Just then, a BALDING WIZARD bumps into Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BALDINGWIZARD"> Move it, will you -- oh, Runcorn! Forgive me... <stage> The
                    Balding Wizard hurries away, clearly frightened, as does ANOTHER WIZARD, merely
                    at the sight of Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE"> You appear to be quite popular. <stage> Ron
                    approaches, running a gauntlet of pitying looks from co-workers who echo the
                    Skinny Wizard’s “Good Luck.” </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> I gotta tell you, I'm starting to freak out a bit. <stage>
                    Just then, a gang of YOUNG, ROUGH-LOOKING WIZARDS, led by their leader, SCABIOR,
                    enter the Atrium, pushing along as mall group of CAPTIVES. </stage></sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> The Ministry must be hiring young these days. </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> hey’re not Ministry. They’reSnatchers. They hunt
                Muggle-borns and blood-traitors for a price. </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> How long did you say this batch of Polyjuice Potion
                would last, Hermione? </sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE"> I didn’t. </sp>
            <sp who="#YAXLEY"> Cattermole! <stage> They all jump. Yaxley strides directly up to Ron.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#YAXLEY"> It’s still raining in my office. Two days now. </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Really? Have you tried an umbrella? <stage> Yaxley eyes
                    Ron curiously, then leans forward menacingly. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#YAXLEY"> You do realize I'm on my way downstairs, don’t you, Cattermole? </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Downstairs...? </sp>
            <sp who="#YAXLEY"> To interrogate your wife! If my wife’s blood status were in doubt and
                the Head of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement needed a job doing, I think
                I’d make it a priority. You’ve got one hour. <stage> Just then, the LIFT behind them
                    clangs open. Hermione tugs Ron inside. Yaxley turns and storms off just as...
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" LIFT - CONTINUOUS ACTION - MORNING  "> ...the doors close. </stage>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Oh my god. What am I going to do? My wife’s all alone
                downstairs? </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> Ron. You don’t have a wife. </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Oh. Right. </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> Look, we’ll go with you -- </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> No, that’s mad. You two find Umbridge. I’ll be fine. But
                how do I stop it raining? </sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE"> Try Finite Incantatem. Of course if something’s gone
                wrong with an Atmospheric Charm -- </sp>
            <sp who="#FEMALE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> Level Two. Department of MagicalLaw Enforcement, including
                Wizengamot Administration Services, Auror Headquarters and Improper Use of Magic
                Department. </sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE"> This is you. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="/EXT. LIFT - LEVEL TWO - CONTINUOUS ACTION - MORNING  "> The
                lift opens and Ron begins to back out. </stage>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Finite Incantatem, okay. And if that doesn’t work...?
                    <stage> But before she can respond the golden grilles of the lift close and she
                    and Harry are swept away. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE"> I don’t like him being on his own down there. </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> Ron’s been coming here since he was two years old. It’s
                us you should be worrying about. </sp>
            <sp who="#MAFALDAHOPKIRK/HERMIONE"> You really have horrible teeth, you know that. </sp>
            <sp who="#FEMALE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> Level One. Minister of Magic and Support Staff... </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY">
                <stage>whispering quickly</stage> I say if we don’t locate Umbridge within the hour,
                we go find Ron and come back another day. Deal? The grilles clang open again and
                Harry and Hermione freeze. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" LIFT - LEVEL ONE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - MORNING  "> Standing
                next to a LONG-HAIRED WIZARD, her neck enwrapped in a fuzzy PINK SCARF, is DOLORES
                UMBRIDGE. She looks up from the clipboard in her hand and sees Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#UMBRIDGE"> Ah, Mafalda! Travers sent you, did he? Good. We’ll go straight
                down. <stage>eying Harry</stage> Albert, aren’t you getting out? <stage> Harry nods
                    mutely, steps out. As the lift descends, he watches Hermione’s anxious face sink
                    out of sight. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" MINISTRY OF MAGIC - LEVEL ONE - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER) ">
                Harry passes one gleaming door after anther, glancing down purple-carpeted corridors
                that stretch into nothingness. A MUTTERING WIZARD passes by, murmuring to a QUILL
                floating in front of him. Otherwise, it is eerily quiet. </stage>
            <sp who="#YOUNGWIZARD">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Weasley! <stage> Harry stops dead, peers around a corner and
                    sees as light, familiar-looking RED-HEADED WIZARD: PERCY WEASLEY. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#YOUNGWIZARD"> They’re waiting for your report downstairs. </sp>
            <sp who="#PERCY"> Oh, yes... of course. <stage> Harry watches Percy hurry off.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry moves on. Hears
                VOICES ahead. Emerges into a wide open space and discovers dozens of witches and
                wizards sitting at a sea of small desks. Waving their wands in unison, squares of
                PINK PAPER flit like kites through the air, dropping into neat stacks. Harry creeps
                closer, sees that they are pamphlets entitled, “MUDBLOODS and theDangers They Pose
                to a Peaceful Pure-Blood Society.” </stage>
            <sp who="#RED-HAIREDWITCH"> Reckon the old hag will be interrogating Mudbloods all day? </sp>
            <sp who="#BESPECTACLEDWIZARD"> Sh...careful. <stage> Pius Thicknesse appears, trailing a
                    retinue of lackeys. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#THICKNESSE"> Runcorn. <stage> Harry returns Thicknesse’s nod, watches him pass
                    FROM VIEW. As his gaze shifts, he finds the Red-Haired Witch regarding him with
                    fear. She looks quickly away, resumes her work at double-time. Harry’s eyes
                    shift again, regard a SHINING MAHOGANY DOOR across the way. He squints:
                    something is imbedded within the door. He crosses the room, stops dead. Fitted
                    into the wood is an EYE. It spins weakly, then stops: Mad-Eye’s eye. He looks
                    down to the BRASS NAMEPLATE next to the door: DOLORES UMBRIDGE HEAD OF THE
                    MUGGLE-BORN REGISTRATION COMMISSION Harry’s jaw tightens in anger and he glances
                    over his shoulder, sees the Red-Haired Witch watching him. She glances away
                    quickly. Harry reaches into an inner pocket and removes a DECOY DETONATOR, an
                    odd object with little weaving legs and a rubber-bulbed horn for a body. He
                    releases it. It scuttles down his body, across the floor and directly into the
                    sea of desks. Harry waits. Then... Bang! Black smoke billows into the air, pink
                    pages fly everywhere and the Detonator gives birth to dozens of tiny replicants
                    of itself, which race about the floor, up the legs and across the desks of the
                    pamphleteers. The Red-Haired Witch SHRIEKS. Others follow and Harry...
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" UMBRIDGE’S OFFICE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - MORNING "> ... slips
                into Umbridge’s office, closes the door. The room’s decor is sickeningly cute. Lace
                doilies. Dried flowers. Harry takes out his wand. </stage>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> Accio locket. <stage> Nothing. Harry frowns, glances
                    about. A LEAFLET bearing his face -- “Undesirable #1” -- lies upon Umbridge’s
                    desk, along with PHOTOGRAPHS of other Order members. Two have a LARGE PINK “X”
                    scratched on them: Dumbledore and Mad-Eye. Harry begins to search the office,
                    opening drawers, riffling through filing cabinets... then stops. Pulls out a
                    file. Inside is a PHOTOGRAPH of Hermione and an accompanying DATA SHEET: “Blood
                    Status: MUGGLE BORN” “Whereabouts: Last seen in the company of Undesirable#1.”
                    Quickly Harry replaces the file and searches outRon’s. “Blood Status: PURE
                    BLOOD... Pro-Muggle leanings.” “Whereabouts: Last seen in the company
                    ofUndesirable #1.” Harry starts to put the file away, then pauses, looks closer.
                    “Father: Arthur Weasley. Ministry Employee. Status: TRACKED. Strong
                    likelihoodUndesirable #1 will contact.” Harry stares at the word“TRACKED.” Then:
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BALDINGWIZARD">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> All right, all right. Let’s calm down, shall we? <stage> Harry
                    replaces the file, steps to the door and peers through. Slowly, he eases open
                    the door, back out and... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" MINISTRY OF MAGIC - LEVEL ONE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - MORNING ">
                ... turns. The Red-Haired Witch is watching him. He puts his finger to his lips. Her
                eyes go wide as saucers. </stage>
            <sp who="#BALDINGWIZARD"> It probably just snuck up here from Experimental Charms. I
                think none of us will soon forget last month’s Poisonous Duck... Seeing the
                Red-Haired Witch’s expression, the Balding Wizard turns and, as before, withers at
                the sight of Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#BALDINGWIZARD"> R-Runcorn. <stage> Harry gives him an appraising look, turns
                    the corner... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HALLWAY - CONTINUOUS ACTION - MORNING  "> ... and dashes off.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" LEVEL ONE - OUTSIDE LIFTS - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry
                sprints INTO VIEW just as the same MUTTERING WIZARD trails his QUILL out of an empty
                lift. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" LIFT - MORNING  "> Harry races inside, hits a button and
                watches the grilles close. He glances at his reflection in the mirrored wall. Bares
                his teeth. Hermione’s right. They’re awful. Just then, the grilles clang open and
                Ron enters, soaking wet and wild-eyed. </stage>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> M-morning. </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> Ron, it’s me. </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Harry! Blimey, I forgot what you looked like. Where’s
                Hermione? </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> She went down to the courtrooms with Umbridge -- The
                grilles open again and reveal... Arthur Weasley, in the company of an elderly witch
                    <stage>WAKINDA</stage>. </sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> I understand, Wakinda, but I can’t be a party to that. <stage>
                    Arthur stops then, seeing Harry, and regards him with utter disdain, then turns
                    his eyes to Ron and softens. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> Hello, Reg. Isn’t Mary in for questioning today? Try to have
                faith. If there’s anything Molly and I can do for you --<stage> Arthur pats Ron’s
                    shoulder, stops. Pulls his dripping hand away. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#WAKINDA"> Let me guess. It’s raining in Yaxley’s office again? </sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> Tell him to try an umbrella. <stage> Arthur and Wakinda exit.
                    As they go, Ron cranes his neck, watching with a look of longing as the grilles
                    begin to close. Suddenly, Harry reaches out, blocks the doors. </stage></sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> Arthur! You know you’re being tracked, don’t you?
                    <stage> Arthur turns. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#ARTHURWEASLEY"> Is that a threat, Runcorn? </sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> No, Arthur. It’s a fact. They’re watching you. <stage>
                    Arthur eyes Harry with a mixture of suspicion and confusion and perhaps...
                    recognition. Harry removes his hand. The grilles close. Ron stares at him.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> I’ll tell you later. Let’s find Hermione. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" PASSAGEWAY - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry and Ron move
                down a dark torch-lit stone passageway. As they move further along, their BREATH
                becomes VISIBLE and Ron, soaked to the bones, begins to tremble. </stage>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Bloody cold down here. <stage> Then they see. Swirling
                    outside the courtroom doors like sentinels are tall black-hooded figures.
                    DEMENTORS. Just then, a man comes stumbling out of the courtroom in the company
                    of a PAIR of DEATH EATERS. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCAREDMAN"> I’m half-blood, I tell you! My father was a wizard! Look him up!
                William Alderton! He worked here for thirty years... <stage> As Ron watches the
                    terrified man pass, Harry grabs his arm, pulls him toward the courtroom.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" COURTROOM - SAME TIME - MORNING  "> A dark cathedral, possessed
                of a palpable chill. Dementors float eerily in the gloom. The ceilings tretches
                high, disappears in darkness. As Harry and Ronenter -- unnoticed at first -- they
                move cautiously, taking in their surroundings. Hermione comes INTO VIEW, sitting
                with a STACK of PARCHMENT behind a balustrade alongside Umbridge and Yaxley, while a
                BRIGHT-SILVER CAT-- Umbridge’s Patronus -- prowls up and down, providing warmth to
                them and them only. Harry’s eyes track the cat, then drift to Umbridge herself.
                Suddenly he falters. Ron notices. Eyes him curiously. WHISPERS: </stage>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> What is it? <stage> The corners of Harry’s eyes contract,
                    his head slightly cocked... as if he can sense the presence of something.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> It’s here... <stage> As Ron reacts -- deciphering
                    Harry’s words -- a WOMAN’S VOICE comes their way: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MARYCATTERMOLE"> Reg... <stage> Ron turns. Below the balustrade, a frail
                    woman, MARY CATTERMOLE, sits alone, wrists chained. Seeing Ron, her wan face
                    brightens. Ron glances at Harry, who nods, urging him on. Ron moves to the
                    center of the room, taking his place behind the woman. Hesitating, he places his
                    hands gently upon her shoulders, then glances up, sees Hermione watching him.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#UMBRIDGE"> Mary Elizabeth Cattermole? </sp>
            <sp who="#MARYCATTERMOLE"> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#UMBRIDGE"> Mother to Maisie, Ellie andAlfred? Wife to Reginald? <stage> Mary
                    looks up to Ron, her eyes glistening with fear. He smiles reassuringly. She
                    looks away, replies: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MARYCATTERMOLE"> Yes. <stage> Harry eyes Umbridge. She has draped the pink
                    scarf over her chair, revealing a GOLD CHAIN that extends from her neck down
                    into the ruffled folds of her blouse. A slight HUMMING, faint and oddly lyrical,
                    rings in Harry’s ears as he studies the chain. As if drawn forward by some
                    irresistible force, he begins to drift toward the balustrade. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#UMBRIDGE"> A wand was taken from you upon your arrival at the Ministry today,
                Mrs. Cattermole. Is this that wand? <stage> Umbridge displays a CHERRYWOOD WAND.
                    Mary Cattermole nods. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#UMBRIDGE"> Would you please tell the court from which witch or wizard you took
                this wand. </sp>
            <sp who="#MARYCATTERMOLE"> But I didn’t take it. I got it in Diagon Alley, at
                Ollivander’s, when I was eleven. It chose me. <stage> Umbridge leans forward, teeth
                    glittering as the cats links by and briefly illuminates her face -- and the
                    chain at her neck trembles like a snake, something heavy swinging forward and
                    dangling over the void. The LOCKET. Ron stares at it dumbstruck. Hermione
                    catches her breath. Harry, fully removed from the shadow now, stands clearly in
                    view, the corners of his eyes narrowing once again, the HUM growing louder in
                    his ears. Slowly, her eaches into his pocket... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#UMBRIDGE"> No, no, I don’t think so, Mrs. Cattermole. Wands only choose
                witches. And you are not a witch. </sp>
            <sp who="#MARYCATTERMOLE"> But I am! Tell them, Reg! Tell them what I am! <stage> Ron
                    starts to speak, but Umbridge’s gaze has shifted, toHarry, to the wand rising in
                    his hand.. and pointed at her. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#UMBRIDGE"> What the devil are you doing, Albert? <stage> As Harry speaks, his
                    own face ripples through Runcorn’s, the Polyjuice Potion wearing off.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> You’re lying. And one mustn’t tell lies, Dolores...
                Stupefy! <stage> A flash of red light hits Umbridge and she slumps, forehead
                    striking the balustrade. Instantly the silver cat vanishes. Yaxley draws his
                    wand, but Ron is too quick and takes him out with a single blast. Hermione
                    strips the locket from Umbridge’s neck and leaps down. Instantly, her breath
                    comes in plumes as the Dementors drift forward. </stage></sp>
            <sp who=" #ALBERTRUNCORN/HARRY"> EXPECTO PATRONUM! <stage> A SILVER STAG soars from the
                    tip of Harry’s wand, circling the room as it drives the Dementors back.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Relashio! <stage> The chains encircling Mary Cattermole’s wrists
                    drop like dead snakes. As she stands, she eyes Harry in amazement as he
                    transforms back into himself. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MARYCATTERMOLE"> You? It’s you! Reg, it’s HarryPotter! </sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> ‘Tis, isn’t it? This’ll be one to tell the kids. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" MINISTRY OF MAGIC - ATRIUM - MORNING (MOMENTS LATER)  "> As the
                trio, along with Mary Cattermole, pelts into the atrium and races toward the
                fireplaces, Harry bumps into the muttering wizard, who spins, takes a look at Harry,
                blinks. </stage>
            <sp who="#MUTTERINGWIZARD"> Harry Potter...? <stage>louder</stage> Harry Potter. <stage>
                    Another wizard hears, looks, then repeats the same, Harry’s name spreading like
                    wildfire in the gloomy hush. Hermione glances about nervously and as she does,
                    begins to transform back into herself. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry... they’ve seen you. We’ve got to get out of here. <stage>
                    Harry nods, quickens his pace. Ron glances about, then turns, facing Mary as he
                    continues to walk backwards. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Mary. Go home. Get the kids. I’ll... I’ll meet you there.
                We have to get out the country, understand? <stage> Mary shakes her head, confused.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> Mary! Do as I say! <stage> Mary stops, a bit teary-eyed,
                    nods dutifully. Ron frowns. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE/RON"> I’m sorry. It’s just -<stage> Mary Cattermole takes him by
                    the collar, pulls him into a deep kiss. Harry and Hermione glance back and watch
                    as Ron transforms -- during the kiss -- back into himself. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#REGCATTERMOLE"> MARY! <stage> All eyes turn. The real Reg Cattermole stands --
                    robeless -- outside one of the fireplaces. She looks up at Ron, now transformed,
                    and jumps back. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Long story. Nice meeting you. <stage> He gives her a peck, races off.
                    He’s halfway to the fireplaces when he spies... Percy. He slows, then stops
                    altogether, and they stare, wordless, at one another. Finally, Percy begins to
                    open his mouth - </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Piss off. <stage> Yaxley staggers into the atrium. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#YAXLEY"> Seal the exits! Now! <stage> Harry, Ron and Hermione glance at each
                    other, break for the fireplaces. As Yaxley fires on them, one fireplace after
                    another seals itself. As they reach the last open grate, they pitch themselves
                    -- as one -- onto the polished marble floor -- spells sailing over their heads--
                    and go sliding inside. As they fall into darkness, Harry glances back and
                    watches Yaxley pitch himself into the void just before a solid block of granite
                    drops -- like a guillotine -- sealing the fireplace and plungingYaxley -- and
                    the trio -- into total darkness. A whirlwind tosses the trio as FLASHES of LIGHT
                    reveal each briefly, including Yaxley, who reaches out for Hermione’s robe. The
                    door of Grimmauld Place rushes forward, the eyes of the SERPENT KNOCKER
                    flashing, then there is a BURST of PURPLE LIGHT, a TORTURED SCREAM and...
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FOREST - DAY (MOMENTS LATER)  "> The world spins as Harry lies
                on his back on a bed of leaves and twigs. Above, sunlight streams through a canopy
                of trees. Wincing, Harry rises on his elbows, sees the locket lying in the dirt. He
                scrabbles up, scoops it into his fingers and GRINS. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, quickly, in my bag, there’s a small bottle labeled ‘Essence
                of Dittany.’ <stage> Harry turns, sees Hermione, bent over Ron’s twitching body.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Quickly! <stage> Harry blinks, stumbles dizzily to the bag. As he
                    reaches in, objects present themselves in furious succession. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Accio Dittany. <stage> A small BROWN BOTTLE lands in his palm.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Unstopper it. <stage> Hermione rips open Ron’s shirt, which is
                    soaked in blood. The flesh of his upper arm is flayed, as if someone had scooped
                    a portion away. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione. His arm - </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Just do it! <stage> Harry does so, hands her the bottle. She
                    sprinkles three drops onto Ron’s BLEEDING WOUND. Greenish SMOKE billows.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What happened? I thought we were going back to Grimmauld Place. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We were. We were there. But Yaxley had hold of me. I knew we
                couldn’t stay once he’d seen, so when he let go I brought us here. Ron got
                Splinched. I’m... sorry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Don’t be stupid. <stage> The smoke sifts, clears. Ron’s wound no
                    longer bleeds. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s all I feel safe doing. <stage> Hermione rises, takes out her
                    wand and begins to walk in a wide circle, MUTTERING. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Salvio Hexia... Protego Totalum... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What’re you doing? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Protective enchantments. I don’t fancy another visit like we had
                onShaftesbury Avenue, do you? Especially with Ron like this. You can get going on
                the tent... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Tent? Where am I supposed to find -<stage> He stops, glances down at
                    her bag, then back to Hermione. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Repello Muggletum... Muffliato... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FOREST - NIGHT (LATER)  "> The tent glows from within under a
                starlit sky. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Hermione pours tea from a kettle
                into cups. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> How’re the mushrooms? Seem to be the only edible things growing
                round here. <stage> Harry grimaces as he chews. “Edible” is clearlyd ebatable.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> They’re great. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Make sure to leave some for Ron. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>under his breath</stage> No problem. <stage> Harry sets his plate aside,
                    plucks up the locket, dangles it in the firelight. Glances at Ron. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How bad is he? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> He’ll be alright in a few days. Hopefully. If we could take him to
                Hogwarts, to Madam Pomfrey -<stage> Harry’s glance stops her, confirming what she
                    knows. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> So where do we go next? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dumbledore had a theory. He felt that the Horcruxes would not be made
                out of random objects. And he felt they wouldn’t be hidden randomly either. We know
                of three so far. The ring, which according to Dumbledore belonged to TomRiddle’s
                grandfather. The diary, which belonged to Tom himself. And this, which -- again,
                according to Dumbledore -- belonged to his mother. <stage> Hermione eyes the locket
                    as it glimmers in the firelight. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It scares me a bit, that, thinking it’s a piece of Vol- </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No, don’t! Don’t say it! <stage> Harry and Hermione turn, see Ron
                    stirring. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> It’s taboo -- You-Know-Who’s name. That’s how they track people now.
                It’s how they found us in the cafe that night. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How d’you know? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I overheard a bloke from the Enforcement office talking about it at the
                Ministry. Blimey, what’s that smell? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>no longer confident</stage> Dinner? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Not bloody likely. Smells like something Ginny would cook. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Tea? <stage> Ron nods. Grimacing, he pushes himself up, notices
                    he’s wearing a SLING of Hermione’s fashioning. He looks from it to her as she
                    tends the tea, a flicker of remorse playing over his face for his “dinner”
                    remarks. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Is that it? <stage> Harry nods, hands him the locket. Ron turns it over
                    in his hand. Frowns. Looks at Harry, who nods. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I know. I felt it too. <stage>off Hermione’s look</stage> It’s... it’s
                like it’s ticking or something, like it has a tiny metal heart, like it’s - </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> ... alive. <stage> Harry nods. Hermione eyes it coldly. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I hate it. It’s like he’s here with us. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> That’s why we’re going to kill it. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FOREST - CLOSE ON LOCKET - DAY  "> LYING UPON A TREE STUMP. Ron
                leans against a tree, looking pale. Hermione nods to Harry. He raises his
                wand.</stage>

            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dissendium! <stage> The locket spins swiftly in place, but remains
                    whole. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Incendio! <stage> Flames engulf the locket and its metal flesh
                    turns scarlet, but then the flames die. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Expulso! <stage> The tree stump EXPLODES, but the locket remains
                    unmarked. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Confringo! <stage> The ground beneath the stump craters, but the
                    locket remains untouched. Hermione lowers her wand, but Harry continues on,
                    firing a succession of spells, looking almost possessed. Hermione studies him
                    oddly until, finally, he stops. All goes silent except for the leaves shifting
                    in wind above. Then, slowly, another sound comes clear... a TICKING. Coming from
                    the locket. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> It’s angry. <stage> Hermione shivers. Harry steps forward, kneels down
                    and takes the locket by its chain. It TICKS. He slings it over his neck. Rises.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What’re you doing? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We have to keep it safe until we can figure out how to destroy it. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I can put it in my bag - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Seems strange, mate. Dumbledore sends you off to find a load of
                Horcruxes, but doesn’t bother to tell you how to destroy them. Doesn’t that bother
                you? <stage> Harry studies the locket, whose TICKING has slowed, then walks off.
                    Hermione eyes Ron, who returns her glance, then pushes away from the tree and
                    walks off slowly int he opposite direction. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT - DUSK  "> Ron lies on his cot, fiddling with the radio.
                VOICES surface in the STATIC briefly, then fade. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ENCAMPMENT - SAME TIME - DUSK  "> Harry turns the MIRROR SHARD
                over in his fingers, then eyes Hermione collecting flowers in the distance. She
                looks beautiful. Seeing him, she smiles, waves, moves on. The RADIO SPITS STATIC and
                he TILTS THE MIRROR so he can see Ron. He looks annoyed, but holds his tongue and
                slips the mirror in his pocket. Noticing the locket, he slips it from his shirt,
                studies the fissures in the locket’s metal skin. Suddenly he WINCES. The locket
                spills from his palm, dances upon the chain. The SKIN encircling his scar
                CONSTRICTS. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> Tell me, Gregorovitch. Tell me where it is... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" WANDSHOP - BACK ROOM - NIGHT  "> An OLD MAN (GREGOROVITCH) with
                pure-white hair and a bushy beard cowers in a dark corner. </stage>
            <sp who="#GREGOROVITCH"> I told you! I no longer have it! It was stolen from me! Many
                years ago! </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> You wouldn’t be lying to me, would you, Gregorovitch? Because, I
                must tell you... that will only make it worse for you...</sp>
            <stage>As a bony hand -- Voldemort’s -- extends a wand, Gregorovitch reacts with fear
                and we RUSH IN, DRIFTING THROUGH his dilating pupil INTO...FLASHBACK - INT. DARK
                CORRIDOR - YEARS PAST ... a hall of shadows. A younger Gregorovitch hurries toward a
                distant room, a lantern bobbing in his hand. </stage>
            <sp who="#GREGOROVITCH">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> I speak the truth! I remember like it was yesterday... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" WORKSHOP - CONTINUOUS ACTION  "> Gregorovitch bursts inside,
                lantern swaying. shavings litter the floor. Wood On the window ledge, perched like a
                giant bird, a YOUNG MAN (GRINDEWALD) with golden hair grins devilishly, then raises
                his WAND. A BLAST of LIGHT bleaches the screen and we -CUT TO: </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" WAND SHOP - BACK ROOM - NIGHT (PRESENT)  "> Gregorovitch’s face
                stricken with terror, as Voldemort’s want tip blazes with light. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Who was he? The thief? </sp>
            <sp who="#GREGOROVITCH"> Just a boy! Not of the village. It was he who took it. I never
                saw it again. I swear on my life. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> I believe you... <stage> A BURST OF GREEN LIGHT engulfs the room
                    and... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TENT - DUSK  "> Harry’s eyes flutter open. He sees Hermione,
                beautiful in the amber dusk, standing a bit away, studying him. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I thought it had stopped. <stage> Harry looks at her, shakes his
                    head. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You can’t let him in, Harry. Dumbledore himself said it. You have
                to close your mind. It’s too dangerous - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s not a candle I can blow out, Hermione. It always burns, even if
                it’s just a flicker. Can you understand that? <stage> Harry eyes her, then looks
                    away. She frowns, concerned by this, then: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Tell me. What you saw. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He’s found him. Vol-<stage> He stops, glancing back toward the tent,
                    toward Ron. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You-Know-Who. He’s found <stage> Gregorovitch - </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> The wandmaker? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. How’d you know? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Viktor got his wand from Gregorovitch. Most Durmstrang students did
                at one time. What’s he got to do with You-Know-Who? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You-Know-Who wants something Gregorovitch once had -- dunno what. But
                he’s desperate to have it. It’s as if his life depends on it. <stage> Hermione
                    studies Harry. The RADIO SQUAWKS from inside the tent. Harry’s eyes flare; he
                    starts to speak - </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Don’t -- It... comforts him. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well it sets my teeth on edge. What’s he expecting to hear? Good news? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I think he just hopes he doesn’t hear bad news. It gets him through
                the day. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And what gets you through the day? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We’ve all made sacrifices, Harry. <stage> Harry eyes her
                    expressionlessly, nods toward the tent. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How long before he can travel? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I don’t know. It takes time. I’m doing all I can. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’re not doing enough. <stage> Hermione studies Harry’s angry
                    profile. Then: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Take it off. <stage> Harry turns, sees Hermione studying him
                    closely. She points toward his throat, toward the locket. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Take it off. Now. <stage> Harry slips the locket off... REACTS.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Better? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Loads. <stage> Hermione takes the locket, cradles it in her fingers.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s cold. Even though it’s been lying against your skin for days.
                    <stage> Hermione sees Harry studying the locket, troubled. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We’ll take turns. Okay? <stage> Hermione slips it over her neck.
                    She frowns briefly, sensing its presence, then looks up at Harry. He studies
                    her, then nods. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT - NIGHT (LATER)  "> Ron sleeps beside the CRACKLING radio.
                Harry lies a few feet away, awake. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TENT - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Hermione huddles outside in the
                frigid darkness, trembling. Her eyes rake the trees. Deep within, there is, for the
                briefest of instances... movement. Or so it seems. She squints. Sees nothing.
                Returns her chin to her chest. As she does, something carries on the air...
                laughter. The cackle of... boys? Or so it seems. Her chin rises. She looks again
                into the trees... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Harry reaches out, starts to turn
                the radio off when: </stage>
            <sp who="#RADIO">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> ... Severus Snape, newly appointed Headmaster of Hogwarts...
                    <stage> As the signal fades, Harry rolls onto his side and twists the dial.
                    Behind him, we see Hermione’s shadow RISE, move away from the tent...
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ENCAMPMENT - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Hermione moves toward the
                trees... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> As the radio resists him, fading
                in and out, Harry grabs his rucksack, pulls out the WRINKLED MARAUDER’S MAP. </stage>
            <sp who="#RADIO">
                <stage>V.O.</stage><stage> ... bears little resemblance to the school under
                    Dumbledore’s leadership. Snape’s curriculum is severe, reflecting the wishes of
                    the Dark Lord and infractions are dealt with harshly by the twoDeath Eaters on
                    the staff... </stage></sp>

            <stage>Harry peers at the map before him and -- sure enough -- discovers Snape’s name
                drifting about Dumbledore’s office. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TREES - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Hermione moves deeper into the
                trees, then stops. SHADOWS splinter amid the towering trunks and VOICES come
                clearer. Standing utterly still, Hermione watches as aGANG of SNATCHERS make their
                way in her direction. They look unwashed and feral, as if they’ve been in the wild
                for some time. As they pass, within feet of her, but unable to see her, only
                Hermione’s eyes track their passage. As before Scabior leads the way, FENRIR
                GREYBACK at his side. Abruptly, Scabior stops, eyes narrowing. </stage>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> What’s that? That... smell? <stage> The others glance about dumbly.
                    Scabior retraces his steps until he stands directly in front of Hermione, his
                    eyes looking right through her. He leans forward ever-so slightly, only inches
                    from her neck, NOSTRILS FLARING. The locket TICKS, trembling upon Hermione’s
                    breastbone. Then, slowly, Scabior pulls back, eyes probing the darkness, before
                    withdrawing, leading the others away. The last pair drag what appear to be
                    BODIES. As they vanish within the trees, Hermione finally swallows.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Snatchers. <stage> She spins, finds Harry standing a few feet
                    off. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Good to know your enchantments work. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> He could smell it. My perfume. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TENT - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Ron pushes past the tent flap,
                peers into the darkness. In the distance, he sees Harry and Hermione. Standing
                close. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TREES - SAME TIME - NIGHT (ALT)  "> Hermione hugs herself.
                Shivers. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We have to leave. We’re not safe <stage> here. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I told you. Ron’s not strong<stage> enough to Apparate.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Then we’ll go by foot. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FARM - DAY "> We PAN DOWN FROM the sky, FIND the HORIZON. THREE
                FIGURES approach in the distance. Harry. Hermione. Ron. We HOLD. Then, faintly, so
                faint it can barely be heard at first, a SOFT WHISTLING SOUND rises on the breeze.
                We PAN BACK UP. Slowly, one by one, DOTS perforate the blue. The WHISTLING SOUND
                BUILDS. Harry stops, listening, then turns. Hermione trailing a few feet behind,
                stops, eyeing him questioningly. We RACK FOCUS, OVER her shoulder, watch the DOTS
                attenuate, take the shape of PLUMES. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FARM - BARN - DAY (SECONDS LATER) "> The WHISTLING is
                EAR-SPLITTING now, more of a ROAR, as the trio scarper into a listing barn and throw
                shut the doors. As they peer upward through the skeletal remains of the hayloft,
                their faces lashed with LIGHT, they see a succession of DEATH EATERS strafe the blue
                above. The rotting timber buzzes and BATS dance crazily in the loft above.
                Gradually, the sound recedes. The bats settle. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ROLLING LANDSCAPE -DAY (ALT)  "> An epic flyover. Three small
                figures move slowly below. One figure -- Ron -- trails the other two: Harry and
                Hermione. We CUT DOWN TO ground level. TO Ron. He glances about sullenly, staring at
                the forsaken landscape, then looks up ahead to Harry and Hermione. The sight of
                them, walking side-by-side, does nothing to improve his mood. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> I’m hungry. </sp>
            <stage>Harry and Hermione stop, turn. Study him for a moment. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I’m hungry. <stage>Hermione glances at Harry, who continues to stare at
                    Ron, as if taking the measure of him.</stage>
            </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We’re all hungry. <stage> Ron returns Harry’s glance, then looks off
                    again. Hermione crosses to Ron, examines his RAGGED BANDAGE. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Leave it. <stage> Hermione glances at Ron’s profile, then -- briefly --
                    atthe Horcrux dangling from his neck. Ignoring his words, she begins to rummage
                    in her beaded bag. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Mum can make food appear out ofthin air. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>tenderly</stage> No one can conjure food out ofthin air. Food is the first of
                the five Principal Exceptions toGamp’s Law. The other four are - </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>sharply</stage> Oh, speak English, can’t you? <stage> As Ron jerks his
                    injured arm away, Hermione looks up, meets Ron’s hard gaze. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I said leave it. <stage> Hermione glances at the bandage in her hand,
                    puts it away. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’ll be dark soon. We need to find a place to sleep. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Good plan. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah. Brilliant. Only, correct me if I’m wrong... wasn’t that
                yesterday’s plan? And the day before that? And the day before that? Walk. Sleep.
                Walk. Sleep. <stage> Harry stares at Ron, then begins to walk toward him. Hermione
                    watches silently. Ron stands utterly still. When Harry stops, he simply nods to
                    Ron’s neck. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> My turn. <stage> As he reaches out, Ron blocks his hand. For a moment,
                    they simply stand silently. Then Ron strips the chain from his neck, hands it to
                    Harry and brushes past him. Harry glances at Hermione, drapes the Horcrux over
                    his head and follows. Hermione watches them go, then does the same.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ENCAMPMENT (COOLING TOWERS) - LATE AFTERNOON "> A light RAIN
                falls. Harry, wearing the locket now, walks the perimeter of the camp. He glowers
                toward the tent in the distance. In the tent, safe, warm and out of earshot,
                Hermione tends to Ron’s arm as he stares at Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> He doesn’t know what he’s doing, does he? A frown creases Hermione’s
                forehead as she studies Ron, then she glances at Harry, a trace of doubt in her
                eyes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> None of us do. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" VALLEY - DAY "> Three figures move through a blood-red autumnal
                landscape. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ABANDONED CARAVAN PARK - DAY "> The charred husks of several
                RVs -- hulking black masses-- lay about the ash-ridden park. Ron, trailed by Harry
                and Hermione, pauses. His eyes scan the scorched earth, fix on a BLACKENED SWING,
                swaying back and forth in a tiny playground. His eyes shift to the ground and he
                crouches. His fingers shift the dry dirt, reveal a SHINY TOY not of Muggle making. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Wizards were here. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I don’t like this place. Harry and Ron both turn, look at her. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I want to go. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" CLEARING - DAY  "> RON’S FACE FILLS THE SCREEN -- unwashed and
                wild. He looks toward something UNSEEN. Then... ... a RABBIT hops INTO VIEW, nose
                probing some brush. Slowly, Ron raises his wand, poised to fire when...BAM! Dirt
                explodes near the rabbit’s rump and it is off and running. Seconds later, Harry
                appears, giving chase. Ron curses and pelts after. The rabbit zig-zags through the
                trees, eluding one blast after another as Harry and Ron trip through the forest.
                They begin laughing, their aim becoming more and more erratic. A tree limb explodes
                over Harry’s head and he wheels, fires playfully back at Ron. They exchange a few
                more blasts when one narrowly misses Harry. Instinctively, eyes flaring, he wheels,
                fires back at Ron, narrowly missing him. They both stop, stare at one another,
                chests heaving, their breath drifting in plumes, smiles gone. Ron rubs his injured
                arm, almost healed now, and turns away. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT"
                where=" TENT - SAME TIME - CLOSE ON A SIZZLING PAN OF MUSHROOMS.  - LATE AFTERNOON"
                >. In the shadows, Ron lies on his back, staring gloomily at the pitched ceiling of
                the tent, listening to the RADIO’S MURMUR, while Hermione, WEARING A RED SCARF
                AGAINST THE CHILL, runs the fingers of her left hand through Harry’s hair,
                alternately employing the wand in her right hand to trim Harry’s hair and flip the
                pages of A History of Magic. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Oh my god... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>alarmed</stage> What? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I’ll tell you in a minute. <stage> Harry watches his hair dropping
                    to the ground. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Maybe you could tell me now. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Alright. The Sword of Gryffindor? It’s Goblin made. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Brilliant. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You don’t understand. Dirt and rust have no effect on the blade.
                    <stage> It only takes in that which makes it stronger. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> O-kay. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry. You already destroyed one Horcrux, right? Tom Riddle’s diary
                -- in the Chamber of Secrets. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> With a basilisk fang. If you tell me you’ve got one of those in that
                bloody beaded bag of yours - </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Don’t you see! In the Chamber of Secrets, you stabbed the basilisk
                with the Sword of Gryffindor. Its blade is impregnated with basilisk venom. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It only takes in that which makes it stronger... </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Exactly! Which means... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> ...it can destroy Horcruxes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Which is why Dumbledore left it to you in his will. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’re brilliant, Hermione. Truly. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Actually, I’m highly logical, which allows me to look past the
                extraneous detail and perceive clearly that which others overlook. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> There’s only one problem... <stage> Suddenly the LIGHTS CLICK OFF...
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> The sword was stolen. <stage> The lights click back ON. Hermione and
                    Harry turn, seeRon, Deluminator in hand, lying in the shadows of his bunk,
                    staring at the roof as the FIRST DROPS OF RAIN hit the canvas above.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah, I’m still here. But you two carry on. Don’t let me spoil your fun.
                    <stage> Harry glances at Hermione, who is studying Ron warily. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What’s the problem? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Problem? There’s no problem. Not according to you, anyway. <stage> Heavy
                    DROPS of rain begin to PELT the canvas of the tent. Plunk. Plunk. Plunk.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Look, don’t be shy. If you’ve got something to say, spit it out.
                    <stage> Ron swings out of the bunk. As his face meets the light, he looks mean,
                    the locket chain glittering. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> All right, I’ll spit it out. Don’t expect me to skip up and down because
                now there’s some other damn thing we’ve got to find. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>quietly</stage> Ron... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I thought you knew what you signed up for. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah, I thought I did too. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I don’t understand. What part of this isn’t living up to your
                expectations? Did you think we’d be staying in five-star hotels? Finding a Horcrux
                every other day? Did you think you’d be back toMummy by Christmas? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No, I just reckoned after all this time, we’d have actually achieved
                something. I reckoned you knew what you were doing. I reckoned Dumbledore had told
                you something worthwhile! I reckoned you had a plan! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’ve told you everything Dumbledore told me! And in case you haven’t
                noticed, we’ve found a Horcrux! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah, and we’re about as near getting rid of it as we are to finding the
                rest of them, aren’t we! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Take it off, Ron. Please take it off. You wouldn’t be talking like
                this if you hadn’t been wearing it all day - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah, he would. D’you think I haven’t noticed the two of you
                whispering behind my back? D’you think I haven’t guessed what you were thinking? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, we weren’t - </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Don’t lie! You said it, too, you said you were disappointed - </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I didn’t! Not like that! Harry -- I didn’t! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Do you know why I listen to that radio, every night? Do you! To make
                sure I don’t hear Ginny’s name or Fred or George or Mum or - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You think I don’t listen! You think I don’t know what it’s like - </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> NO! YOU DON’T KNOW WHAT IT’S LIKE! YOUR PARENTS ARE DEAD! YOU HAVE NO
                FAMILY! <stage> Dead silence. Harry glares at Ron. Hermione looks shocked. Suddenly,
                    they both rush forward and lock on each other’s throats, Hermione rushes in.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Stop! Stop! <stage> They let go, step back. Harry points to Ron’s
                    neck. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Go then. But leave that. <stage> Hermione, eyes flashing with panic,
                    glances from Harry toRon. Ron strips the chain from his neck, casts it away,
                    then turns to Hermione. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> And you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Me? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Are you staying? Or coming? <stage> Hermione looks anguished, glancing
                    from one to the other. The canvas streams with rain behind her. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Fine. I get it. I saw you two the other night. Yeah, that’s right.
                Didn’t know I knew, did you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What? Ron, no -- please -<stage> He whips aside the tent flap and
                    the RAIN ROARS. As Hermione rushes after him, she tips over the radio. As it
                    HISSES Harry glowers at the Horcrux. Seconds later, Hermione returns, sopping
                    hair plastered to her face. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> He’s gone. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" RIVERBANK - MORNING  "> The river flows quietly, thick and
                muddy from the previous night’s rain. Harry emerges from the tent, peers into the
                trees. Hermione stands far down by the riverbank, tying the red scarf to a tree.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" RIVERBANK - LATE MORNING  "> Hermione, eyes red from crying,
                clutches the beaded bag in one hand while the locket dangles from the other. She
                peers one last time toward the trees, then, without turning, reaches out her hand.
                Harry studies her, then steps forward, gently takes her fingers in his. Instantly...
                ... they Disapparate, pitched into a whirlwind of darkness. As they reappear...
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HILLSIDE - LATE MORNING  "> ... on a windswept hillside, their
                hands break free and Hermione stumbles away, sobs racking her body as she buries her
                face in her hands. Harry watches her, then turns away, takes out his wand and begins
                to walk in a circle, casting enchantments in a soft voice. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Salvio Hexia... Protego Totalum... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HILLSIDE - DUSK  "> Harry walks the perimeter of the camp,
                looking up everys o often to look at the ILLUMINATED TENT. He watches HERMIONE’S
                SHADOW pass within, sliding over the canvas. Seconds later, the RADIO CRACKLES to
                life. He shakes his head, vaguely annoyed, then starts to move off again when a SONG
                comes CLEAR. He stops. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT - DUSK (SECONDS LATER)  "> As Harry ducks into the tent,
                Hermione looks up. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s a Muggle station. </sp>
            <stage>Hermione smiles and Harry does too. Harry listens then, debating, reaches out his
                hand. Hermione eyes him uncertainly, then allows him to pull her to her feet. He
                steps forward, gently removes the locket from her neck and tosses it to the ground.
                She looks at it, then back to him. He smiles and, without prompting... ... they
                begin to dance, tentatively at first, then letting themselves go. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TENT - SAME TIME - DUSK  "> Their shadows flicker upon the
                canvas like joyous shadow puppets, moving with abandon until, abruptly, the signal
                slips away and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT - SAME TIME - DUSK  "> ... the STATIC returns. Their
                smiles fade. They stop moving. Hermione averts her eyes, exits. Harry watches her
                go, then takes the locket from the floor, slings it over his neck. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HILLSIDE - DAY  "> Hermione, wrapped in a blanket, sits just
                outside the tent by a wind-whipped fire, going back and forth betweenTales of Beedle
                the Bard and another book, Spellman’s Syllabary. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT - SAME TIME - DAY  "> Harry lies on the top bunk above
                Ron’s empty lower, eyeing his face in the surface of the Snitch sitting there. As he
                takes it in hand, the wings begin to flap slowly up and down. He watches it for a
                long time... when an idea strikes. Folding his fingers around the orb, he brings it
                to his lips briefly, then turns it over in his palm. The Snitch’s tired wings go
                still. Then, as if written by an invisible hand, WORDS appear on the smooth golden
                surface: “I open at the close.” </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HILLSIDE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAY  "> Harry slips through the
                flap, hands her the Snitch. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You were right. It’s like you said. Snitches have flesh memories. But
                I didn’t catch my first Snitch with my hand. I almost swallowed it. <stage> Hermione
                    watches the WORDS VANISH on orb. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> ‘I open at the close?’ </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What do you reckon it means? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I don’t know. But look, I’ve found something as well... <stage> She
                    turns The Tales of Beedle the Bard into the flickering light, points to the top
                    of the title page, to a SMALL DRAWING of a TRIANGULAR EYE. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I thought it was a picture of an eye, but now I don’t think it is.
                It isn’t a rune and it’s not in Spellman’s Syllabary either. And it’s been inked in
                -- somebody drew it -- it isn’t part of the book. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Luna’s dad was wearing that, at Ron <stage>catching himself</stage> At
                Bill and Fleur’s wedding. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What d’you mean -- wearing it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Around his neck. Like an amulet. I didn’t think much of it at the
                time. You know Luna -- she’s always got some mad thing or the other she’s carrying
                around. I just figured it ran in the family. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Why would someone have drawn it in a children’s book? <stage> As
                    Hermione shakes her head, musing, Harry eyes her. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione, I’ve been thinking. I -- I want to go to Godric’s Hollow.
                It’s where I was born, it’s where my parents died - </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> And it’s exactly where You-Know- Who will expect you to go. Because
                it means something to you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But it means something to him too, Hermione. You-Know-Who nearly died
                there. Wouldn’t that be just the kind of place he’d hide a Horcrux? <stage> Hermione
                    eyes him. Despite herself, she knows he’s right. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s dangerous, Harry. But I have to admit, recently even I’ve been
                thinking we might have to go. I think it’s possible something else is hidden there.
                    <stage>off Harry’s look</stage> The sword. If Dumbledore didn’t want it falling
                into theMinistry’s hands, but wanted you to find it, what better place to hide it
                than the birthplace of the founder of Gryffindor himself? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Godric’s Hollow is the birthplace of Godric Gryffindor -- I mean,
                ’course it is. Obvious, isn’t it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>eyeing him knowingly</stage> Harry, did you ever even open A History of
                Magic? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Tossed it at Neville once when he was snoring -- might’ve popped open.
                    <stage> She smiles, then rises, collecting her books and blanket. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione... <stage> Words fail him. Hermione reaches out, lightly
                    strokes his hair as she heads toward the tent. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Don’t ever let me give you a haircut again. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" GODRIC’S HOLLOW - NIGHT  "> Golden streetlights glimmer along a
                narrow road leading to the center of town. Christmas decorations twinkle in the
                windows of small cottages, roofs blanketed in snow. Hermione and Harry Apparate INTO
                VIEW, wearing HEAVY COATS and hats, scarves wrapped around their mouths. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I still think we should’ve used Polyjuice Potion. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. This is where I was born. I’m not returning as someone else.
                    <stage> He holds out his arm and Hermione takes it. They move off. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TOWN CENTER - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry and Hermione
                walk, arms linked. A PUB DOOR opens briefly and LAUGHTER and MUSIC spill forth. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, I think it’s Christmas Eve! Listen... <stage> Her voice is
                    wistful. As they listen, VOICES carry from the church up ahead. Harry eyes the
                    GRAVEYARD beyond. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Do you think they’d be in there? My mum and dad? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Yeah. I think they would. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" CHURCH - CLOSER - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> The SINGING is FULL
                AND RICH here as Harry and Hermione make their way through the snow toward the
                graveyard. Harry peers up at the STAINED GLASS windows glittering over him. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" GRAVEYARD - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry pushes through a
                gate, then lets go of Hermione’s hand, row upon row of snowy tombstones stretch
                before him. As he heads off, Hermione studies him, then follows. NEW ANGLE -
                GRAVEYARD Hermione pauses by a large tombstone freckled with lichen. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Is it -- ? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No. But look. <stage> Harry steps over, looks: KENDRA DUMBLEDORE
                    AND HER DAUGHTER ARIANA. A quotation is etched in the granite: “Where your
                    treasure is, there will your heart be also.” </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Did you know he had a sister? <stage> Harry stares at the stone,
                    his face a mask. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. <stage>Harry turns away, walks off. </stage>
            </sp>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - TOMBSTONES Hermione walks amid the stones, studying the names, then
                stops by an extremely old grave. She crouches. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Lumos. <stage> Hermione plays the wand’s light over the surface of
                    the stone, then stops. Though deeply worn by time, the symbol is unmistakable:
                    the TRIANGULAR EYE. Hermione rakes the light over the name: IGNOTUS PEVERELL.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ignotus... Hey, Har - <stage>She stops. Harry stands several rows
                    away. Utterly still.</stage>
            </sp>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - HARRY As he stares at the tombstones of his parents: JAMES POTTER
                LILY POTTER Born 27 March 1960 Born 30 January 1960Died 31 October 1981 Died 31
                October 1981 “The last enemy that shall be destroyed is death.” Hermione appears,
                looks at Harry. Sees that tears are streaming down his cheeks. Hermione raises her
                wand, traces a circle in the air and a WREATH of CHRISTMAS ROSES blossom in the
                snow. Harry nods, staring at them. </stage>

            <sp who="#HARRY"> Happy Christmas, Hermione. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Happy Christmas, Harry. <stage> Hermione laces her arm around his
                    waist and he drapes his arm over her shoulder. They stand silently. Then:
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Someone’s watching us. By the gate. <stage> Harry nods, careful not
                    to look too soon, then glances up. A STOOPED FIGURE, barely discernible in the
                    drifting snow, stands in the shadows of the church. She -- it is distinctly
                    female, and older -- doesn’t move initially -- as if wanting Harry to see her --
                    then turns away. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> C’mon. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TOWN CENTER - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> All light has left the
                sky. The stooped figure hobbles along, past the pub, where shadows play against the
                windows and muffled voices can be heard. Harry and Hermione follow. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" NARROW ALLEY - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Hermione eyes the
                woman ahead, then looks about their surroundings, feeling trapped. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I don’t think this is a good idea. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We look like ordinary Muggles. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Muggles who’ve just been laying flowers on your parents’ grave.
                    <stage> Just then, up ahead, the stooped woman holds up her hand and Hermione
                    and Harry stop. Seconds later, a group ofSNATCHERS passes by the alley. As they
                    vanish, the woman continues on. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Relax. This is right. I know it. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" LANE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> The woman hobbles on. The lane
                is lined with modest cottages with small and tidy gardens. Hermione barely gives
                them a glance, nervously eyeing the woman ahead, before realizing she is walking
                alone. She turns, sees Harry standing several yards back, staring at a dark cottage,
                its garden overgrown with weeds, its roof entirely covered in ivy and snow. Hermione
                returns to him, looks. GASPS. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Omigod. Harry... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> This is where they died, Hermione.<stage> This is where he murdered
                    them. Hermione studies Harry’s bitter profile, then the house, careful not to
                    disturb the moment with words. Absently, Harry places his fingers upon the
                    locket at his chest. It is trembling -- over-so-slightly. Then, without turning,
                    while still staring at the house, Harry speaks: </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’re Bathilda, aren’t you? <stage> Hermione blinks, confused, then
                    turns and jumps. The old woman is standing only yards away, watching them.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BATHILDA BAGSHOT’S HOUSE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> The door
                rattles open and tiny BATHILDA BAGSHOT hobbles inside, followed first by Harry, then
                Hermione, who wrinkles her nose. As Bathilda exits the room, Hermione glances about. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, I’m not sure about this. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione, she knew Dumbledore. She might have the sword. Besides,
                she’s barely knee-high to a house-elf. I think we can overpower her if it turns
                ugly. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> There’s something odd about her. And what’s that smell? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> She’s gaga, remember? <stage> Bathilda returns, holding a box of
                    matches. She strikes one, tries to light a candle, but her movements are clumsy.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Here. Let me do that. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You have a lovely house, Miss Bagshot. Hermione eyes a PHOTOGRAPH
                of a CURIOUSLY COMPELLING YOUNG GIRL <stage>ARIANA</stage>, then runs a finger along
                a table. It comes away thick with dust. She frowns, looks up, finds Bathilda
                watching her. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Miss Bagshot? Who is this man? <stage> Harry stands by a chest of
                    drawers, holding the match over a grouping of PHOTOGRAPHS. Coated in DUST, the
                    figures in the frames flit like ghosts behind veils. Harry picks one up, wipes
                    away the dust with his hand. In it a merry-faced boy looks out, his cheery
                    expression belying a particularly intense gaze. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> His name. Can you tell me his name? <stage> Bathilda stares at the
                    photograph solemnly, then peers up at Harry. Her eyes are THICK with CATARACTS.
                    Harry stares, unnerved, then Hermione walks over, looks at the picture.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> This is him, Hermione. The one I saw in Gregorovitch’s wand shop. The
                thief. Miss Bagshot, who is he? <stage> She looks at him, then jerks her head toward
                    the stairs. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> She wants us to go upstairs. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> All right... <stage> As Hermione moves, Bathilda shakes her head,
                    points at Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> She wants me to go. Alone. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Why? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s all right. You stay here. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry... <stage> Harry holds up his hand, silencing her, then
                    follows Bathilda. Just before he disappears, he looks back and winks, but
                    Hermione doesn’t look reassured. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" SERPENTINE STAIRCASE - NIGHT (SECONDS LATER)  "> Harry trails
                Bathilda up a circular staircase, uncomfortably narrow and lined with books.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BAGSHOT HOUSE - SITTING ROOM - CLOSE ON A BOOK - "> </stage>
            <stage>SAME TIME - NIGHT The Life and Lies of Albus Dumbledore. A hand reaches in, takes
                it. Hermione’s hand. A NOTE is attached: “Dear Batty. Thanks for your help. You said
                everything... even if you don’t remember. Rita.” </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BAGSHOT HOUSE - BEDROOM - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Harry enters a
                dark low-ceilinged room. He wrinkles his nose at the smell, then hears the door
                close behind him. The room plunges into darkness. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Lumos. <stage> Harry sweeps the room, gives a start. Bathilda’s face
                    wavers in the dark, only feet away, staring at him. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HALLWAY - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Hermione hugs herself as she
                exits the sitting room and peers into the adjacent hallway. A sliver of the kitchen
                can be seen and a faint BUZZING heard. A strange SHADOW dances on one kitchen wall,
                of SPECKS moving. Hermione approaches. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BAGSHOT HOUSE - BEDROOM - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Harry watches
                as Bathilda moves closer, transfixed by her milky eyes. The Horcrux on his chest
                TWITCHES. </stage>
            <sp who="#BATHILDABAGSHOT">
                <stage>in Parseltongue</stage> You are Potter? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>in Parseltongue</stage> Yes. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BAGSHOT HOUSE - HALLWAY/KITCHEN - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> As
                Hermione nears the kitchen, she eyes the CLOUD of SPECKS swarming the wall
                curiously. The BUZZING GROWS to a HISS as the room... comes INTO VIEW. Hermione
                GASPS. CLOTTED BLOOD streaks the sink and great wide swaths of RED stain the floor
                where HUNDREDS OF FLIES swarm. </stage>
            <sp who="#BATHILDABAGSHOT">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> (in Parseltongue) I have something for you... <stage> Hermione’s
                    gaze rises, to the ceiling, to the HEATING VENT, from which the hissing voice
                    has just come. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BAGSHOT HOUSE - BEDROOM - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Harry’s arm
                droops, his wand tip painting the room with dots of light as he sways, wincing as
                his scar stings. Bathilda points, to a dressing table cluttered with soiled laundry,
                her milky eyes fixed on Harry. Something surfaces in her filmy corneas, her pupils
                changing from dots to silts. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" SERPENTINE STAIRCASE - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Hermione, wand
                drawn, ascends the stairs. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BAGSHOT HOUSE - BEDROOM - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Harry peers at
                the foul laundry, moving closer, when, out of the corner of his eye, Bathilda moves
                weirdly. He wheels and watches in horror as... Bathilda’s old body collapses and
                Nagini pours from her neck. As Harry raises his wand, Nagini STRIKES, piercing his
                forearm. His wand flies out of his hand, its light spinning dizzily around the room.
                Nagini’s tail swings about, knocks Harry’s legs out from under him. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Harry! </sp>
            <stage>As Harry rolls onto his back, gasping for breath, Nagini’s massive body rolls
                over him, the Horcrux ticking feverishly against his chest. As Harry ROARS in pain,
                the lenses of his GLASSES fracture. The bedroom door swings open, reveals Hermione
                silhouetted against the stairwell, wand poised. A FLASH OF RED LIGHT ricochets
                around the room and Nagini’s tail whips angrily about, shattering the bedroom
                window. Hermione dives aside and Harry covers his face as the curtains burst into
                flames and shards of glass shower the room in a rush of cold air. As Harry reclaims
                his wand and rises, Nagini’s body uncoils in fury, splintering furniture and
                blasting holes into the walls. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Confringo! <stage> As Hermione’s spell caroms off the trembling
                    walls, we see both her and Harry reflected in a MIRROR. He leaps, sweeping her
                    toward the smoldering window. As they pitch themselves into the night, the
                    mirror EXPLODES and shards of glass, reflecting bits of Hermione and Harry and
                    the giant snake, tumble in the night, slowly vanishing into... nothingness.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" RIVER/WOODS (FOREST OF DEAN) - DAY  "> Weirdly quiet. Like the
                memory of a day long ago. A lone figure -- Hermione -- walks from the river to the
                woods, a pail of water in hand, leaving silent footprints in the FROST that glitters
                on the ground. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT (FOREST OF DEAN) - EARLY MORNING DARKNESS. "> For a
                moment, we hear nothing. Then, Hermione’s voice SOFTLY WHISPERS: </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Harry... Harry, can you hear me...? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Good. That’s good... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> We got away. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Are you alright? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> I’m fine. But you’ve been sick. Rest... Rest a bit more...
                    <stage> All stays DARK... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TENT (FOREST OF DEAN) - MORNING  "> Hermione sits reading a
                BOOK by the fire. is glorious, overlooking a vast valley. The hillside </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> You’ve outdone yourself this time. Hermione turns, finds Harry
                standing outside the tent, admiring the view. He looks pale, battle-worn. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> The Forest of Dean. I came here once with my mum and dad, years
                ago. It’s just how I remember it. The trees. The river. It’s like nothing’s changed.
                Not true, of course. Everything’s changed. If I brought my parents here, they
                wouldn’t recognize any of it. Not the trees. Not the river. Not... me. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Where are they? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Wendell and Monica Wilkens now reside happily in Sydney, Australia.
                They have two dogs, run a small sweet shop, but floss daily. No children. She
                smiles, then it fades. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Maybe we should just stay here, Harry. Grow old. Harry has no
                words. She inhales, shakes off her tears. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You wanted to know who the boy in the photograph was. Well, I know.
                    <stage> Hermione holds up the book in her lap: The Life and Lies of Albus
                    Dumbledore. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It was in Bathilda’s sitting room. Rita Skeeter had sent it to her.
                Harry, it doesn’t make for very nice reading - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who is he, Hermione? The thief? Did Dumbledore know him? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> For a time. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Tell me, Hermione. Who is he? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Gellert Grindelwald. He’s not very well known in Britain, but there
                was a time, before You-Know-Who... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione, I don’t need to have read A History of Magic to know who
                Gellert Grindelwald is. Hermione nods, hands him the book, open to a PHOTOGRAPH of a
                TEENAGED DUMBLEDORE laughing with another BOY<stage>GELLERT GRINDELWALD</stage>. The
                caption: “For the Greater Good? Dark Days; Dumbledore and Grindelwald.” On the
                opposite page is a PHOTOGRAPH of Grindelwald in later days, clad in black, holding a
                JAGGED WAND -- no longer the carefree lad of youth. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> When Grindelwald was seventeen, he was expelled from Durmstrang.
                He’d started doing some twisted things at school -- experiments. A few teachers had
                always protected him, but they couldn’t anymore. After he left, he traveled for
                awhile, then ended up in Godric’s Hollow where his great aunt lived, Bathilda
                Bagshot. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Get to the hard part, Hermione. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> She introduced him to Dumbledore. It made sense. Dumbledore’s
                mother had just died, Grindelwald was troubled and they were both brilliant --
                they’d never really had anyone they could talk to ont he same level. They did a lot
                of talking that summer. But they always returned to one particular subject. <stage>
                    Harry looks up. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Wizard rule over Muggles. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And Dumbledore believed in it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Yes. <stage> Harry nods, looking at the photograph again.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> ‘For the Greater Good.’ What does that mean? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It was something Dumbledore came up with. He believed wizards were
                superior and should rule overMuggles, but gently, for their own good. Grindelwald
                took a more violent position. <stage> Harry shakes his head, staring at the book.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It was a different time, Harry. It was one summer. Dumbledore was
                young - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We’re young, Hermione. And here we are, risking our lives to fight
                against the very thing Dumbledore supported. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> He changed, Harry. Years later, it was Dumbledore who put
                Grindelwald in prison. <stage> Harry stares at the photograph of the laughing thief
                    one last moment, then tosses the book away. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Where’s my wand? I’ll take the watch. <stage> Hermione hesitates. Her
                    expression makes him apprehensive. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione. Where’s my wand? <stage> She points. There, lying by the
                    fire, is a shattered stick. He picks it up gently, sees that it is nearly
                    severed in two. One fragile strand of phoenix feather holds it together.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s my fault. As we were leaving Godric’s Hollow, I cast a curse
                and it rebounded... I’m sorry, Harry, I tried to mend it but wands are different - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s done. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Maybe we can - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s done. <stage> His tone puts an end to it. She nods. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Leave me yours. You get back in the warm. And give me that. <stage>
                    Harry gestures to the locket. Hermione starts to speak, then simply hands it
                    over. She starts to leave, pauses. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> He loved you, Harry. I know he loved you. </sp>
            <stage>She trails her fingers lightly over his hair, and he closes his eyes. We
                -DISSOLVE TO: </stage>

        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TENT (FOREST OF DEAN) - NIGHT (LATER)  "> The fire is merely
                embers. Harry sits with a frost- encrusted blanket draped over his shoulders,
                staring bitterly into the dark forest. The silence is eerie, SHADOWS play in the
                trees. He peers through the tent flap and sees Hermione slumbering in the light of a
                SMALL BOWL of FLAMES. Then, slowly, LIGHT CRAWLS briefly over the tent canvas and he
                turns, peers into the forest once more. Something seems to GLIMMER FAINTLY, but so
                briefly as to seem a trick of the eye. The air is cold, gives texture to the
                darkness, makes it a living thing. And then it is there again, the LIGHT -- pure and
                bright and silver and moving through the trees toward him. Harry rises and the
                blanket slithers off his shoulders. Gripping Hermione’s wand, he watches the LIGHT
                drift closer, then shatter throughout the trees, momentarily blinding. And then it
                appears... ... a SILVER-WHITE DOE, moon-bright and dazzling. It gazes at Harry and
                he stands, transfixed. And then the doe turns away. His voice cracks: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FOREST OF DEAN - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> FROST CRUNCHES
                beneath Harry’s feet as he dashes through the trees in pursuit of the silent doe up
                ahead, breath streaming from his lungs. She leads him deep into the forest until,
                finally, she stops, as does Harry. As he watches, she turns her beautiful head
                toward him... and vanishes. For a moment, a GHOST IMAGE of her, like a retina burn,
                hangs in the air and then Harry is plunged into darkness. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Lumos! <stage> Hermione’s wand-tip ignites. Harry paints the clearing
                    with light and something GLEAMS: a small FROZEN POOL. He crosses to it, looks
                    down. He sees his own image reflected dully and then, deeper, within, a SILVER
                    CROSS. He looks closer. It is the SWORD OF GRYFFINDOR. Harry steps back, blinks.
                    It’s still there. He glances about, painting the trees with light, looking to
                    insure he is alone, then casts light upon the pool once more. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Accio Sword. <stage> Nothing. Harry walks about the pool again and
                    again and then stops. He crouches... ... and looks slowly down at his chest. The
                    Horcrux around his neck has begun to TWITCH. Harry places his fingers upon it
                    briefly, then rises. Quickly, with fumbling fingers, he SHEDS his clothes and
                    points Hermione’s wand at the pool. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Diffindo. <stage> The pool’s icey crust CRACKS, echoing in the
                    silence. CHUNKS of DARK ICE rock the surface. Harry steps to the pool’s edge,
                    peers within... and PLUNGES... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ICY POOL (FOREST OF DEAN) - UNDERWATER - CONTINUOUS  "> ACTION
                - NIGHT ... SCREAMING in the dark silence of the chill water. He kicks down to the
                glimmering sword, grabs the hilt and kicks for the surface when... ... the locket’s
                chain begins to COIL, tightening like aSNAKE about his neck. As the links bite into
                his throat, he releases the sword and begins to thrash about, struggling to get his
                fingers under the chain. Realizing it’s no use... ... he reaches for the pool’s
                edge, his fingers scrabbling desperately over the ice, but unable to gain purchase.
                Slowly, his hands go limp and slip from the ice back into... ... the water, where he
                drifts slowly down, a slow trail of bubbles escaping his mouth, eyes half-closed as
                he peers upward, watching as the surface of the water grows slowly calm...
                peaceful... when... a SHADOW appears and... ... a PAIR of HANDS shatter the glassy
                surface of the water and Harry is pulled upward and out, landing... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FOREST OF DEAN - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> ... face-down on
                the frigid ground, choking and retching. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione... <stage> A HAND reaches in, strips the locket from his
                    neck. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Are -- you --mental? <stage> Harry’s eyes pop open. Standing a few yards
                    away, fully dressed and half-drenched, clutching the sword of -- Gryffindor in
                    one hand and the locket in the other, isRon. Harry just stares, then begins to
                    pull on his clothes. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It was you! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well, yeah. Bit obvious, I'd think. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And the doe. That was you as well. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No. I reckoned it was you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> My Patronus is a stag. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Right. Antlers. <stage> Ron brings his arms up, vaguely pantomiming
                    antlers, but the effect is lost, what with the sword and locket. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You didn’t see anyone else? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No, I... I did think maybe I saw something -- when I was running -- over
                there --<stage> Harry crosses to a pair of OAKS grown close together. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Anything? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>shaking his head</stage> But I reckon whoever cast the doe, put the sword in
                that pool hoping we’d find it. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> And we did, didn’t we? <stage> The “we” hangs in the chill air. Harry
                    eyes Ron, then steps forward and dangles the locket close to the sword. It
                    immediately begins to TWITCH. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> See that? It knows. It’s afraid. <stage>looking up</stage> Do it. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What? No. Harry. That thing’s bad for me. I can’t handle it. I’m not
                making excuses for how I acted, but that thing affects me more than it affects you
                and Hermione. It made me think stuff -- stuff I was thinking anyway, but it made
                everything worse. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> All the more reason. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No. I can’t -- </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Then why are you here? Why did you come back? <stage> Harry’s tone is
                    hard, meant to wound. This stops Ron. He steps back, grips the sword with both
                    hands. Harry nods. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’ll have to speak to it in order for it to open. When it does, don’t
                hesitate. I don’t know what’s in here, but it’ll put up a fight. The bit of Riddle
                that was in his diary tried to kill me. <stage> Ron nods and then Harry sweeps a
                    layer of frost from a flat rock, lays the locket down. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> On three. One. Two. Three. <stage>in Parseltongue</stage> Take me
                inside... <stage> Click! The twin doors of the locket SNAP open. Behind each glass
                    window a LIVING EYE blinks -- Tom Riddle’s eyes. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Stab it, Ron. Now. <stage> Ron raises his trembling hands, poises the
                    sword. Then a VOICE hisses from the Horcrux. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOICE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> I have seen your heart and it is mine... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Don’t listen to it. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOICE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> I have seen your dreams, Ronald Weasley, and I have seen your
                fears... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron. Don’t listen to it! </sp>
            <sp who="#VOICE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> Least loved, by the mother who craved a daughter. Least loved,
                by the girl who prefers your friend... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron. Stab it! <stage> The locket QUIVERS in Harry’s fingers, turning
                    WHITE-HOT, and he releases it. As the eyes gleam SCARLET, Harry grimaces and a
                    FLASH OF BLINDING LIGHT BURSTS forth, leaving in its wake two FIGURES floating
                    in the darkness-- GHOST IMAGES of Harry and Hermione. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RIDDLE-HARRY"> We were better without you, happier without you. </sp>
            <sp who="#RIDDLE-HERMIONE"> Who could look at you beside Harry Potter? What are you,
                compared with the Chosen One...? <stage> Ron stands transfixed, sword in hand,
                    horrified. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron. It lies! Stab it! STAB IT! </sp>
            <sp who="#RIDDLE-HARRY"> Your mother confessed that she would have preferred me as a
                son... </sp>
            <sp who="#RIDDLE-HERMIONE"> Who wouldn’t prefer him, what woman would take you, you are
                nothing, nothing, nothing to him... <stage> The ghostly Hermione, frightening yet
                    beautiful, entwines herself around the ghostly Harry, her hair running like silk
                    over their faces as she leans forward and covers his mouth with hers.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Do it, Ron! Kill it! <stage>Ron’s head turns then, to Harry, and Harry
                    freezes. A trace of SCARLET glints in Ron’s eyes. He raises the sword high and
                    -- for a moment -- Harry looks fearful. Then, Ron pivots and brings the blade
                    down hard, cleaving the locket. A SCREAM echoes throughout the forest and the
                    ghostly Harry and Hermione turn to dust, becoming one with the vapor drifting
                    from Ron’s mouth and all is... Quiet. Harry eyes the shattered locket, then
                    turns his gaze onRon who stands alone, sword dangling from the end of his arm,
                    chest heaving. Harry scoops up the locket and examines it. Riddle’s eyes are
                    gone, the silk lining stained and faintly smoking. Ron lets the sword fall to
                    the ground, drops to his knees. Harry steps forward and -- carefully -- places a
                    hand upon his shoulder.</stage>
            </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> After you left, she cried for a week. She’s like my sister. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I’m sorry. I’m sorry I left. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’ve sort of made up for it tonight. Getting the sword. Finishing
                off the Horcrux. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Saving your life. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> That too. <stage> They both stare at the remains of the locket.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> And just think of it. Only three to go. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT (FOREST OF DEAN) - DAWN (LATER)  "> The bowl of flames
                boils timidly now; Hermione still slumbers. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Hermione! <stage> She stirs, sits up. Pushing her hair out of
                    her face, she peers through the tent flap. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" TENT (FOREST OF DEAN) - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAWN  "> Harry
                sticks the sword in the ground. As Hermione emerges, she blinks against the
                brightness of the morning sun. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Everything all right? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Fine. Actually... more than fine. <stage> He steps aside and Hermione
                    sees Ron, standing at the edge of the camp. She stares, mute, then walks
                    pastHarry and the ashes of the campfire, stopping right in front of Ron. He
                    raises a hand, smiles sheepishly. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Hey. <stage> And then... Hermione begins to PUNCH HIM. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Wo -- hey -- ouch! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>with each punch</stage> You -- complete --arse -- Ronald -- Weasley! You
                crawl back here after all these weeks and say, ‘Hey?’ (turning to Harry) Where’s my
                wand? Harry, where’s my wand! <stage> Harry places his hand over his pocket.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Um... I don’t know? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry Potter, you give me my wand! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> How come he’s got your wand? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Never mind why he’s got my wand -<stage> stopping</stage> What is
                that? <stage> She stares at the blackened locket dangling in Ron’s hand.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You destroyed it? <stage> Hermione glances at Harry. He indicates
                    Ron. She turns back to Ron. He nods. She starts to speak when her eyes shift,
                    see the sword stuck in the ground. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> And exactly how is it you have theSword of Gryffindor? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s a long story. <stage> Hermione ponders this, baffled, then looks
                    back at Ron. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Don’t think this changes anything. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No, of course not. I only destroyed a bloody freaking Horcrux! Why would
                that change anything! Do you know what it was like for me to hear those words coming
                from you! To see you doing those things -<stage> Ron stops. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> See me doing what things? <stage> Ron blinks, mortified. Hermione
                    turns to Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What happened out there? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>at a loss, then</stage> It’s a long story. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Look, I wanted to come back the minute I’d left. I just... didn’t know
                how to find you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Exactly how did you find us? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> With this. <stage> Ron reaches into his pocket, pulls out the
                    Deluminator. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> It doesn’t just turn off lights. I don’t know exactly how it works, but
                Christmas morning I -- I was sleeping -- in this little pub-- I’d given some
                Snatchers the slip the night before, me being a blood- traitor and all -- anyway, I
                was sleeping when I heard it... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> A voice. <stage> Ron turns to Hermione, holds up the Deluminator.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Your voice, Hermione. Coming out of this. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> And what may I ask did I say? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> My name. Just my name. Like a whisper. <stage> Hermione stands perfectly
                    still... and blushes. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> So I took this and I clicked it and this tiny ball of light appeared.
                And I knew. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Knew what? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Just knew. On account of Hermione’s voice. And sure enough, it floated
                toward me, the ball of light, right to my chest and then -- went straight through--
                right here. <stage> Ron touches a point close to his heart. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I could feel it inside me. It was warm, like the first sip of a good cup
                of tea. And I knew it would take me where I needed to go. So I Disapparated and came
                out on this hillside. It was dark. I didn’t have any idea where I was. I just had to
                hope one of you would show yourselves in the end. And you did. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT (FOREST OF DEAN) - NIGHT  "> Harry lies in his bunk while
                Ron sits cross-legged, warming his hands over a bowl of FLAMES. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> I’ve always liked it. These flames Hermione makes. <stage> Harry peers
                    at the bowl, then beyond the tent flap, sees Hermione sitting just outside,
                    keeping watch. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> How long you reckon she’ll stay mad at me? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Keep talking ‘bout that little ball of light touching your heart --
                she’ll come round. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> It was true. Every word. <stage>a beat</stage> You’re going to think I’m
                mental, but I think that’s why Dumbledore left it to me -- the Deluminator. I think
                he knew that at some point I’d... need to find my way back. And she’d lead me.
                    <stage> Harry eyes Ron, pondering this. Then suddenly, Ron jump sup, grabs his
                    own rucksack and begins to fish through it. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell. I just realized.<stage> You need a wand, right?
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah... </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well, I’ve got one. Here. It’s Blackthorn, ten inches, nothing special,
                but I reckon it’ll do. I took it off a Snatcher a few weeks back.
                    <stage>whispering</stage> Don’t tell Hermione, but they’re a bit dim, Snatchers.
                This one was definitely part Troll. The smell off him... <stage> Harry points the
                    wand at the flames. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Engorgio. <stage> The flames FLARE MASSIVELY and Ron leaps back.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Wo. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Reducio! <stage> As the flames subside, Ron pats down a small flare-up
                    on the canvas. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What’s going on in there? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> Nothing. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>to Harry</stage> Maybe a bit more practice, eh? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We need to talk. <stage> Ron wheels, sees Hermione standing in the
                    mouth of the tent, Life and Lies in hand, looking at Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> All right. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>ignoring him</stage> I want to go and see Xenophilius Lovegood. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sorry? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> See this? It’s a letter Dumbledore wrote to Grindelwald. Look at
                the signature. It’s the mark again. <stage> Hermione turns the book in Harry’s
                    direction. Dumbledore replaced the “A” in Albus with the TRIANGULAR EYE.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It keeps cropping up. Here. In Beedle the Bard. In the graveyard in
                Godric’s Hollow -- what? <stage> Hermione looks at Harry, who is staring hard at the
                    book. Suddenly, we are... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" VILLAGE STREET - DAWN  "> ... MOVING through the village
                streets again, PAST the cloaked figures, turning down the narrowing alleyway that
                leads toward Gregorovitch’s wand shop and... HOLDING on the TRIANGULAR SYMBOL
                scratched crudely into the wall... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT (FOREST OF DEAN) - SAME TIME - NIGHT  "> Harry blinks. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Jesus. It was there too. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Where? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Outside Gregorovitch’s wand shop. on the alley wall... </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> But what does it mean? <stage> They all look down at the symbol etched
                    in Dumbledore’s fine hand in the book. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, you don’t have a clue where the next Horcrux is. And neither
                do I. But this, this means something. I’m sure of it. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I think Hermione’s right. I think we ought to go and see Lovegood. What
                say we vote on it? Those in favor... <stage> Ron’s hand flies into the air. Harry
                    eyes him knowingly. Hermione rolls her eyes, then lifts her hand as well.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Sorry, Harry. Looks like it’s Hermione and me this time. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HILLSIDE - LATE AFTERNOON  "> The sun hangs low over a hillside
                gloriously free of snow. Ron leads the way, far ahead of Harry and Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Not still mad at him, are you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I’m always mad at him. <stage> As we RISE, a STRANGE-LOOKING HOUSE
                    appears in the distance, etched like a great black cylinder against the sky.
                    Seeing it, Ron turns back, GRINNING as he calls out. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Luna? <stage> Harry and Hermione take a look. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY #HERMIONE"> Luna. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" LOVEGOOD HOUSE - FRONT DOOR - LATE AFTERNOON  "> A SIGN is
                tacked to a door studded with nails: “THE QUIBBLER. EDITOR: X. LOVEGOOD. Hermione
                raps three times. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Keep off the dirigible plums. <stage> Hermione turns, gives him an odd
                    look. Ron points to aSIGN: “KEEP OFF THE DIRIGIBLE PLUMS.” Just then, the door
                    swings open and Xenophilius Lovegood appears, barefoot, wearing a soiled
                    nightshirt. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD">
                <stage>to Hermione</stage> What is it? (to Ron) Who are you? (to Harry) What do you
                want --<stage> Seeing Harry, Lovegood’s jaw goes slack in shock. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hello, Mr. Lovegood. I’m Harry Potter. We met a few months back?
                    <stage> Lovegood’s eyes drift to Harry’s scar. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Would it be okay if we came in? It won’t take long, sir. I promise.
            </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" LOVEGOOD HOUSE - PRESS ROOM - LATE AFTERNOON  "> Great
                tottering towers of Quibbler back-issues rise to the ceiling while an old-fashioned
                WOODEN PRINTING PRESS chugs away in the center of the room, spitting out new ones. </stage>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Excuse me. </sp>
            <stage>As Lovegood steps to the wheezing press, the trio glanc eat past QUIBBLERS laying
                about: MUGGLE MURDERS RISE, DOZENS DIE AS DEATH EATERS ATTACK, HARRY IN HIDING,
                WHERE IS THE CHOSEN ONE? YOU-KNOW-WHO CLAIMS ANOTHER VICTIM: QUIDDITCH WORLD CUP
                CANCELLED AMID DEATH THREATS. Abruptly, the press goes silent and Lovegood turns. </stage>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> So. What brings you here, Mr. Potter? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well, sir, we need some help. </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Ah. Help. I see. Yes, well, the thing is, helping Harry
                Potter, rather dangerous these days... <stage> The trio exchange glances.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Aren’t you the one who keeps telling everyone it’s their first duty to
                help Harry? </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> I have expressed that view, yes. In the past. Would you
                excuse me one moment. I shall return shortly and, um, try to help you... <stage>
                    Lovegood dashes from the room. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What’s going on here? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> He’s mental. Let’s face it. Luna’s always good value, but she’s nutty as
                squirrel poo. <stage> Just then, Hermione GASPS, points to an ENORMOUS SPIRAL HORN
                    mounted on the wall. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Do you see that? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well, yeah, of course. It’s massive, isn’t it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No! Don’t go near it! <stage> Harry stops. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s an Erumpent horn. It’s a Class B Tradeable Material. <stage>
                    Harry and Ron exchange a “she’s mental” glance. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah, all right... <stage> Just then, Lovegood returns with a TRAY
                    rattling with CUPS. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> May I offer you all an infusion of Gurdyroots? We make
                it ourselves. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Where is Luna, sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Luna? Oh, um, she’ll be along. Now how can I help you,
                Mr. Potter? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well, sir, it’s about something you were wearing around your neck at
                the wedding. A symbol... </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> You mean this? <stage> Lovegood reaches into his
                    nightshirt and pulls out the chain with the TRIANGULAR EYE. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes! Exactly. What we wondered, sir, is, well, what is it? </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> What is it? Well, it’s the sign of the Deathly Hallows,
                of course. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY #RON #HERMIONE"> The what? </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> The Deathly Hallows. I assume you’re all familiar with
                ‘The Tale of the Three Brothers?’ </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE #RON #HARRY"> Yes. No. <stage> Harry looks at the others, then
                    Hermione reaches into her beaded bag and pulls out The Tales of Beedle the Bard.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s in here. </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Well, there’s no real reason to go on unless one is
                familiar with the tale. Why don’t you read it aloud, Miss...? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Granger. Well... all right. <stage>opening the book</stage> There
                were once three brothers who were traveling along a lonely, winding road at twilight
                - </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Midnight. Mum always said midnight. <stage>as Hermione glowers</stage>
                But twilight’s fine. Better actually. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> In time, the brothers reached a river too treacherous to pass...
                    <stage>As Hermione continues, Lovegood looks out the window. A CROW cycles INTO
                    VIEW and we FOLLOW it, the sky DARKENING... STORY - EXT. RIVER/BRIDGE - TWILIGHT
                    ...as the crow swoops over a river to reveal THREE SILHOUETTES. </stage>
            </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> But being learned in the magical arts, the three brothers simply
                waved their wands and made a bridge. They were halfway across it when they found
                their path blocked by a hooded figure. <stage> A BRIDGE MAGICALLY MATERIALIZES and
                    the three figures begin to cross, when the HOODED FIGURE appears. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> It was Death and he felt cheated, for travelers usually drowned
                in the river. But Death was cunning. He granted each brother a wish for their
                cleverness. The oldest, who was a combative man, asked for a wand more powerful than
                any in existence. So Death fashioned one from an elder tree on the banks of the
                river. <stage> All of this is dramatized in surreal silhouette. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> The second brother, who was an arrogant man, asked for the power
                to recall others from Death. So Death plucked a stone from the river. Finally Death
                turned to the third brother. A humble man, he asked for something that would make
                him disappear. And so it was that Death handed over his own Cloak of Invisibility.
                Death then stepped aside and the brothers went their separate ways... <stage> We see
                    the brothers cross the bridge, and part. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> The first brother traveled to a distant village where, with
                ElderWand in hand, he killed a wizard with whom he had once quarreled. Proceeding to
                an Inn, he bragged of his invincibility. But that very night... <stage> We see a
                    wizard, in shadow, slip into a room, KNIFE in hand. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> ... another wizard crept upon him as he lay sleeping. He took
                the Elder Wand... and slit the brother’s throat for good measure. And so Death took
                the first brother for his own... We see the second brother approach a cottage. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> Meanwhile, the second brother journeyed to his home, where he
                took out the stone and turned it thrice in hand. To his delight, the girl he had
                once hoped to marry before her untimely death appeared before him. Yet soon she
                turned sad and cold, for she did not belong in the mortal world. Driven mad with
                hopeless longing, the second brother killed himself so as to join her. And so Death
                took the second brother... <stage> We see Death etched upon a bleak hillside.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>V.O.</stage> As for the third brother, Death searched for many years but was
                never able to find him. Only when he had attained a great age did the youngest
                brother shed theCloak of Invisibility and give it to his son. He then greeted Death
                as an old friend and went with him gladly, departing this life as equals... <stage>
                    As Death and the third brother retreat, the crow returns, beating into the sky,
                    which LIGHTENS, and we PULL BACK... </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" LOVEGOOD HOUSE - PRESS ROOM - DUSK  "> ... to find Xenophilius
                Lovegood staring out the window. The sun has nearly vanished over the lip of the
                hill. </stage>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Well, there you are. Those are the Deathly Hallows. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sorry... I still don’t really understand... <stage> Lovegood turns
                    and, taking quill and parchment, draws a STRAIGHT VERTICAL LINE... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> The Elder Wand... <stage> ... then adds a CIRCLE on top
                    of the line... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> The Resurrection Stone... <stage> ... then encloses both
                    in a TRIANGLE. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> The Cloak of Invisibility. Together... they make the
                Deathly Hallows. Together... they make one master of Death. <stage> The trio stare
                    at the symbol. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Mr. Lovegood, does the Peverell family have anything to do with the
                Deathly Hallows? <stage>to Harry and Ron</stage> That was the name on the grave with
                the mark on it in Godric’s Hollow. Ignotus Peverell. </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Ignotus and his brothers Cadmus and Antioch are thought
                to be the original owners of the Hallows and therefore the inspiration for the
                story. <stage> Lovegood’s focus abruptly wavers, sadness in his eyes, then he
                    blinks, eyes the tea kettle. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Ah, but your tea’s grown cold. Excuse me, I'll be right
                back. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>as Lovegood exits</stage> Let’s get out of here once he’s back. I’m not
                touching this stuff, hot or cold. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>lost in thought</stage> Which one would you choose if you could? Of the
                Deathly Hallows? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s obvious, isn’t it? <stage>All three speak at once:</stage> The
                Wand. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON #HERMIONE"> The Cloak. The Stone. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> They glance at each other, amused. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You’re supposed to say the Cloak, but who wants to spend all day being
                invisible. Dead boring if you ask me. But an unbeatable wand! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Its owner grew drunk with power and was murdered. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah, but imagine what a short wicked life you’d lead. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>rolling her eyes</stage> Why the Stone, Harry? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well, you could bring people back, couldn’t you? Mad-Eye. Dumbledore.
                Sirius. Anybody. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>gentle</stage> But according to the story they don’t want to come back. It’s
                all rubbish anyway. There’s no such thing as the Deathly Hallows. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But I have one. The InvisibilityCloak my father left me. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> There have always been Cloaks -- </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Not like Harry’s. I’ve seen a fair few. Dad used to bring home the ones
                the Ministry confiscated from petty thieves and the like. They always got holes or
                tears. Harry’s is different. It’s perfect. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And I think I’ve actually held theResurrection Stone in my hands, that
                night in Dumbledore’s office when he showed me the ring he’d destroyed, the Horcrux.
                It had a symbol on it. Now I think it was the mark of the Hallows. <stage> The trio
                    stand silently when Lovegood returns. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Mr. Lovegood. Thank you, sir -- </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You forgot the water. </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> The water? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> For the tea. </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Did, didn’t I? How silly of me. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No matter, sir. We really ought to be go- </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> No, you mustn’t - </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> You’re my only hope. They were angry, you see, about
                what I’d been writing, so they took her. They took my Luna... <stage>eyes finding
                    Harry</stage> But it’s really you they want... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who took her, sir? <stage> Hermione eyes the printing press. A copy of
                    the Quibbler lies stuck under a roller. She reaches out, pulls it free, the INK
                    STREAKING over the cover, over HARRY’S FACE and the BLAZING HEADLINE:
                    UNDESIRABLE NUMBER #1. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Him. Surely you call him You-Know-Who. But his real name
                of course is... Voldemort. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Nooooooooo! <stage> Instantly, out the window, FIGURES on BROOMSTICKS
                    appear in the sky, jetting directly toward the house. As Harry, Ron and Hermione
                    hit the floor, ROPES of LIGHT ricochet off the windowsill. The printing press
                    EXPLODES, rainingQuibblers everywhere, like a flock of doves, smoking with
                    flames. Lovegood waves madly from the window. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#XENOPHILIUSLOVEGOOD"> Stop! I’ve got him --<stage> Lovegood is blasted off his
                    feet by a Stunning Spell so great the chain around his neck flies across the
                    room and settles at Harry’s feet. Harry glances down, watches the symbol of the
                    Deathly Hallows dissolve like mercury, then looks up, sees Lovegood streak out
                    the door. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron! Harry! Take my hand! <stage> Harry and Ron begin to crawl on
                    their knees toward Hermione when another volley of spells ricochet about the
                    room and -- ping! -- strike the Gurdyroot teapot. As Hermione watches, it flies
                    into the air, tumbling end over end toward the Erumpent Horn. Harry’s hand
                    closes on hers, Ron reaches out and... ... the teapot strikes the Erumpent Horn.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" LOVEGOOD HOUSE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DUSK  "> There is a
                COLOSSAL EXPLOSION. The second floor of the black cylinder ruptures. Quibblers belch
                into the air like confetti as Lovegood narrowly escapes and the DeathEaters are
                engulfed and Harry, Ron and Hermione... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" RIVERBANK -DUSK  "> ... tumble INTO VIEW and roll to their
                feet, barely visible in the darkness. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> That treacherous old bleeder! Is there no one we can trust! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>softly</stage> They’ve kidnapped Luna because he supported me. He was just
                desperate. <stage> Ron says nothing, then SPITS, clearing the grit from his teeth
                    and peers toward the river. Unlike the raging force it was the last time they
                    were here, it is littl emore than a trickle now. The trees are eerily quiet.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I’ll do the enchantments. <stage> Ron takes out his wand... when
                    Hermione raises her hand, stopping him. Her eyes rise. Her breath catches. Ron
                    and Harry look. Clinging to the branches of the trees above, almost as if a part
                    of the trees themselves, are... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SNATCHERS."> A wand BLOOMS above, illuminates the face of Scabior. Hermione’s
                red scarf, now faded and filthy, dangles from his neck. He presses it to his grimy
                nose, inhales andGRINS. </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> Hello, beautiful. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FOREST -DUSK (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Harry, Ron and Hermione DASH
                through the trees. As they diverge, we CUT BACK AND FORTH BETWEEN THE THREE:
                Hermione, swift as the wind, flickers through the trees as Scabior pursues her.
                Harry slashes through the river, looks up, and sees aSnatcher leap across the divide
                from one tree to another. Ron pounds through thick brush, over a fallen tree. The
                forest grows more dense, the shadows thicken. Spells splinter through the trees,
                ropes of light lace the night. Hermione stumbles, regains her footing, finds herself
                in a clearing. Another figure pelts toward her: Harry. They freeze briefly, then the
                clearing explodes with light as spells ricochet. They hit the ground. Hear the
                Snatchers closing in. Harry looks to Hermione. The TIP of her WAND GLOWS and her
                face blooms in the darkness, looking mildly demonic. She reaches out, STRIPS HIS
                GLASSES FROM HIS FACE, then points her wand... at him. A BURST of WHITE LIGHT
                strikes him in the eyes. As her wand goes dark... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FORTRESS - NIGHT  "> ... he is flying toward a fortress,
                gliding around the high walls, up to the topmost window of the highest tower. He
                passes through the window -- little more than a slit -- and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CELL - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT  "> ... finds a SKELETAL
                FIGURE lying beneath a ragged blanket. The figure stirs, looks up, and grins with
                broken teeth. It is the young man -- the thief -- grown old. Grindelwald. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRINDELWALD"> Ah, Tom, I thought you would come one day. But surely you must
                knowI no longer have what you seek... </sp>
            <stage>A SHADOW -- Voldemort’s -- falls across Grindelwald. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> If not you, then who? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRINDELWALD"> You’re so innocent, Tom. Like a schoolboy. There’s so much you
                don’t understand... </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Tell me, Grindelwald. Tell me where to find it! Tell me who
                possesses it! The name, Grindelwald! The name! </sp>
            <sp who="#GRINDELWALD"> Can’t you guess, Tom? It lies with him, of course. Buried within
                the earth. It is he who possesses it, even in death. Your old friend and
                mine...Dumbledore. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" FOREST -DUSK  "> Harry blinks and IN A (SWOLLEN) BLUR peers at
                Hermione, WHISPERS QUICKLY: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> They exist. The Hallows. <stage> Hermione looks at him expectantly. He
                    nods, his FACE SHROUDED IN SHADOW, BARELY VISIBLE. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But he only wants the one, the last one. That’s what he’s been looking
                for. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What’re you saying? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He knows where it is, You-Know- Who. He’ll have it by the end of the
                night. He’s found the Elder Wand. <stage> As Hermione stares in stunned disbelief,
                    figures emerge from the trees. Ron is shoved to the ground next to them. Scabior
                    strips Harry and Hermione of their wands. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Don’t touch her! <stage> A fist hits Ron hard. It’s GREYBACK.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Stop it! </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> Your boyfriend’ll get worse than that if he doesn’t behave, lovely.
                    <stage> Scabior paints her face with light then casts it onHarry. Harry peers
                    up, his eyes SWOLLEN to slits, his face HORRIBLY MISSHAPEN. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> What happened to you, ugly? <stage> Harry’s hand finds his face,
                    feels the lumps. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> What’s your name? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dudley. Vernon Dudley. </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> Check the list. And you, ginger? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Stan Shunpike. </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> Like ‘ell you are. We know skinnyStan. Try again. <stage> Greyback,
                    his boot to Ron’s neck, presses harder. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Weasley... <stage>making it up</stage> Barney Weasley. </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> Weasley, eh? Wouldn’t be related to that blood traitor Arthur
                Weasley, would you? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Piss off! Arthur Weasley’s ten times the wizard you are! </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> Worth ten times you if I can find him. Wasn’t you that tipped him
                off, was it? <stage> Ron stays mute. Scabior turns to Hermione. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> How ‘bout you, lovely? What do they call you...? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Penelope Clearwater. Half-blood. <stage> Scabior strokes the nape
                    of Hermione’s neck, then takes her hair in hand, sniffs it. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> You smell like vanilla, Penelope. I think you’re going to be my
                favorite. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNATCHER"> There’s no Vernon Dudley on ‘ere. <stage> Reluctantly, Scabior
                    turns from Hermione to Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FENRIRGREYBACK"> Hear that, ugly? The list says you’re lying. How come you
                don’t want us to know who you are? Hm? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The list is wrong. I told you who I am --<stage> Scabior puts a finger
                    to his lips, silencing Harry, his wand probing Harry’s face more closely.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> Change of plans, boys. We won’t be taking this lot to the Ministry.
            </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" NIGHT SKY - NIGHT  "> The sea of treetops shift eerily below as
                we sweep over them. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" MALFOY MANOR - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)  "> Scabior and the others
                escort Harry, Ron and Hermione past the yew hedges. Hermione eyes the white peacock,
                looking like a ghostly lawn ornament. Harry WHISPERS: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What did you put on me? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> A Stinging Jinx. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How long will it last? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Not long. <stage> Harry glances down, sees his GLASSES cupped in
                    Hermione’s palm. As he slips them into his pocket, the group suddenly slows. Up
                    ahead, on the other side of the gate, BELLATRIX, LUCIUS and NARCISSA approach.
                    Scabior grabs Harry’s arm, pushes his face up to the iron bars. Bellatrix steps
                    close. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Show me.</sp>

            <stage>Scabior reaches out and pushes Harry’s hair off his forehead. Bellatrix points
                her wand, illuminating the skin. Slowly, she smiles. Despite the swelling, one
                intriguing feature can be seen. A SCAR. In the shape of a LIGHTNING BOLT? We HOLD,
                then...CUT TO BLACK. THE END </stage>
        </scene>
    </script>
</xml>
