<?xml-model href="potterScripts.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
    <header>
        <!--metadata in here -->
        <title>HARRY POTTER AND THE DEATHLY HALLOWS - PART 2</title>
        <screenWriter>Steve Kloves</screenWriter>
        <productionStart date="2009-09-09"/>
        <!--Optional: if available. -->
        <release date="2010-12-14"/>
        <!--Look this up and verify -->
        <digitalProject>
            <editor who="#bca">Bianka Alexander</editor>
            <advisor who="#ebb">Elisa Beshero-Bondar</advisor>
            <span from="2020-10" to="2021-05"/>
            <desc>.....</desc>
            <sourceText>
                <siteName>.....</siteName>
                <link><!--Website URL --></link>
                <dateRetrieved>yyyy-mm-dd</dateRetrieved>
            </sourceText>
        </digitalProject>
    </header>
    <script>
        
        <scene>
            <stage>FADE IN: Out of SHIFTING DARKNESS... ... the WARNER BROS. LOGO surfaces... ... then
                VANISHES... swallowed by the shifting darkness once more. Slowly we discern that the
                darkness has form, surface. There is a sense of movement as we realize we...</stage>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="DARK WATER - NIGHT"> ... are RUSHING wicked fast over dark
                water, hastened by a STIFF WIND. Below, a SHADOW flickers intermittently on the
                water’s surface but it is too dark and the surface too uncertain for the shadow to
                be identified. We RISE SLIGHTLY, the VIEW EXPANDING until a SMALL ISLAND comes INTO
                VIEW. We CIRCLE SLOWLY. All is dark below. The WIND SCREAMS. Then something
                GLIMMERS, something PALE and SMOOTH, an OBELISK crafted of MARBLE. We DROP FROM the
                sky, as if on wings. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="ISLAND -CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> The obelisk looms larger
                from this vantage point. A tomb fit for an emperor. A NAME is inscribed upon its
                surface: ALBUS DUMBLEDORE. The obelisk begins to TREMBLE, then DRIFTS SLOWLY ASIDE,
                revealing a TRANSLUCENT STONE SLAB, beyond which a BODY in REPOSE can be discerned.
                SMASH! The translucent slab SHATTERS. The air glimmers briefly with diamond-like
                shards and Dumbledore’s body is revealed. He appears to be sleeping. A few of the
                diamond shards cling to his cheek. A SHADOW -- the shadow from before -- eclipses
                his face and... ... VOLDEMORT appears, peering down at Dumbledore’s lifeless body.
                For a moment, he simply stares, transfixed by the sight of his old foe at peace.
                Then he reaches out and... ... covers Dumbledore’s interlaced hands with his own.
                The moment is oddly tender. After a moment, he retracts his hand, claiming the WAND
                clutched in Dumbledore’s fingers as his own. He studies it, his face a mask. The
                wind rises yet again, carrying us AWAY, BACK TO... ... the darkness of the water.
                TITLE CARD: HARRY POTTER AND THE DEATHLY HALLOWS</stage>
            <stage>A LAKE COMES INTO VIEW, the BLACK LAKE of HOGWARTS, its surface thick and still
                as tar, shrouded in what appears to be a FOUL MIST but which is, we come to find, in
                reality a festering cluster of DEMENTORS... The Quidditch Pitch stands silent,
                untended, faded House flags hanging limply... Under the slate sky, the CASTLE stands
                like a dark fortress, its quirky angles and gleaming windows diminished in the gray
                light... FIGURES COME INTO VIEW, STUDENTS, marching in lines, like GRIM REGIMENTS,
                across the BRIDGE, chivvied on by a pair of DEATH EATERS (ALECTO and AMYCUS CARROW)
                while high upon a ballustrade, his face a mask, SEVERUS SNAPE looks on. We DRAW
                CLOSER, but nothing more is revealed. His face remains a mask, his eyes untelling.
                Finally, he turns away, his CLOAK wiping our field, pitching us once more into...
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="NIGHT SKY - NIGHT"> DARKNESS. The STATIC, little more than a
                feeble hiss now, dies out altogether. A SOFT WHISPER of WIND fills our ears, faint
                but clear, and we are MOVING once more, UP HIGH yet again. The earth falls away
                below us, revealing... A sea of treetops, shifting eerily as we SWEEP OVER them. A
                gravel road COMES INTO VIEW, and then, a few yards on, FIGURES on foot. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="MALFOY MANOR - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> SCABIOR, FENRIR GREYBACK
                and a ragtag group of SNATCHERS escort HARRY, RON and HERMIONE past thick yew
                hedges. Hermione eyes a white peacock, looking like a ghostly lawn ornament. Harry,
                his face horribly swollen, WHISPERS: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What did you put on me? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> A Stinging Jinx. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How long will it last? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Not long. </sp>
            <stage>Harry glances down, sees his GLASSES cupped in Hermione’s palm. As he slips them
                into his pocket, the group suddenly slows. Up ahead, on the other side of the gate,
                BELLATRIX, LUCIUS and NARCISSA approach. Scabior grabsHarry’s arm, pushes his face
                up to the iron bars. Bellatrix steps close. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Show me. </sp>
            <stage>Scabior reaches out his DIRTY FINGERS and pushes Harry’s hair roughly off his
                forehead. Bellatrix SHINES her wand. Despite the swelling, one intriguing feature
                can be seen: a SCAR, in the shape of a LIGHTNING BOLT? Bellatrix studies it long and
                hard... then SMILES. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="ENTRANCE HALL - NIGHT (SECONDS LATER"> As Bellatrix leads the
                procession inside, she speaks to Narcissa. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Get Draco. </sp>
            <stage>Narcissa eyes her sister briefly, warily, then strides off, toward the
                brightly-lit room ahead, where her husband Lucius stands, cradling a nearly-empty
                wine glass. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> Why Draco? </sp>
            <stage>Narcissa passes her husband without a word. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Just sit back and watch, Lucius. Hm? Pour yourself another glass
                of wine. </sp>
            <stage>As she passes, she flicks her finger off the rim of his glass -- pling! </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MAIN ROOM -SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Bellatrix turns, eyeing Harry,
                Ron and Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Where’d you find them? </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> In the North Forest. </sp>
            <stage>WORMTAIL quietly enters the room. As Harry eyes him, Bellatrix pauses, studying
                his scar again. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Lovely scarf, Scabior. Though I’m not sure it’s your color. </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> It’s not mine. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> You don’t say. </sp>
            <stage>Her eyes slide, catch him looking at Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Fancy her, do you, Scabior? Can’t say I blame you. Maybe we’ll
                workout a little reward for you, hm? That is, assuming all is as it appears. Ah,
                Draco. Come here, darling. </sp>
            <stage>From the shadows at the far end of the room Draco separates from Narcissa, steps
                cautiously forward. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> My friends here say they’ve got Harry Potter. Seeing as he’s an
                old school chum of yours, I thought you could confirm the fact for us. </sp>
            <stage>Draco stares at Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Well...? </sp>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> I can’t... I can’t be sure. </sp>
            <stage>Lucius steps forward, wine glass sloshing. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> Look close, Draco. If we’re the ones who hand Potter over to the Dark
                Lord, everything will be forgiven. Do you understand -</sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"><stage>quietly menacing</stage> Now, we won’t be forgetting who
                actually caught him, I hope, Mr. Malfoy? </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Of course not. <stage>eyes hardening</stage> Narcissa. Tend to
                your husband. Lucius staggers back nervously next to his wife. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX">
                <stage>to Draco</stage> Don’t be shy, sweetheart. Get up nice and close.</sp>
            <stage>Bellatrix nudges Draco forward until he’s only inches from Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> What’s wrong with his face? </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> What is wrong with his face, Scabior? </sp>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> He came to us that way. I reckon he picked it up in the forest. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Or ran into a Stinging Jinx. </sp>
            <stage>Bellatrix, eyes flashing, steps up close to Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Was it you, dearie? Give me her wand. We’ll see what the last
                spell was. </sp>
            <stage>Hermione looks alarmed as a Snatcher steps forward. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> What is that? </sp>
            <stage>Bellatrix’s tone is quietly murderous. She pushes past Scabior and Greyback,
                steps before another Snatcher. Hermione’s beaded purse dangles from one hand. In the
                other, he holds... the Sword of Gryffindor. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Where did you get that! </sp>
            <sp who="#SNATCHER"> It was in her bag when we searched her. Reckon it’s mine now. </sp>
            <stage>Bang! Quick as lightning, Bellatrix stuns the Snatcher and catches the sword as
                he drops. Scabior wheels. </stage>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> Are you mad! </sp>
            <stage>Bang! Bellatrix drops him to his knees before his wand escapes his cloak. He
                BELLOWS in fury. </stage>
            <sp who="#SCABIOR"> How dare you! Release me, woman! </sp>
            <stage>Bellatrix stares at him, eyes full of fire, then flicks her wand and he slumps
                forward, wincing. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Go. GO! </sp>
            <stage>Scabior eyes her resentfully, then exits with Greyback and the others. Bellatrix
                turns. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Wormtail. Put these two in the cellar. I want to have a little
                conversation with this one. Girl to girl. </sp>
            <stage>As Wormtail jerks them away, Ron’s eyes flash with panic, meet Hermione’s. She
                mouths: “It’s okay.” </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CELLAR -CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Wormtail prods Harry and Ron
                down a steep flight of stairs, SLAMS the door. Ron throws himself against it, turns
                to Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Harry! What’re we going to do? We can’t just leave Hermione alone with
                her! </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Ron? Harry...? </sp>
            <stage>Harry peers into the small, shadowy space below, senses movement. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Luna...? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MAIN ROOM -SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Bellatrix twirls a SILVER DAGGER
                in her fingers. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> This sword is meant to be in my vault at Gringotts. How did you
                get it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I don’t know what you’re talking about.</sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Liar. What else did you take? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CELLAR - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> CLICK! -- Ron, Deluminator in hand,
                sends a BALL of LIGHT across the darkness and a GASLIGHT BLOOMS faintly. Luna’s pale
                face floats forward, hovers vaguely. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> You look strange, Harry. Mr. Ollivander, look who’s here. It’s Harry
                Potter.</sp>
            <stage>Harry looks past Luna and sees a GOBLIN (GRIPHOOK) standing in the shadows. Next
                to him, sitting slumped against the wall, is the wandmaker OLLIVANDER, looking
                frail. His chin lifts slightly, runny eyes glimmering against the light as he
                studies Harry’s swollen face. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hello, sir. </sp>
            <stage>Ollivander falters, his face troubled. Harry eyes him curiously, when Bellatrix’s
                voice ECHOES through the VENT.</stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX "><stage>O.S.</stage> I’m going to ask you once again: what else did
                you and your friends take from my vault! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE "><stage>O.S.</stage> I told you. I don’t know what you’re talking
                -Hermione SCREAMS in pain. wall, turns. Ron slams his fist against the </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> We have to do something, Harry! </sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> There’s no way out. We’ve tried everything. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> You’re bleeding, Harry. </sp>
            <stage>She points downward. Harry removes his glasses from his pocket, slips them on and
                peers at his sock, where BLOOD has soaked through. Harry reaches down, pulling the
                sock away from his ankle, revealing a SMALL GASH and the thing that caused it: the
                MIRROR SHARD. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> That’s a curious thing to hide in your sock. </sp>
            <stage>Taking the shard, Harry turns the silvery side toward himself (and only himself)
                -- and for a split second -- the EYE seems to flicker there again. Harry wipes away
                the film of blood... but the eye is gone. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> You were hiding it, weren’t you? </sp>
            <stage>Before Harry can respond, Hermione SCREAMS again. Pained by this, Harry debates
                something, then peers into the mirror: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Help us. </sp>
            <stage>The others study him curiously, then FOOTSTEPS SOUND. Ron CLICKS the Deluminator
                and all goes DARK. The cellar door squeals open and Wormtail’s silhouette appears in
                a shaft of light. Ron rushes forward, but Wormtail stops him with a gesture of his
                wand. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Let her go! Let her go! </sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> Shut it! You. Goblin. Come with me. </sp>
            <stage>As Griphook mounts the stairs he turns, eyeing Harry curiously, then Wormtail
                grabs his arm, slams shut the door. Ron clicks the Deluminator again and -- CRACK!
                -- as light returns... DOBBY materializes before them. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dobby. What’re you doing here? </sp>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby has come to rescue HarryPotter, of course. </sp>
            <stage>Everyone stares, stunned. Harry stares in similar amazement at the mirror
                glittering in his palm. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Do you mean to say you can Apparate in and out of here? And take us
                with you? </sp>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Of course. I’m an elf. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Works for me. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Right. Dobby, I want you to takeLuna and Mr. Ollivander to -</sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Shell Cottage on the outskirts of Tinworth. <stage>as Harry looks at
                    him</stage> Trust me. <stage>Harry nods, turns to Luna.</stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’ll see to Mr. Ollivander? </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Of course. <stage>to Dobby</stage> Whenever you’re ready, sir.</sp>
            <stage>Dobby blinks at Luna’s use of “sir.” He GRINS. </stage>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Like her very much. <stage>to Ron and Harry</stage> Meet me at the top
                of the stairs in ten seconds.</sp>
            <stage>Luna takes Ollivander’s withered hand in hers and Dobby reaches out. CRACK! --
                they vanish. Harry and Ron peer at each other, then rush up the stairs toward the
                SLIVER of LIGHT under the door above. CRACK! The knob turns and light splashes into
                the cellar as... ... Wormtail fills the doorway. Harry and Ron stiffen, then watch
                Wormtail fall forward, stiff as a board, tumbling in a heavy heap on the cement
                floor below. They turn back as Dobby appears, Wormtail’s wand in his tiny
                fist.</stage>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Who gets his wand? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR TO MAIN ROOM - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Quickly,
                cautiously, Harry and Ron (brandishing Wormtail’s wand now) pad toward the main room
                as Dobby slips off in another direction. As Ron steps past the lifeless Snatcher
                without a glance, Harry hesitates, glances down. Something FLUTTERS WEAKLY in the
                Snatcher’s pocket. The tip of a golden wing. Harry crouches, looks. It’s the Snitch. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Sss.</sp>
            <stage>Harry looks up, sees Ron gesturing for him. Quickly, he takes the Snitch, slips
                it in his pocket. </stage>
            <stage> NEW ANGLE As Harry joins Ron and looks: Slowly, Bellatrix comes INTO VIEW,
                towering over Griphook, who holds the sword, studying it. Hermione lies at
                Bellatrix’s feet. Seeing her, Ron starts to lurch forward. Harry restrains him. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Well? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> I left Gringotts employ many weeks ago, but when I was last in your
                vault, the sword was there. </sp>
            <stage>Hermione studies the two then watches as a STRAND of BELLATRIX’S HAIR drifts free
                and, as if in a dream, floats through the air... </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Perhaps it just walked out on its own then. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> There is no place safer than Gringotts, Madam LeStrange. </sp>
            <stage>... and catches on Hermione’s shirt. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Liar! You can’t deceive me! </sp>
            <stage>As Hermione looks up, away from the hair, Bellatrix slashes the dagger across
                Griphook’s cheek and a deep gash opens. He barely flinches, the hint of a SMILE on
                his lips. Bellatrix looks mildly unnerved by his reaction. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Consider yourself lucky, Goblin. The same won’t be said for this
                one. </sp>
            <stage>Bellatrix poises the dagger over Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Like hell! </sp>
            <stage>Bellatrix wheels, sees Ron pelting forward. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Expelliarmus! </sp>
            <stage>Bellatrix’s dangling wand shoots free, tumbles end over end... right into Harry’s
                hand. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Stupefy! </sp>
            <stage>Lucius Malfoy drops instantly, his wine glass shattering in a burgundy bloom on
                the hearth. Narcissa and Draco draw their wands. JETS of LIGHT spray across the
                room. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Stop or she dies! </sp>
            <stage>Harry and Ron freeze, see Hermione leaning limply against Bellatrix, the dagger
                at her throat. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Drop your wands. Ron stands rigidly, staring balefully at
                Bellatrix. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> I said drop them! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>angrily</stage> All right!</sp>
            <stage>Ron flings away Wormtail’s wand. Harry drops Bellatrix’s. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Pick them up, Draco. Now! Well, well, look what we have here.
                Harry Potter. All bright, shiny and new again. Just in time for the Dark Lord. </sp>
            <stage>Harry glances in the mirror opposite, sees that the Stinging Jinx is wearing off. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Call him, Draco.</sp>
            <stage>Draco hesitates. But Lucius doesn’t, pulling up his sleeve and touching his
                finger to the DARK MARK on his forearm. Harry’s SCAR CONSTRICTS and he GRIMACES in
                agony. Bellatrix CACKLES maniacally, her knife pressed against the tender flesh of
                Hermione’s neck. A bead of blood bubbles on the blade and then... a GRINDING NOISE
                is HEARD. Harry glances up, sees the CHANDELIER begin to TREMBLE. As the TINKLE of
                GLASS fills the room, Bellatrix stares directly upward, watching as... ... the
                chandelier bursts free of the ceiling and plummets. Bellatrix bolts and Hermione
                staggers clear, falling into Ron’s arms. Griphook grabs the sword and as GLASS
                EXPLODES in razor-sharp slivers, Draco screams and covers his bloody face. Harry
                wrests the blood-soaked wands from his hands and, wheeling, points all three at
                Lucius. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Stupefy! </sp>
            <stage>Lucius flies off his feet and drops in a heap. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> You dirty little monkey! You could have killed me! </sp>
            <stage>Harry turns, sees Bellatrix raging at Dobby. The elf stands fearlessly across
                from her, defiant. </stage>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby meant only to maim or seriously injure, not kill. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> For God’s sake, Cissy, you’ve got a wand! Use it! </sp>
            <stage>Narcissa hesitates. Crack! -- Dobby waves his little fist and Narcissa’s wand
                flies from her hand. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> How dare you take a witch’s wand. How dare you defy your masters. </sp>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Dobby has no master! Dobby is a free elf, and Dobby has come to save
                Harry Potter and his friends! </sp>
            <stage>Harry tosses Ron a wand, grabs Hermione’s beaded bag and joins the others in the
                center of the room. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Give the Dark Lord our regards.</sp>
            <stage>Harry’s hand closes on Dobby’s and the drawing room begins to SPIN. Bellatrix’s
                face twists into an ugly blur. Her arm rises, dagger in hand. There is a flash of
                SILVER. Then... All goes BLACK. For a long time. Then... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="CLIFF - SHELL COTTAGE - DAWN (SECONDS LATER"> ... with a great
                WHOOSH, Harry and the others tumble onto solid earth and hear the CRASH of WAVES. As
                Harry staggers to his feet, stars whirl above him. He sees he is on a cliff
                overlooking a dark sea. Ron holds Hermione gently. Tears sting her eyes. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s all right, Hermione. You’re safe. We’re all safe. </sp>
            <stage>She doesn’t respond, nor Ron. Then Harry realizes they are looking past him, even
                Griphook, the sword hanging limply in his hand. Harry turns. Dobby stands alone, a
                queer smile on his face, hand over his heart, the hilt of Bellatrix’s dagger
                protruding between his fingers. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dobby... no... </sp>
            <stage>As Harry rushes to him, the elf crumples in his arms, his eyes rolling up to the
                stars. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s okay... Here... Just hold on, Dobby... I’ll fix you -- Hermione--
                your bag --you must have something -- Essence of Dittany -- something... Hermione!
                Help me! </sp>
            <stage>She merely stands, tears streaking her cheeks. </stage>
            <sp who="#DOBBY"> Such a beautiful night... to be with friends. Dobby is happy... to be
                with his friend... Harry Potter...</sp>
            <stage>Dobby gives a little shudder, then goes still. The others simply stare, mute,
                listening to the waves thunder. Footfalls sound. Ron turns, sees his brother Bill
                and Luna approaching from the cottage in the distance. </stage>
            <sp who="#BILL"> Fleur’s seeing to Ollivander. Anyone else need tending -</sp>
            <stage>He eyes Harry curiously, crouched, his back turned. Then sees Dobby’s limp little
                legs dangling lifelessly. As the others watch, Harry reaches out and --gently as he
                can -- pulls the dagger from Dobby’s chest, then shrugs off his jacket and enwraps
                the elf’s body. Slowly, his shoulders begin to shake. Only Luna dares to step
                forward. Kneeling, she sees Harry is silently crying. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> We should close his eyes. Don’t you think? </sp>
            <stage>Luna reaches out, tenderly places her fingers upon Dobby’s eyelids and closes
                them. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> There. Now he could be sleeping. </sp>
            <stage>She turns then, looks at Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Harry. It’s all right. That it hurts. That’s what reminds us how lucky
                we are to be alive. </sp>
            <stage>Harry turns, studies her serene face briefly, then his eyes shift to Dobby, his
                face serene as well, in death. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I want to bury him properly. Without magic. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="SHELL COTTAGE - DAY (MORNING)"> A SPADE pierces the earth as
                Harry begins to dig, fiercely obsessed by his task. A moment later, Ron kneels
                beside him and begins to do the same, then Hermione. CAMERA RISES and the THUNDERING
                OCEAN comes INTO VIEW and the lone cottage in the distance... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="SHELL COTTAGE - KITCHEN - SAME TIME - DAY"> As Bill fills a
                kettle, Luna taps the WIND CHIME hanging in the window and a GHOSTLY REFRAIN fills
                the room. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> It’s beautiful here. </sp>
            <sp who="#BILL"> It was our Aunt’s. We used to come here as kids. The Order uses it now
                as a safe house -- what’s left of us, at least. </sp>
            <stage>Luna ponders this, then taps the chime again. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Muggles think these keep evil away. But they’re wrong... </sp>
            <stage>Bill studies her curiously. Then Harry appears in the doorway with Ron and
                Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I need to talk to the goblin.</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="SHELL COTTAGE -BEDROOM 2 - DAY (MOMENTS LATER)"> A KNOCK sounds.
                Griphook turns, watches Bill push open the door, step aside for Harry, Ron and
                Hermione. Harry waits for Bill to withdraw. Turns to Griphook.</stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How are you? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Alive. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You probably don’t remember -</sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> -- that I showed you to your vault the first time you visited
                Gringotts? Even amongst goblins, you are famous, Harry Potter. <stage>nodding to the
                    window</stage> You buried the elf. I saw you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> And brought me here. </sp>
            <stage>Griphook studies him curiously. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> You are a very unusual wizard. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Why did you leave Gringotts? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Soon the Death Eaters will control it. That was unacceptable to me. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Then you’re on our side. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> This is a wizard’s war. I take no side. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I need to get inside Gringotts, into one of the vaults. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> It is impossible. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Alone, yes. With you, no. </sp>
            <stage>Griphook stares impassively at him, silent. He glances at the Sword of
                Gryffindor, which stands in the corner. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> How did you come by this sword? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s complicated. Why did Bellatrix Lestrange think it should be in
                her vault at Gringotts? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> It’s complicated. </sp>
            <stage>Harry and the goblin stare at each other, as if testing one another. Finally,
                Harry speaks: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The sword presented itself to us in a moment of need. We didn’t steal
                it. </sp>
            <stage>Griphook nods, pondering this. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> There is a sword in Madam Lestrange’s vault identical to this one,
                but it is a fake. It was placed there this past summer. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And she never suspected? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> The replica is very convincing. Only a goblin would recognize that
                this is the true Sword of Gryffindor. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Who put it there? The fake. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> It was not my place to ask, nor did I desire to. There are more
                than a few curious things in the vaults at Gringotts. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And in Madam Lestrange’s vault as well? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Perhaps. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I have gold. Lots of it. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> I have no interest in gold. Then what?</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The goblin twists the curl at his chin... then his eyes drift once
                again to the sword. Harry starts to respond, but the goblin cuts him off with
                finality. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> That is my price. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"><stage>a beat</stage> All right.</sp>
            <stage>Ron and Hermione look shocked.</stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> I have your word, Harry Potter, that you will give me the Sword of
                Gryffindor if I help you? Griphook extends his hand. Harry reaches out, takes it.
            </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="SHELL COTTAGE - HALLWAY - DAY (MOMENTS LATER"> The trio walk.
                Hermione WHISPERS. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, are you thinking there’s a Horcrux in Bellatrix’s vault? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> She was terrified when she thought we’d been in there. She kept asking
                you what else we’d taken. I’d bet anything there’s a Horcrux there. If we find it,
                we can kill it. And if we kill it, we’re one step closer to killing him. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> And if we find one? How’re we supposed to destroy it if we’ve given
                Griphook the sword? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’m still working on that part. FLEUR exits the room ahead, a
                half-empty bowl in hand. Seeing Harry, she stops, effectively barring the door. </sp>
            <sp who="#FLEUR"> He’s too weak. </sp>
            <stage>Harry stares at her. Resolved. Fleur steps aside.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="SHELL COTTAGE - BEDROOM 1 - SAME TIME - DAY"> Ollivander rolls
                his sunken eyes toward the trio as they enter. Attempts a feeble smile.</stage>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> Forgive me if I don’t get up. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Mr. Ollivander, I need to ask you a few questions. </sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> Anything, m’boy, anything. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Can you identify these, sir? </sp>
            <stage>Harry removes TWO WANDS. Ollivander takes one in hand. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> Walnut and dragon heartstring. Twelve and three quarter inches.
                Unyielding. This belongs to Bellatrix Lestrange. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And this? </sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> Hawthorn. Unicorn hair. Ten inches. Reasonably pliant. This was
                the wand of Draco Malfoy. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Was? Isn’t it still? </sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> Perhaps not -- if you won it from him. I sense its allegiance has
                changed. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You talk about wands like they’ve got feelings. Can think. </sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter. That much has always
                been clear to those of us who have studied wandlore. </sp>
            <stage>Harry nods, pondering the wand that Ollivander returns to him, then speaks: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What do you know about the Deathly Hallows, sir? </sp>
            <stage>Ollivander eyes Harry with surprise. And a hint of fear. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> There are rumored to be three: The Elder Wand, the Resurrection
                Stone and the Invisibility Cloak. It is said that to possess the mall is to make
                oneself the Master of Death. But few truly believe such objects exist -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But you, sir? Do you believe they exist? </sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> I see no reason to put stock in an old wives tale -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’re lying. You know one exists and you told him about it. You told
                him about the Elder Wand and where to go looking for it. </sp>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> He tortured me! Besides, I conveyed only rumors. There’s no
                guarantee he will find it -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He has found it, sir. </sp>
            <stage>Ollivander blinks. Ashen. Stunned. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> That’s all, sir. We’ll leave you to get some rest now. </sp>
            <stage>The trio begins to exit. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> He’s after you, Mr. Potter. If it’s true, what you say, that he
                has the Elder Wand, I’m afraid you really don’t stand a chance. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Then I guess I’ll just have to kill him before he finds me, sir. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="SHELL COTTAGE - PARLOR - NIGHT"> A FIRE CRACKLES. Harry toys
                with the SNITCH Dumbledore bequeathed him. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> You’re sure it’s hers? </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks up, sees Ron turning a STRAND OF HAIR in the firelight. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Positive. </sp>
            <stage>Harry turns to the two wands on the table --the ones he showed Ollivander -- and
                extends the longest to Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I reckon you should take this then. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Can’t I use the other? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You heard Ollivander. It’s Harry’s now. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> But I hate that thing -- that’s the wand that killed Sirius! How
                can I hold it and not feel... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> If I can hold it, you can. </sp>
            <stage>Hermione looks him in the eye, then takes it. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> How will we know what it is when we get in there? After all, a Horcrux
                can be anything. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’ll know. I can’t explain. It’s like... <stage>touching his
                    chest</stage> ... they sing to me.</sp>
            <stage>Hermione and Ron exchange a troubled glance. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> That’s a bit scary. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It is, Harry. Did Dumbledore ever say anything to you, something
                that might explain why -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. I just know. When one’s near. </sp>
            <stage>Hermione and Ron stare at him, silent, when a FLOORBOARD SQUEAKS. They turn,
                watch SHADOWS appear: Bill and Fleur. Fleur hands Hermione a LONG BLACK WOMAN’S
                CLOAK. </stage>
            <sp who="#FLEUR"> This is the closest I could find to what you described, Hermione. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s perfect. Thank you, Fleur. </sp>
            <stage>Fleur lays the cloak in Hermione’s hands, then steps back next to Bill. He
                studies the trio. </stage>
            <sp who="#BILL"> You’re leaving, aren’t you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> In the morning. </sp>
            <sp who="#BILL"> And Griphook? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He’ll be leaving too. </sp>
            <stage>Bill nods, staring off briefly. Then: </stage>
            <sp who="#BILL"> Listen, I don’t know what you’re up to, but I know goblins. If you’ve
                struck any kind of bargain with Griphook, you must be exceptionally careful to live
                up to it. If you don’t... he won’t be forgiving. </sp>
            <stage>The trio sits in silence. Watches Bill withdraw. Harry glances down at his palm
                again, at the Snitch. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="CLIFF - MORNING"> The ocean crashes. Harry crouches by Dobby’s
                fresh grave, which now bears a simple STONE: “Here Lies Dobby, A Free Elf.” Harry
                ponders the mirror shard, turning it from sky to sea when: </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA "><stage>O.S.</stage> The sky has lost a star. Luna’s image skitters
                across the mirror’s surface and Harry looks up, finds her standing there clutching
                as mall TRAVELING BAG, staring at Dobby’s stone. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> My father used to say that when a child died. </sp>
            <stage>She looks up, smiles. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Funny how Mr. Dobby knew exactly where to find us. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah. Funny. Listen, Luna, about your father, I don’t want you to
                think I -</sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> I know you understand why my father did what he did, Harry. That’s why
                we don’t need to talk about it. </sp>
            <stage>She continues to smile. Harry eyes the traveling bag. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hogwarts? </sp>
            <stage>She nods, looks to the sea. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s not the place you left, you know. It’s not the same. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Neither am I. </sp>
            <stage>She gives a little wave, still bearing the trace of a smile, then DISAPPARATES
                and is gone. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON "><stage>O.S.</stage> Always good value. I’ll miss her.</sp>
            <stage>Harry turns, sees
                Ron standing nearby. He has BROWN HAIR. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> What d’you think? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Wouldn’t know you if I didn’t know you. </sp>
            <stage>Ron studies the mirror as Harry turns it over in his palm. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> You want to tell me what that is? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sirius gave it to me. He had a matching piece. He said if I ever
                needed him, all I had to do was look into it. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You mean he could see you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Something like that. I don’t know. He died before I ever got to use
                it. The thing is... </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Go on. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’ll think I’m mental, but more than once, when I’ve looked into it
                -- I think I’ve seen Dumbledore. </sp>
            <stage>As Ron reacts, Harry’s eyes shift. Bellatrix Lestrange and Griphook, clutching
                the sword, approach from the cottage. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell... that’s a sight. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"> Well, how do I look? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Hideous. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"> Oh dear, I missed a spot, didn’tI? Hold still... </sp>
            <stage>Hermione poises her wand tip over the bit of ginger pushing through the brown of
                Ron’s hair. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Couldn’t do anything about that bit in the back that’s always flipping
                up, could you? Dead annoying -</sp>
            <stage>Hermione casts Bellatrix’s malevolent gaze upon him. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Never mind. I’m good. (peering warily at her) That is you in there,
                isn’t it? </sp>
            <stage>Harry eyes Griphook, who is studying the sword. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You can give that to Hermione to </sp>
            <stage>hold, all right, Griphook? Hermione extends the beaded bag. Griphook eyes Harry
                and then, grudgingly, lets the sword drop within. </stage>
            <stage>CLOSEUP - LINKED HANDS - MOMENTS LATER Harry, Ron, Hermione and Griphook stand in
                a tight circle. As Griphook’s hand joins the others --WHOOSH! -- they vanish.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="DIAGON ALLEY - DARK ALLEY - MORNING"> As they reappear, Harry,
                Ron and Griphook fall back into the shadows and Hermione, as Bellatrix, steps to the
                mouth of the alley to see if the coast is clear. A WARLOCK passes. </stage>
            <sp who="#WARLOCK"> Madam Lestrange. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"><stage>cheerily</stage> Good morning. The Warlock eyes her
                oddly, then continues on. As Hermione retreats back into the alley, Griphook emerges
                from the shadows, his voice harsh and mocking. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Good morning? Good morning? You’re Bellatrix Lestrange, not some
                dewy-eyed schoolgirl! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Hey. Easy. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> She gives us away and we might as well use that sword to slit our
                own throats. Understand? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> He’s right. I was being stupid. </sp>
            <stage>Harry pulls the Invisibility Cloak from his coat, tosses it to Ron. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> C’mon. Let’s do it. </sp>
            <stage>A GUST of WIND BLOWS and we SHIFT TO a FADING POSTER of HARRY flapping on the
                brick wall, bearing the caption “UNDESIRABLE NUMBER ONE.” On the wall, in SHADOW, we
                see Griphook clamber onto Harry’s back. As Ron pitches the cloak over them... they
                vanish. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="GRINGOTTS - DAY (MOMENTS LATER"> White. Towering. Hermione and
                Ron mount the steps, enter. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GRINGOTTS - BANKING HALL - DAY"> A vast marble hall. A long
                counter. Goblins perched on high stools. WIZARD GUARDS positioned throughout. As Ron
                and Hermione enter, WIND whistles through the doorway, sends the PAGES of the
                Goblin’s massive ledgers trembling. As the door closes, the room returns to its
                eerie silence. Hermione glances at Ron. He nods and she steps to the long counter,
                where an AGED GOBLIN scribbles in his ledger. </stage>
            <sp who="#AGEDGOBLIN"> Identification. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"> I hardly think that will be </sp>
            <stage>necessary. </stage>
            <sp who="#AGEDGOBLIN"><stage>looking up</stage> Madam Lestrange! Dear me! How may I help
                you today? </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"> I wish to enter my vault. </sp>
            <sp who="#AGEDGOBLIN"> I see. Very well. Excuse me, won’t you?</sp>
            <stage>The goblin slips off his stool, goes to consult with another, even more ancient
                goblin (BOGROD). </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"> I don’t like to be kept waiting.</sp>
            <stage>Hermione’s tone is harsh, authoritative. She turns to Ron, raises an eyebrow. He
                nods, mouths “Well done,” then looks away, eyeing the guards stationed about the
                room. One looks up, meets his gaze. </stage>
            <sp who="#TALLGOBLIN"> Next. </sp>
            <stage>Ron turns, sees the Tall Goblin eyeing him. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"> He’s with me. <stage>with utter disdain</stage> As
                difficult as that may be to imagine.</sp>
            <stage>Ron frowns, takes in the scene again. The SCRATCH of goblin quills seems to grow
                louder. Ron fidgets, eyes the guard again, who is looking at him more closely now.
                Ron runs a finger under his collar, shifts his eyes to the Aged Goblin who continues
                to consult with the one known as Bogrod. Bogrod says something and they both glance
                at Hermione. Then GRIPHOOK’S VOICE HISSES in his ear: </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK "><stage>V.O.</stage> They know! Ron stiffens, turns slightly toward
                the empty spot to his left. WHISPERS: </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What do you mean? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK "><stage>V.O.</stage> They know she’s an imposter! They’ve been
                warned! Ron looks back, watches the two goblins return to Hermione. </sp>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> Madam Lestrange. Would you mind presenting your wand? </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"> And why should I do that? </sp>
            <stage>Just then, the guard across the room begins to walk toward Ron. Ron’s eyes dance.
                He averts his face, WHISPERS: </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Harry, what do we do? Harry...?</sp>
            <stage>No response. Ron extends his hand as casually as he can, finds only empty space.
                We --</stage>
            <stage>CUT TO: ANOTHER ANGLE CAMERA MOVING TOWARDS Hermione, simulating Harry’s movement
                toward her. </stage>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> It’s the bank’s policy. I’m sure you understand, given the current
                climate --</sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX(HERMIONE)"> No, I most certainly do not understand --</sp>
            <stage>Sensing Harry’s presence, she falters, her own voice emerging through
                Bellatrix’s. Bogrod eyes her intensely. </stage>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> I’m afraid I must insist. </sp>
            <stage>As the guard closes on Ron, Ron looks about frantically, reaching for his wand
                when a GUST of WIND fills the Hall, sending the ledgers trembling again. The guard
                approaching Ron shifts his gaze briefly to the entrance, as do the Aged Goblin and
                Bogrod. None see Harry’s hand slip from the cloak, his wand pointed at Bogrod.
                Imperio. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY "><stage>O.S.</stage> The door glides shut. The wind dies. Bogrod
                blinks. </sp>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> Very well, Madam Lestrange. you will follow me. If </sp>
            <sp who="#AGEDGOBLIN"> But... Bogrod, there have been special instructions regarding
                theLestrange vault. </sp>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> I’m fully aware of that. I’m also aware the Lestranges are one of our
                oldest and most respected families. </sp>
            <sp who="#AGEDGOBLIN"> Yes, sir, but our instructions are very specific -BOGROD Let me
                be specific with you, Ricbert. I’ve run this bank for forty-five years, long before
                anyone had even heard of a Death Eater. The day may come that they feel they can run
                this place better than me, but that day has not yet arrived. Am I understood! The
                Aged Goblin hesitates, then nods. Hermione. Bogrod turns to </sp>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> Madam, if you will, I will escort you myself. <stage>to the
                    guard</stage> Teffington, see to that door, will you. The guard glances at Ron,
                then reluctantly heads for the entrance. Ron quickly falls in line behind Hermione
                as Bogrod leads them out of the Hall. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="TUNNEL - DAY (SECONDS LATER"> A cart hurtles through the
                darkness, ferrying the lot of them -- Harry, Ron, Hermione, Griphook and Bogrod --
                down the rickety rails, twisting and turning, sloping ever downward. Harry leans
                toward Griphook, who commandeers the cart. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How long before they come after us? </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Time will tell. </sp>
            <stage>Harry’s eyes meet Griphook’s in the flickering darkness, then Ron’s face appears
                over Harry’s shoulder. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> What’s that? Up ahead. </sp>
            <stage>Ron points. In the distance, directly over the tracks, something SHIMMERS like a
                CURTAIN of WATER. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> I should have known -</sp>
            <stage>Furiously, Griphook starts to throw levers, trying to slow the cart. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What is that, Griphook? </sp>
            <stage>The wheels SCREECH, throwing off SPARKS. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Griphook! What is that! <stage>He doesn’t answer, furiously
                    preoccupied with the cart. Harry turns to Hermione, hoping she has an
                    explanation, but she just shakes her head, staring up ahead as... ... Griphook
                    slumps back, powerless, watching in grim resignation as the cart careens wildly
                    down the rail and PIERCES the shimmering curtain. Instantly, water ENGULFS them
                    with FEROCIOUS POWER. The seats beneath them collapse, flipping downward and...
                    They drop. ... in a cascade of roaring water toward the ground rushing up 30
                    feet below. Hermione SCREAMS something, her wand flashing and one by one... ...
                    they SPLASH DOWN (relatively) gently, (relatively) unscathed. As the water
                    drains away, they peer upward, watching as, ALARMS BLARING, the cart rattles
                    back the way it came. Harry turns to Hermione as she pockets her
                wand.</stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well done. Hey. <stage>studying her</stage> You look like... you.
                Hermione is soaking wet and looks like... Hermione. Ron looks like Ron. Griphook
                nods to the waterfall. </sp>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> The Thief’s Downfall. Washes away all enchantments. Can be deadly. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You don’t say. (as the cart’s alarms </sp>
            <stage>grow faint) Just out of interest... is there any other way out of here? </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> No. </sp>
            <stage>Before the trio can savor this tidbit: </stage>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> What the devil are you all doing down here! </sp>
            <stage>They all turn, seeing a soaking Bogrod, cleansed of the Imperius curse, backing
                away in angry confusion. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> We need him! </sp>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> Is this your doing, Griphook? You have no rights here anymore. When
                you gave up your keys, you -</sp>
            <stage>Hermione and Harry raise their wands. Too late. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Imperio! </sp>
            <stage>Bogrod blinks, resumes his mild demeanor. Harry and Hermione turn, see Ron, wand
                outstretched. Griphook steps past, pushes Bogrod on. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Well done. </sp>
            <stage>The trio watch the goblins go, exchange a glance. Unnerved. Just then a MOAN is
                heard, DEEP and unsettling, coming from down the tunnel. Ron cocks his ear in
                disbelief. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> No. It’s not possible... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="OUTSIDE LESTRANGE VAULT - DAY (MOMENTS LATER"> Ron appears
                first, trailed by Harry and Hermione, and finds Bogrod standing placidly by himself.
                As Harry and Hermione hang back, Ron moves forward slowly, squinting. Something
                massive shifts heavily. CHAINS CLINK. He looks: a GIANT DRAGON tethered to the
                ground, bars access to a DEEP VAULT. Its scales are pale and flaky, its eyes milky. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell. That’s a Welsh </sp>
            <stage>Green. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It looks like it’s been down here forever.</sp>
            <stage>HINGES SQUEAL SHARPLY and they jump, watch Griphook -- in the SHADOWS -- take
                something from a wooden box on the wall. An ODD-LOOKING METAL INSTRUMENT. As he
                steps into the light, he tosses it to Hermione. She glances from it to Griphook,
                sees him eyeing her with a strange intensity. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Go on. </sp>
            <stage>She looks unsure. Then gives it a SHAKE. A SHRILL RINGING echoes off the rocky
                passage, eerie and unpleasant. The dragon rears back instantly, howling in fear,
                then, as the ringing subsides, settles. Ron nods knowingly. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> It’s been trained to expect pain when it hears the noise.</sp>
            <stage>Hermione’s eyes flash to Ron, then to the SCARS on the dragon’s face and neck. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> That’s barbaric. I...</sp>
            <stage>She hands the instrument back, horrified. Griphook takes it, unmoved. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> We’ll only have a few seconds. In other words... they’ll be no
                do-overs. Understood?</sp>
            <stage>The trio eye the dragon, nod. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Ready, Bogrod? </sp>
            <sp who="#BOGROD"> Hm? Oh. Yes. Of course.</sp>
            <stage>Bogrod holds up his hand, waggles it. Griphook nods, eyes the dragon. Its eyes
                glimmer angrily. Griphook raises the instrument... and SHAKES IT. The cacophony is
                murderous. Harry, Ron and Hermione grimace. The dragonROARS hoarsely, then slowly
                retreats. Bogrod strides forth, blissfully ignoring the dragon’s bobbing head and
                presses his hand to the vault’s door. It MELTS. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="LESTRANGE VAULT - DAY"> All rush inside. In the ensuing silence,
                the dragon spits FIRE... just as the vault re-seals itself and all goes DARK.
                HARRY/RON/HERMIONE Lumos! A TRIO of wandtips BLOOM, illuminate a huge vault swimming
                in GLITTERING TREASURE and EERIE ARTIFACTS. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Blimey... </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Look.</sp>
            <stage>Hermione crosses to what appears to be the Sword of Gryffindor. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No wonder Bellatrix thought it was real.</sp>
            <stage>Harry pays no attention, having drifted away from the others, playing his
                WANDLIGHT over the glittering walls. The others notice and go silent, watching.
                Griphook eyes Harry with particular curiosity. Finally, Ron speaks. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Is it here, Harry? Can you feel anything?</sp>
            <stage>Harry doesn’t respond, his wandlight continuing to travel over the small
                treasures above. Gradually, a HUM rises in his ears and he closes his eyes. As
                Hermione watches, transfixed, the CAMERA TRAVELS DOWN her arm TO her hand, which
                dangles nary a quarter inch from the lip of a SILVER BOWL perched on the edge of the
                table beside her. The HUM in Harry’s ears grows LOUDER and his wand hand begins to
                TWITCH. The BEAM of LIGHT TREMBLES over the objects nestled nearest the ceiling,
                then settles on an ANCIENT CUP, bearing the HUFFLEPUFF CREST. Harry’s SCAR
                CONTRACTS. He opens his eyes... The skin of Hermione’s wrist BRUSHES the LIP of the
                BOWL... Harry stares at the ANCIENT CUP above, glimmering dully in the light of his
                wand when... Hermione YELPS. As the others turn, they see her retract her hand, as
                if stung, sending the SILVER BOWL tumbling to the floor. She holds up her wrist --
                displays a RED WELT. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It’s hot!</sp>
            <stage>All eyes turn to the bowl, WOBBLING MADLY on the floor, when... it SPLITS APART
                and begins to MULTIPLY. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> They’ve added Gemino and Flagrante Curses! Everything you touch
                will burn and multiply!</sp>
            <stage>The multiplying bowls skitter across the floor and flip into the air. As one
                caroms off Ron’s shoe, it bursts into twenty more. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron, your foot!</sp>
            <stage>It’s SMOKING. As Ron stamps the ground, Harry pivots, tipping a towering STACK of
                GALLEONS to the floor where they multiply like cockroaches. Instantly, the room is a
                RIOT of multiplying white-hot metal. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> We’ll be crushed! Hurry! </sp>
            <stage>Harry points his wand once again at the small cup near the ceiling. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> That’s it. Up there. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> How’re we going to reach it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Give me the sword! The real one.</sp>
            <stage>Hermione reaches into her beaded bag, tosses it to Harry, who catches it by the
                hilt. Griphook’s eyes glitter greedily at the sight of it. Instantly, Harry begins
                to scale the multiplying mountain of objects, climbing towards the cup. As the
                sizzling surface shifts beneath his feet he moves upward, beads of sweat trailing
                over his forehead. Suddenly, halfway up, he SLIPS and -- instinctively -- to keep
                from falling, he reaches out and plants the flesh of his palm against the shifting
                slope. Instantly, OBJECTS EXPLODE FORTH, MULTIPLYING CRAZILY and CASCADING down onto
                Ron, Hermione and Griphook in a small avalanche. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Keep going!</sp>
            <stage>Harry climbs faster -- the sound DEAFENING, objectsCLANGING off one another --
                until, finally, he stops just shy of the ceiling. Reaching out, he extends his arm
                -- further, then further still -- and slips the sword’s tip through the cup’s
                handle. As it shimmies down the blade, a SCREAM RISES. Harry looks down, sees a
                terrified Bogrod pinned against the door, watching as Griphook sinks beneath the
                rising tide. Ron dashes forward, grabs Griphook’s fingers as he’s about to go under
                and yanks the blistered Goblin free. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry! Behind you!</sp>
            <stage>Harry turns and sees the swelling mountain has reached the ceiling and -- with
                nowhere else to go -- is about to spill itself down upon him. Turning back... Harry
                leaps. He plummets, feet first, soaring through the air, then crashes down on the
                swelling treasure. The sword -- and cup -- fly free. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> The cup!</sp>
            <stage>Harry dives into the scalding treasure, hand outstretched, and catches it.
                Instantly, DOZENS of Hufflepuff Cups burst from his fist, but he holds tight to the
                original, grimacing in pain. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> In here!</sp>
            <stage>Hermione holds her beaded bag before Harry and he jams it inside. As they turn
                for the door, they stop. Griphook holds the sword, the real sword, in his hands,
                turning the blade in the light. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We have a deal, Griphook.</sp>
            <stage>Griphook looks up. A kind of madness burns in his eyes. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> I said I’d get you in. I never said anything about getting you
                out.</sp>
            <stage>Pivoting swiftly, he SLAMS Bogrod’s hand to the door and as it melts, Harry, Ron
                and Hermione ride an avalanche of silver and gold into the outer chamber. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="OUTSIDE LESTRANGE VAULT - DAY"> As the trio find their feet, the
                dragon ROARS and SPITS FIRE, illuminating the tunnel. SHADOWS APPROACH, stretching
                over the tunnel walls: GRINGOTTS GOBLINS and GUARDS. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Griphook! Griphook! </sp>
            <stage>But Griphook merely looks back, grins madly and, sword in hand, rushes to join
                the approaching throng. </stage>
            <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Thieves! Help! Thieves! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Foul little git. Least we’ve got Bogrod. </sp>
            <stage>The dragon SPITS again, reducing Bogrod to dust. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> That’s unfortunate. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We can’t just stand here! Who’s got an idea? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You’re asking us? You’re the brilliant one. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I’ve got something. But it’s mad. </sp>
            <stage>Harry and Ron eye the approaching throng, turn back to Hermione with looks of
                mild panic. Steeling herself, she raises her wand. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Relashio! </sp>
            <stage>The IRON CUFFS on the dragon snap free. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> That’s your idea? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Come on! </sp>
            <stage>Harry fires stunning spells toward the goblins as he pelts toward the dragon and
                flings himself onto its neck. Hermione and Ron jump up behind. The dragon doesn’t
                move. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It doesn’t realize it’s free! (trying out spells) Leviosa! Aviates!
                Ex Cappa! </sp>
            <stage>Nothing. Ron and Harry glance at each other and then -- as if reading each
                other’s mind -- raise their wands high and, as one, JAB the dragon with the tip of
                their wands. It ROARS, rears, and soars into the air. As it caroms off the sides of
                the tunnel and scrapes the ceiling, the trio duck, watching the goblins scatter like
                skittles and dust and debris rain down. Harry looks back, sees the dragon’s SPIKED
                TAIL THRASHING, the tunnel caving. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="TUNNEL - DAY (SECONDS LATER"> A LOW RUMBLE is heard, growing
                louder, then a MASSIVE DUST CLOUD billows forth and... ...the dragon BURSTS INTO
                VIEW. It soars by, wings flapping, eyes blind, gulping fresh air. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GRINGOTTS - DAY (MOMENTS LATER"> The Hall trembles, fissures
                appear and the dragon erupts through the floor. Pillars spill, goblins dive for
                cover. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="DIAGON ALLEY - DAY"> The grand facade of Gringotts disintegrates
                as the dragon penetrates, wheels upward and beats toward the sky. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="OVER LONDON - DAY"> The dragon soars over London, shedding
                scales and debris as the dust-ridden trio hunker low, the cool breeze bathing their
                blistered skin. Ron BELLOWS in delight: </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> That was brilliant! BRILLIANT! </sp>
            <stage>Ron looks down, realizes he’s on a dragon, several hundred feet in the air. Goes
                a bit green. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell.</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GRINGOTTS - BANKING HALL - DAY"> Dust still hangs in the air.
                Those Goblins that survived straggle over the rubble -- and the occasional dead
                colleague -- toward the exits. Among them, a familiar figure emerges... Griphook.
                Clutching the sword of Gryffindor, he bumps past his dazed brethren, taking an
                agitated glance over his shoulder as he hurries on before turning back round... ...
                and coming to a dead halt before a Death Eater, who raises his wand and points it
                directly between Griphook’s eyes. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="OVER COUNTRYSIDE - AFTERNOON (LATER"> The sun has dropped.
                Below, the dragon’s GIANT SHADOW passes over patches of brown and green.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="OVER MOUNTAINS/LAKES - LATE DAY (LATER)"> The trio shiver as
                they cling to the dragon. Harry slides a few inches. He peers up, past the beast’s
                head. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We’re dropping! The dragon circles, lower and lower. A lake shimmers. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I say we jump! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> When? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> NOW! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="LAKE - LATE DAY"> They drop like stones into the water. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="BELOW THE SURFACE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - LATE DAY"> Harry spears
                through, feet first, and we INTERCUT... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MALFOY MANOR - SAME TIME - LATE DAY"> ... Voldemort, in a rage,
                wand slashing the air, as he murders GOBLINS and GUARDS, their bodies falling as...
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="BELOW THE SURFACE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - LATE DAY"> ... Harry’s
                body twists, feet kicking for the surface as... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MALFOY MANOR - CONTINUOUS ACTION - LATE DAY"> ... Nagini
                slithers through the FALLING BODIES, smearing the tiled floor with RED as the AGED
                GOBLIN COUGHS BLOOD and...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="LAKE’S SURFACE - LATE DAY"> ... Harry bobs to the surface,
                COUGHING up water. As his face streams...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MALFOY MANOR - CONTINUOUS ACTION - LATE DAY"> ... blood runs
                into the eyes of the GUARD who had stalked Ron at Gringotts. Lucius, Narcissa and
                Draco survey the carnage in stunned silence, while Bellatrix -- lips parted, eyes
                narrowed -- watches a WIDENING POOL of BLOOD encircle his boot. VOLDEMORT, ELDER
                WAND clutched in his bony hand, speaks in PARSELTONGUE to Nagini: </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> The boy has discovered our secret, Nagini. We must find out just
                how much he knows. We must return to our hiding places and see if the others are
                safe.</sp>
            <stage>A RAPID SUCCESSION OF IMAGES FLASH: Dumbledore’s DESK DRAWER sliding open,
                revealing TOM RIDDLE’S DIARY and a RING with a BLACK STONE; the underground LAKE; an
                OLD WOMAN (HEPZIBAH SMITH) in a PARLOR, her teeth black with age, opening a box to
                reveal Helga Hufflepuff’s CUP; HOGWARTS CASTLE; the FACE of a BEAUTIFUL, SAD-EYED
                WOMAN (HELENA RAVENCLAW) standing with her EQUALLY-BEAUTIFUL MOTHER (ROWENA
                RAVENCLAW); the LESTRANGE’S VAULT at GRINGOTTS; a TARNISHED TIARA, a filagreed
                RAVENCLAW EAGLE among the crown’s detail; HARRY HIMSELF, staring STRAIGHT INTO
                CAMERA, EYES DARK, THE SURFACE OF HIS SKIN TREMBLING LIKE WATER; NAGINI, FANGS
                FLASHING... </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"><stage>to Nagini</stage> And you, my friend, must stay
                close...</sp>
            <stage>As the great snake wends its way around Voldemort’s feet, we see a BLOODY HAND
                gripping the Sword of Gryffindor. It is Griphook, eyes blank, body still. As we
                watch, the sword slowly... VANISHES.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="LAKE’S SURFACE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - LATE DAY"> Harry, face
                ashen, shivers as he watches the dragon, fifty feet up, swoop down, slurp some water
                and fly on. Seconds later, Ron and Hermione break the surface.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="SHORE/LAKE - EVENING"> The trio crashes through the water to the
                shore. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He knows. </sp>
            <stage>Ron and Hermione, both dripping wet, eye Harry. His chest heaves from the swim to
                shore. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"><stage>out of breath</stage> You-Know-Who. He knows we broke into
                Gringotts. He knows what we took. He knows we’re hunting Horcruxes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> How is it you -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I saw him. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You let him in! Harry, you can’t -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I can’t always help it, Hermione! <stage>frowning</stage> Maybe I can.
                I don’t know. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> He’s going to make sure the other </sp>
            <stage>Never mind! What did you see? </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He’s angry. But he’s scared too. </sp>
            <stage>Horcruxes are safe. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> What happens when he finds out four are gone? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I reckon he’ll do anything to stop us from finding the rest. There’s
                more: one of them’s at Hogwarts.</sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE #RON">What? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You saw it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I saw the castle. And Rowena Ravenclaw. I think it must have something
                to do with her. We have to go there, now. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Tonight? But we have to plan. We have to figure out what -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Honestly, Hermione, when have any of our plans actually worked? We
                plan, we get there and all hell breaks loose. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> ‘Fraid he’s right. One problem: Snape’s Headmaster now. We can’t just
                walk in the front door. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We’ll go to Hogsmeade. To Honeydukes. Take the secret passage in the
                cellar. </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks off then, over the lake, in the direction the dragon flew off. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> There’s something wrong with him. In the past, I could always follow
                his thoughts. Now everything feels disconnected. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Maybe it’s because of the Horcruxes. Maybe he’s growing weaker. Maybe
                he’s dying. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. It’s more like he’s wounded. If anything, he feels more dangerous.
            </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HIGH STREET (HOGSMEADE) - NIGHT"> An eerie calm. POSTERS OF
                HARRY -- “UNDESIRABLE NUMBER ONE” -- droop from every light post. SHOPS, shuttered
                at this hour, sit silently, SHROUDED IN A THICK FOG. OnlyTHE THREE BROOMSTICKS
                evidences life, where YELLOW LIGHT and COURSE LAUGHTER drift from greasy windows.
                Just beyond lies Honeydukes. Suddenly, there is a DISTURBANCE in the MIST and the
                trio APPARATE INTO VIEW. They glance about when... A SCREAM rents the air. INHUMAN.
                SHRILL. The laughter dies inside THE THREE BROOMSTICKS, a MOB OF SHADOWS fills the
                windows. Instantly, the trio pelt for Honeydukes. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="STREET (OUTSIDE HONEYDUKES) - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)"> As the
                trio close in on Honeydukes, Death Eaters spill from the Broomsticks. DEATH EATER #
                There! Right there! The trio turn on their heels and vanish into the mist. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="STREET - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)"> Harry leads the way, the trio
                running wicked fast through the twisting streets, glancing down alleyways for signs
                of pursuers, the mist both friend and foe. Suddenly, aDARK FIGURE appears on the
                roof above. He WHISTLES. DEATH EATER # I’ve got them! Down here!! </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="SIDE STREET - NIGHT (SECONDS LATER)"> Harry, Ron and Hermione
                race down a side street and stumble into an ALCOVE, lungs burning. Hermione
                WHISPERS: </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> They were ready for us.</sp>
            <stage>Suddenly BEAMS of LIGHT fracture the mist.</stage>
            <sp who="#DEATHEATER1">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> We know you’re here, Potter. There’s no getting away.</sp>
            <stage>Harry slips the MIRROR from his pocket and ANGLES it. His own FACE SLIDES BRIEFLY
                over the surface, then the end of the alley comes INTO VIEW. A DEATH EATER stands
                there, wand glowing in the mist.</stage>
            <sp who="#DEATHEATER1">
                <stage>O.S.</stage> Perhaps you need some convincing. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What’s he mean by that?</sp>
            <stage>Hermione GASPS, eyes looking upward. Ron and Harry follow her gaze.</stage>
            <stage>Just above the rooftops, barely distinguishable from the night, DEMENTORS DRIFT
                like smoke. As Harry draws his wand, Hermione’s hand covers his. She WHISPERS: </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No, you’ll give us away.</sp>
            <stage>The night grows darker, the streetlights dim. The trio’s breath drifts visibly in
                the gathering chill. As the Dementors descend, the trio grimace, beset by bleak
                thoughts. A tear escapes Hermione’s eye, trails down her cheek. Finally, Harry can
                take it no more. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Expecto Patronum! <stage>A SILVER STAG bursts from his wand and
                    charges down the street, scattering the Dementors before vanishing around the
                    other side of the HOG’S HEAD INN.</stage>
            </sp>
            <sp who="#DEATHEATER"> It’s him! He’s down there!</sp>
            <stage>FOOTSTEPS clatter on the cobblestones. Harry, Ron and Hermione glance desperately
                about when -- suddenly -- BOLTS GRIND, HINGES SQUALL and a DOOR OPENS. A CAT
                SLITHERS out and a MAN (ABERFORTH) appears in SILHOUETTE, the profile familiar... </stage>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> In here, Potter.</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="HOG’S HEAD INN - NIGHT"> Harry, Ron and Hermione slip quickly
                past the man and inside. He gestures toward a rickety wooden staircase, brings a
                finger to his lips: Shhhh. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="SITTING ROOM - NIGHT"> Harry enters a room with a threadbare
                carpet and a small fireplace, above which hangs a large OIL PAINTING of a BLONDE
                GIRL with a SWEET, but VACANT STARE. He steps to a grimy window and peers down to
                the street, where half a dozen DEATH EATERS glance about in confusion. Just then,
                Hermione and Ron enter the room. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Did you get a look at him! For a second I thought it was -</sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"><stage>mildly shaken by this</stage> I know. Hearing this, Harry
                slips the mirror from his pocket. FOOTSTEPS sound from below. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry! I can see you! In here! </sp>
            <stage>Harry turns, watches Hermione take a JAGGED SHARD similar to his own from the
                mantel. He glances down at the piece in his palm, sees Hermione’s eye looking out at
                him. Just then, Aberforth’s hulking form appears on the landing. </stage>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> You bloody fools! What were you thinking coming here? Do you have
                any idea how dangerous it is --</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’re Aberforth. </sp>
            <stage>The room goes quiet. The man turns, eyes Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dumbledore’s brother. It’s you I’ve been seeing -- here. It’s you who
                sent Dobby. </sp>
            <stage>Harry holds up his shard. Aberforth eyes it briefly. </stage>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> Where’ve you left him? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He’s dead. </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> Sorry to hear it. I liked that elf. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How’d you come by it? </sp>
            <stage>Harry nods to the shard in Hermione’s hand. </stage>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> Mundungus Fletcher, ‘bout a year ago. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dung had no right selling you that. It belonged to -ABERFORTH Sirius.
                Albus told me. He also told me that you’d likely be hacked off if you ever found out
                I had it. But ask yourself whereyou’d be if I didn’t. Harry doesn’t respond. </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> Right then. Reckon you’re hungry. Let’s get you fed, then think of
                the best way to get you out ofhere. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="SITTING ROOM - NIGHT (LATER"> A tray of food is set down on the
                table. RON and HERMIONE set to, they haven’t eaten for days. ABERFORTH pours himself
                a glass of mead. Not his first. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Do you hear much from the others? From the Order? </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> The Order is finished. You-KnowWho’s won. Anyone who says
                otherwise is kidding themselves. The trio exchange glances. HARRY doesn’t touch the
                food, just stares quietly at ABERFORTH. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We need to get into Hogwarts. Dumbledore gave us a job to do. Did he
                now? </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> Nice job? Easy? An awkward silence, the tension heavy. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We’ve been hunting Horcruxes. We think the last one’s in the school.
                But we’ll need your help getting in. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> <stage>CONT'D</stage> If we can find it and kill it, then we kill him,
                and then we can end this war once and for all. We need to get into Hogwarts tonight.
                Aberforth stares at him for a moment, until the silence grows. </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> It’s not a job my brother’s given you, it’s a suicide mission. Do
                yourself a favor boy. Go home. Live a little longer. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dumbledore trusted me, to see this through. </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> What makes you think you can trust him! What makes you think you
                can believe anything my brother told you! In all the time you knew him, did he ever
                mention my name? Did he ever mention hers? </sp>
            <stage>Aberforth gestures to the painting of the girl. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Why should he... </sp>
            <stage>Keep secrets? </stage>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> You tell me. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I only care about the Dumbledore I knew. I trusted him. </sp>
            <stage>Did you now? </stage>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> And why is that? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I had no reason not to - </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> That’s a boy’s answer. A boy who goes chasing Horcruxes on the
                word of a man who won’t even tell him where to start. You’re lying. Not just to me,
                which doesn’t matter, but to yourself as well. That’s what a fool does. You’re
                drunk. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> You don’t strike me as a fool, Mr. Potter. So I’ll ask you again.
                There must be a reason. Why do you trust anything my brother ever said to you? Why? </sp>
            <stage>Harry stands mute, his face at war with itself. For a moment, it’s unclear which
                competing emotion will win out, then -- finally -- he speaks, his voice steady. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Because I need to. Because if I don’t, I don’t know who I am anymore.
                I’ve lost too many people to lie down now. I’m not interested in what happened
                between you and your brother, I don’t even care that you’ve given up. I trust the
                man I knew. I’m going to see this through. <stage>pause</stage> I need to get into
                the castle tonight. Silence. HERMIONE and RON exchange a glance. ABERFORTH regards
                HARRY darkly, but HARRY merely stands, waiting. After several seconds, Aberforth’s
                gaze shifts... to the painting. </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> You know what to do... </sp>
            <stage>The girl smiles, turns, and walks away, growing slowly smaller in the painting
                with each step she takes. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Where’ve you sent her? </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> You’ll see soon enough. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> That’s Ariana, isn’t it? Your sister. She’s beautiful. </sp>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> She’ll always be beautiful.</sp>
            <stage>Ron and Harry glance at each other, confused.</stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> * She died very young, didn’t she.</sp>
            <stage>This hangs.</stage>
            <sp who="#ABERFORTH"> My brother sacrificed many things, Mr. Potter, in his journey to
                find power, including her. She was devoted to him --he gave her everything, but
                time. </sp>
            <stage>Aberforth looks to the empty frame. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Mr. Dumbledore... thank you. </sp>
            <stage>Aberforth stares hard at Hermione, nods curtly, exits. As he disappears Ron looks
                to Hermione to explain her“Thank you.” </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Did save our lives twice. Kept an eye on us in that mirror. That
                doesn’t seem like someone who’s given up, does it? </sp>
            <stage>Ron and Harry exchange a glance, eye the empty doorway. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> She’s coming back! And she’s got someone with her! </sp>
            <stage>Just then, the painting BLOOMS FAINTLY and ARIANA emerges from deep within the
                dark canvas. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Who’s that with her? Bloody hell... </sp>
            <stage>As ARIANA draws closer, the LIMPING FIGURE beside her comes clear: NEVILLE. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> I knew you’d come! I told them all! Harry Potter would never abandon
                Hogwarts! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"><stage>softly</stage> Neville... The GILDED FRAME SWINGS OPEN,
                revealing -- in actuality -- what the painting had replicated. Harry pelts
                forward... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="PASSAGE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> ... into the passageway as
                Neville comes into the light drifting from the sitting room. Long hair. Gashed face.
                Swollen eye. Clothes ripped and torn. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Neville, you look... </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Like hell? I reckon. This is nothing. Seamus is worse. You’ll see.
                Hermione! Ron!</sp>
            <stage>Neville embraces them, then turns to Aberforth.</stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Hey, Ab. There might be a couple more people on the way.</sp>
            <stage>The trio turns, see Aberforth standing in the doorway, watching Ariana drift back
                into the canvas. Neville turns to Harry, Ron and Hermione. Smiles again. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Well? Ready? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="PASSAGE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Neville leads the others down
                the passage. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> I don’t remember this being on the Marauder’s Map. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> That’s because it never existed till now. The seven secret passages
                were sealed off before the start of the year. This is the only way in or out now.
                The grounds are crawling with Death Eaters and Dementors. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> How bad is it, Neville? With Snape as Headmaster. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Hardly ever see him. It’s the Carrows you have to watch out for. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The Carrows? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Brother and sister. They’re in charge of discipline. Like
                punishment, the Carrows. </sp>
            <stage>Neville points to a GASH on his face. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> They did that to you? But why? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Today’s Dark Arts lesson had us practicing the Cruciatus Curse. On
                First Years. I refused. Hogwarts has changed. </sp>
            <stage>The others look shocked. Neville grins. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Aw, c’mon. Don’t be grim. We’re all used to it by now. And the thing
                is, it helps when people stand up, gives everyone hope. I used to notice that when
                you did it, Harry. C’mon, we’re almost there. </sp>
            <stage>The trio exchange glances, follow Neville. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="PASSAGE - NEW ANGLE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Neville leads them
                up a short flight of stone steps to aDOOR, pauses. Looks back. WHISPERS. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Let’s have a bit of fun, shall we? <stage>pushing open the
                    door</stage> Hey! Listen up, you lot! I’ve brought you a surprise! </sp>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS "><stage>O.S.</stage> Not more of Aberforth’s cooking, I hope. Be a
                surprise if we could digest it.</sp>
            <stage>Neville looks back, jerks his head toward the open door. Harry, Ron and Hermione
                step forward, duck through and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="ROOM OF REQUIREMENT - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> ... emerge
                into a large room that looks like a sumptuous tree house. Faces turn. Blink. Utter
                silence. Then... </stage>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> Blimey.</sp>
            <stage>... VOICES EXPLODE. Madness ensues as the trio is swallowed up in a scrum of
                backslaps and handshakes. Many familiar faces are present. Luna. Dean Thomas. CHO
                CHANG. LAVENDER BROWN. Neville leans down, WHISPERS to NIGEL. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Get the word out to Remus and the others that Harry’s back.</sp>
            <stage>Nigel nods, scrambles over to a battered WIZARD WIRELESS. As it CRACKLES to life
                he leans close, SPEAKS. </stage>
            <sp who="#NIGEL"> River, DA calling. Do you read? We have a new weather report:
                Lightning has struck. I repeat, lightning has struck... </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Okay, okay! Stand down! Let’s not kill them before You-Know-Who gets
                the chance! <stage>as they settle</stage> Right then. What’s the plan, Harry? Harry
                gazes out over the expectant faces in the room, noting the hollow eyes and broken
                bodies and the desperate, almost palpable desire for hope. For a moment he seems
                lost, awed by the sacrifice his friends have made, much of it for him. Finally, he
                speaks: </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Okay. There’s something we need to find, something hidden here in the
                castle. It could help us defeat You-Know-Who. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> What is it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We don’t know. </sp>
            <sp who="#DEAN"> Where is it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Don’t know that either. </sp>
            <stage>A confused MURMUR fills the room. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I realize it’s not much to go on. </sp>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> That’s nothing to go on.</sp>
            <stage>Harry falters, then his gaze happens upon the RAVENCLAW BANNER hanging across the
                room, bearing the symbol of an EAGLE. He studies it, a notion forming. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I think it might have something to do with Ravenclaw. It would be
                small, easy to conceal, valuable. Any ideas? </sp>
            <stage>He looks up. For a moment, there’s no response, then: </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Well, there’s Rowena Ravenclaw’s lost diadem. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"><stage>under his breath</stage> Oh, bloody hell. Here we go. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> The lost diadem of Ravenclaw? Hasn’t anyone ever heard of it? It’s
                quite famous. </sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Yes, but Luna, it’s lost. For centuries now. There’s not a person alive
                today who’s seen it. </sp>
            <stage>Her fellow Ravenclaws nod. Ron frowns. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Excuse me. But would someone tell me: what’s a bloody diadem? </sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> It’s a kind of crown. You know, like a tiara. </sp>
            <stage>As she says this, Harry frowns, trying to think if he’s seen such a thing in the
                castle. </stage>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Ravenclaw’s was rumored to have magical properties, to enhance the
                wisdom of the wearer.</sp>
            <stage>Just then QUICK FOOTSTEPS ARE HEARD and a GIRL appears atop the far staircase.
                She stops, staring at Harry. Ginny. </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hey there. </sp>
            <stage>Ron smiles, about to speak, then notices Ginny’s eyes have not left Harry. He
                frowns, speaks to Hermione. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Six months she hasn’t seen me and it’s like I’m Frankie First Year. I
                mean, I’m only her brother. </sp>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> Got loads of those, though, doesn’t she? There’s only one Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Shut up, Seamus. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> What is it, Ginny? </sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Snape knows. He knows that Harry was spotted in Hogsmeade. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - NIGHT (LATER)"> Mist encircles the parapets of
                the castle itself, barely distinguishable from the DEMENTORS that drift like silent
                sentinels over the grounds. LIGHTS GLIMMER in the castle. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="COURTYARD -NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)"> A stream of HUFFLEPUFF
                STUDENTS move toward the Great Hall. They walk grimly, their faces blank, as if
                accustomed to such exercises. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> The Ravenclaws walk in
                lockstep as well. One TINY GIRL (MAISY REYNOLDS) stands out, walking alongside Luna,
                her bearing more defiant than defeated. The DEATH EATER chivvying them along eyes
                her cruelly. </stage>
            <sp who="#ALECTOCARROW"> Put a smile on, Miss Reynolds. Wouldn’t want me to have to pay
                a visit to Daddy again, would you? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="DUNGEON CORRIDOR - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Slytherin House walks in
                rigid synchronization, backs straight, in perfect rhythm. We catch sight of BLAISE
                ZABINI and GOYLE. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> As the Grffindors walk,
                Harry moves in their midst, effectively shielded. Harry slips past a few people,
                reaches out and... enfolds Ginny’s hand in his own. She doesn’t look back, knows
                it’s him, knows his touch. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GREAT HALL -SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Each House stands together as a
                group, the room buzzing. No one sits. Harry is nowhere to be seen. At the Tall Table
                at the top of the Hall two DEATH EATERS -- AMYCUS AND ALECTO CARROW -- stand like
                sinister sentinels, their eyes raking the crowd. PROFESSOR McGONAGALL, her face
                ashen, her bearing reduced, stands along the right wall, while Flitwick stands by
                the left wall. As Snape enters, the room goes slowly silent. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Many of you are surely wondering why I have summoned you here at this
                hour. It has come to my attention that earlier this evening... Harry Potter was
                sighted in Hogsmeade.</sp>
            <stage>A MURMURED THRILL fills the Hall. McGonagall’s eyes glisten with curiosity. Snape
                raises his voice, briefly, to quell the noise in the Hall. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> I mention this in the hopes that truth will not be supplanted by
                rumor. For myself and a few select members of the staff this comes as little
                surprise. We have, for some time, considered Mr. Potter’s return to Hogwarts to be
                not only possible but inevitable. Consequently, in the past several months and under
                my specific direction, exhaustive defensive strategies have been employed to defeat
                any attempt Mr. Potter might make to breach these walls. But know this. Should
                anyone -- student or staff -- attempt to aid Mr. Potter, that person will be
                punished in a manner consistent with the severity of their transgression. Rest
                assured: So long as I am Headmaster at Hogwarts, Harry Potter will never again step
                foot in this castle.</sp>
            <stage>As APPLAUSE erupts from the Slytherins, Maisy Reynolds, glowers over at them.
                Snape raises a hand. The room returns to silence. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Now then. If anyone here has knowledge of Mr. Potter’s movements this
                evening... I invite them to step forward now.</sp>
            <stage>Snape’s eyes rake the Hall. Dead silence. A nervous shift of glances. And then... </stage>
            <stage>FOOTSTEPS. A FIGURE appears in the shadows at the back of the Hall. McGonagall’s
                chin rises in disbelief. Maisy’s face blooms with hope. And then... </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY "><stage>O.S.</stage> I think I can help you out with that...</sp>
            <stage>... Harry appears. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It would seem that, despite your exhaustive defensive strategies, you
                have a bit of a security problem, Headmaster.</sp>
            <stage>Snape stares in stunned disbelief, then his gaze shifts as one by one, others
                emerge: Ron. Hermione. Lupin. Arthur. Molly. Fred. George. Percy. Luna. Dean Thomas.
                Bill. Fleur. Kingsley Shacklebolt. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And I’m afraid it’s rather extensive. </sp>
            <stage>The Carrows, who had been moving towards Harry, falter, turn to Snape with
                uncertainty. Harry’s eyes narrow with malice as he stares at Snape. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> How dare you stand where he stood. </sp>
            <stage>Snape watches Harry draw his wand, point it at him. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Tell them how it was that night. Tell then how you looked him in the
                eye, a man who trusted you... and killed him. Tell them!</sp>
            <stage>Snape’s eyes find Harry’s, but his face remains a mask. McGonagall stands poised,
                no longer an ashen ghost. Flitwick’s hand twitches over his wand. The air prickles
                with anticipation. Snape moves as if to retrieve his wand. McGonagall steps forward
                and sends a VOLCANIC BLAST Snape’s way. Pivoting, he parries the spell -- barely --
                and sends it RICOCHETING around the room. CHAOS ensues. Flitwick and the rest of the
                staff -inspired by Harry and McGonagall --leap forth, wands out. Snape, outnumbered,
                standing at the epicenter, parries spell after spell with astonishing skill
                deflecting two of the curses into Alecto and Amycus Carrow. Snape takes the measure
                of the room and sweeps his wand over his head, reducing the TORCHES that line the
                wall to SMOKE and pitching the Hall into total DARKNESS. As STUDENTS SCREAM, a GREAT
                WHOOSHING sound fills the Hall and some flying thing flickers past the windows,
                RATTLING the PANES before BLASTING through one. Instantly, the torches BURST back to
                life and we see that it’s McGonagall, wand raised aloft, who’s done it. In the
                moonlight, Harry can see a BATLIKE CREATURE beating into the night. McGonagall peers
                bitterly into the darkness. </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Coward! COWARD! And he didn’t even stay to fight! <stage>turning
                    to Harry</stage> Mr. Potter, do you mind telling me what you’re doing here,
                which, I trust you realize, is an act of complete and utter lunacy? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’m a Gryffindor. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> I thought it might have something to do with that. <stage>turning
                    to the room</stage> All right! Settle down! Settle down! The room quiets. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> It appears that your Headmaster, to use the common phrase, has
                done a bunk. </sp>
            <stage>CHEERS RISE from all Houses save Slytherin, where PANSY PARKINSON glowers along
                with Blaise and Goyle. Even McGonagall can’t help but smile. Just then, Harry WINCES
                slightly, pressing his fingers to his temple. </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Potter...</sp>
            <stage>A slow RUMBLING fills the Hall. Harry, fingers trembling with pain, glances up,
                sees DARK CLOUDS coagulating in the Enchanted Ceiling. McGonagall follows his gaze,
                as do others, watching as the clouds shift eerily, like blots of blood. Suddenly the
                FLAMES in the torches along the wallsTREMBLE as a CHILL BREEZE consumes the room.
                The Hall slowly DIMS. All grows progressively silent when... ... a GIRL SCREAMS, her
                voice rising and rising. Harry rushes through the throng, the students parting as he
                pelts forwards, pushing past them until he finds... ... Maisy, cowering on the floor
                in the corner, hands over her ears, eyes clenched tight. She seems possessed.
                Everyone watches, chilled. Finally Harry starts to move forward, when he himself
                WINCES, pressing his fingers to his temples. Another person SCREAMS somewhere in the
                Hall, then another. Harry glances about him, at the circle of faces in his vicinity.
                All are a mirror image of Maisy now, grimacing in pain. Harry stares, confused,
                stricken with pain, when... ... a VOICE BLOOMS in his head in a DEATHLY WHISPER. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT "><stage>V.O.</stage> I know that many of you will want to fight.
                Some of you may even think this wise. But this is folly.</sp>
            <stage>We WEAVE THROUGH the room, taking in the faces, listening in mute misery as
                Voldemort speaks. Ginny, Hermione, Ron, Fred, George, Seamus... on and on. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT "><stage>V.O.</stage> I wish you no harm. I have greatrespect for
                the students of Hogwarts. I was once one myselfafter all. I ask for but one thing
                and if granted no magical blood shall be spilt... For a moment they stand, hung in
                silence... </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT "><stage>V.O.</stage> Give me Harry Potter. Do this and none shall
                be harmed. Give me Harry Potter and I shall leave Hogwarts untouched. Give me Harry
                Potter and you will be rewarded.</sp>
            <stage>With that, the whisper recedes and those in the Hall slowly surface back into the
                prickling ambience of the here and now. Above them, the clouds evaporate in the
                Enchanted Ceiling. And then, like iron filings flaking to the surface of a magnet,
                every eye finds...Harry. For a moment, silence. Then, Pansy Parkinson jabs her
                finger at Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#PANSYPARKINSON"> But he’s there! Potter’s there! Someone grab him!</sp>
            <stage>Instinctively, Ginny steps in front of Harry, wand drawn. Then, as one, the
                Gryffindors assemble in a line and face towards the Slytherins, shielding Harry.
                Moments later, the Ravenclaws and Hufflepuffs do the same. Harry’s eyes glitter at
                the sight, moved. Ginny lowers her wand. Just then... FILCH bursts in the Hall. </stage>
            <sp who="#FILCH"> Students out of bed! Students in the corridors!</sp>
            <stage>Filch stops dead, as MRS. NORRIS wends through his legs. </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> They’re supposed to be out of bed, you blithering idiot! </sp>
            <sp who="#FILCH"> Oh. Sorry, mum. </sp>
            <stage>Filch begins to turn away. </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">Wait! As it turns out, Mr. Filch, your arrival is most opportune.
                If you would, I’d like you to lead Miss Parkinson and the rest of Slytherin House
                from the Hall. </sp>
            <sp who="#FILCH"> Right away. <stage>stopping</stage> Er, exactly where is it I’d be
                leadin’ em to, mum? </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">
                <stage>a thought, then...</stage> The dungeons should do. CHEERS rise again and
                McGonagall’s eyes turn on Harry. She rises up to full height, her jaw firm. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">I presume you have a reason for returning, Potter. What is it you
                need? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Time. As much as you can give me. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Do what you have to do. I’ll secure the castle. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Is that possible, Professor? </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> We teachers are rather good at magic, Potter. We’ve even been
                known to turn out a worthwhile witch or wizard on occasion. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">
                <stage>CONT'D</stage> I think it’s time I ask a few of them to take their magic
                beyond the classroom. What d’you think? Harry follows McGonagall’s gaze, sees
                Neville and Ginny conferring with a sprinkling of DA members. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I think you’re right. </sp>
            <stage>McGonagall nods, still sizing up Neville and the others. Harry turns, starts to
                exit. </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> By the way, Potter... <stage>as he looks back</stage> It’s good
                to see you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You, too, Professor.</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT/EXT" where="GREAT HALL/COURTYARD -SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Neville and Ginny
                flank McGonagall as she sweeps out of the Great Hall and into the courtyard.
                Flitwick and other members of the DA -- including Seamus -- trail after. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Let me get this straight, Professor. You’re giving us permission to
                do this? </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> That is correct, Longbottom. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> To blow it up. Boom. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Boom. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Wicked. <stage>a frown</stage> Um... exactly how do you propose we
                do this, Professor? </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Why don’t you confer with Mr. Finnegan. As I recall, he has a
                particular proclivity for pyrotechnics.</sp>
            <stage>Neville and Ginny glance back at Seamus. </stage>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> I can bring ‘er down. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">That’s the spirit. Now off you go.</sp>
            <stage>Neville, Ginny, Seamus and the DA peel off. </stage>
            <sp who="#FLITWICK"> You realize, of course, that nothing we do will be able to keep out
                You-Know-Who indefinitely. </sp>
            <sp who="#SPROUT"> That doesn’t mean we can’t hold him up. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> That doesn’t mean we can’t hold him up. And his name is
                Voldemort, Filius. You might as well use it. He’s going to try to kill you either
                way.</sp>
            <stage>With that, McGonagall wheels, raises her wand and points it in the direction of
                the Great Hall. </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">Piertotum Locomotor! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="ENTRANCE TO GREAT HALL - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Instantly,
                all along the corridor STATUES and SUITS OF ARMOR come to life on their plinths.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> As McGonagall and the
                others watch, the statues parade INTO VIEW.</stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Hogwarts is threatened! Man the boundaries and protect us! Do
                your duty to our school!</sp>
            <stage>As the statues thunder past, heading toward the viaduct, McGonagall watches with
                evident pleasure. </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> I’ve always wanted to use that spell. Several yards off, Flitwick
                holds his wand aloft, his face grimly determined. Momentarily a “disturbance”
                troubles the atmosphere -- this is powerful stuff -- McGonagall and other Staff
                members step forward to assist, wands raised high. Together, they conjure... </sp>
            <sp who="#TEACHERS"> Protego Maxima... Finato Duri... Repello Inimicum... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS (AERIAL) - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT "> ... a magical
                SHIELD, which expands ever outward, blooming over the castle grounds, while far
                below the STATUES march the length of the viaduct and take their positions along the
                perimeter, still as sentinels. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="WOODEN BRIDGE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Further on, small as
                ants from this vantage, Neville, Ginny, Seamus and half a dozen DA members approach
                the WOODEN BRIDGE. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS ROCK - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> As we leave them
                behind, MOVING BEYOND the Shield’s reach, a MASSIVE, QUIVERING SHADOW comes INTO
                VIEW, drifting toward the castle: DEATH EATERS, their numbers staggering. We DESCEND
                INTO their midst and a FIGURE EMERGES, stepping onto an OUTCROPPING, robes
                billowing, flanked by Bellatrix and PIUS THICKNESSE. We SWEEP AROUND, FIND his face:
                Voldemort. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - NIGHT"> Controlled chaos as scores of
                students and Staff sweep over the staircase, preparing for battle. Harry moves
                quickly, followed by Ron and Hermione. They speak with urgency. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Harry, Hermione and I have been thinking. It doesn’t really matter if we
                find the Horcrux.</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"><stage>stopping</stage> What’re you saying? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Unless we can destroy it. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> So we were thinking -</sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You were thinking. It’s Ron’s idea. And it’s brilliant. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You destroyed Tom Riddle’s Diary with a Basilisk fang, right? Well, we
                know where we might find one, don’t we? </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks at the two of them. Ponders this. Nods. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Okay. But take this. That way you can find me when you get back. </sp>
            <stage>Harry hands Hermione the MARAUDER’S MAP. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Where are you going? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ravenclaw Common Room. Got to start somewhere.</sp>
            <stage>Hermione nods, slips the Map in her beaded bag and she and Ron head off. Just
                before they turn the corner, Ron looks back, holds Harry’s glance briefly... and
                then is gone. As Harry continues on, Luna steps INTO FRAME, watches him vanish in
                the crowd. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="SPANNING BRIDGE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Harry dashes across the
                bridge. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Harry! Wait! I need to talk to you! </sp>
            <stage>He glances back, slowing, but doesn’t break stride. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’m a bit preoccupied right now, Luna. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> But you won’t find anything where you’re going. You’re wasting your
                time. </sp>
            <stage>Harry frowns, mildly annoyed, doesn’t glance back. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> We’ll talk later, Luna. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Harry -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Later.</sp>
            <stage>Luna stops, watching him recede. Then suddenly: </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> HARRY POTTER! YOU LISTEN TO ME RIGHT NOW!</sp>
            <stage>Harry stops, stunned. Turns. Luna collects herself. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Don’t you remember what Cho said about Rowena Ravenclaw’s diadem:
                ‘There’s not a person alive who’s seen it.’</sp>
            <stage>Harry stares dumbly back, shrugs, “So?” </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> It’s obvious, isn’t it? We have to talk to someone who’s dead. </sp>
            <stage>Harry stares at her oddly when suddenly he becomes aware of the DISTURBANCE in
                the AIR around them. He looks up, toward the shield above, then at the tiny figure
                of Flitwick, wand aloft, standing with McGonagall andSprout. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> He’s very impressive, isn’t he? </sp>
            <stage>Harry starts to respond when he WINCES, clutches his scar, sees... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS ROCK -SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... Voldemort, regarding the
                castle pityingly as the Hogwarts faithful take their positions. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> They never learn. Such a pity. Voldemort smiles, as if amused. His
                eyes gleam fiercely. Begin. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Bellatrix RAISES HER ARM in signal and the sea of Death Eaters
                settle, poised and waiting. The air goes still... </sp>
            <sp who="#THICKNESSE"> But, my Lord, shouldn’t we wait -Voldemort’s eyes shift, killing
                the remainder of Thicknesse’s sentence before it can escape his throat. Bellatrix’s
                eyes narrow in contempt. Chilled, Thicknesse looks away. Then -- as if burying a
                knife deep in the heart of an enemy... Bellatrix drops her arm. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="SPANNING BRIDGE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> EXPLOSIONS SOUND. Harry
                blinks, looking upward as the sky blazes with light and SMOKING TENDRILS plummet
                towards the castle. BOOM! The bridge ROLLS under his feet but the shield holds...
                for now. As fire fills the sky again, Fred and George burst out of the castle,
                grinning madly. </stage>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Nice night for it! Harry turns to Luna. Okay, Luna. mind? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who’ve you got in </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="EMPTY CORRIDOR - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Ron and Hermione move down
                a desolate corridor. They react to the distant sound of MUTED EXPLOSIONS, consider
                the door to the bathroom before them, then each other. Without a word, they pass
                through. Gone. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="WOODEN BRIDGE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Neville limps into our
                FIELD OF VIEW and peers outward, marveling at the bombardment above. </stage>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS "><stage>O.S.</stage> That’s it. I want a charge on each and every
                joist.</sp>
            <stage>Neville peers below. Down amongst the pilings, Seamus directs KATIE BELL, CHO and
                NIGEL in placing magical“charges” (spells) on key pressure points. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> You do know what you’re doing, don’t you, Seamus?</sp>
            <stage>Seamus winks, gives a thumbs-up -- he seems to be enjoying himself, perhaps
                inordinately so. Neville exhales, shakes his head. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Blimey.</sp>
            <stage>Neville looks off then, peering back along the bridge’s spine to where Ginny
                stands at the far end. Seeing him, she raises her hand to wave... then goes still,
                her hand suspended in the air, looking past Neville as a HOWLING rises on the air
                like a crude battle cry. Hearing it, too, Neville turns, our view expanding, rising,
                revealing... HUNDREDS OF BAYING SNATCHERS rolling in an angry wave over the hill
                opposite. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Not good. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="STAIRCASE -NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Luna leads Harry up a SHADOWY
                STAIRCASE, out into... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GREY LADY CORRIDOR - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> ... a corridor. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> If you’re to find her, you’ll find her down there. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Aren’t you coming? </sp>
            <stage>Luna cocks her head, staring down toward the dark end. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> No. I think it best if you two talk alone. She’s very shy. Luna exits.
                Harry eyes the shadows ahead. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="BATTLEMENTS - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Lupin and SHACKLEBOLT stride
                out into the night as Dean tags after. Shacklebolt gives instructions to Dean. </stage>
            <sp who="#SHACKLEBOLT"> Tell Professor McGonagall Remus and I will handle this
                side of the castle. Yes, sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#DEAN"> As Dean starts off, the grounds beyond and below come INTO VIEW: a sea
                of Death Eaters. Kingsley and Remus stop dead, narrow their eyes. </sp>
            <sp who="#SHACKLEBOLT"> Dean! (as Dean stops) On second thought, tell Professor
                McGonagall we might need one or two more wands this side. Dean nods, continues on,
                merely trading a glance withArthur, Fred and George as they appear, staring in
                stunned disbelief at the deadly throng across the landscape. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> It’s the quality of one’s conviction that determines success, not the
                number of one’s followers. Lupin stares straight ahead, as does Shacklebolt. </sp>
            <sp who="#SHACKLEBOLT"> Who said that? Me. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> For the first time, they look at each other, share a fatalistic smile.
                Just then TONKS appears. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> Speaking of quality. </sp>
            <stage>Tonks rushes past the Weasleys, lightly touching Arthur’s arm as she leaps into
                Lupin’s embrace. He hugs her deeply. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> You shouldn’t have. It’s Teddy who needs you. </sp>
            <sp who="#TONKS"> He’ll sleep ‘til dawn and snore like his father. It’s you who needs me
                tonight.</sp>
            <stage>He looks her in the eye, not denying it. Then a THUNDEROUS BOOM SHATTERS the
                night and ACRID PLUMES of smoke strafe the sky. As they plummet, we TRACE their
                arcs... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GREY LADY CORRIDOR - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> ... DOWNWARD,
                as SHADOWS, streaking across the walls of the corridor Harry walks. Up ahead, a
                GAUZY SHADOW plays eerily in the corner, undulating like the fins of a goldfish. As
                he turns the corner, Harry finds a BEAUTIFUL GHOST (Helena Ravenclaw) floating
                before aVEINED MIRROR, her reflected eyes distant and sad. As her face comes INTO
                VIEW, he reacts, recognizing her from his visions. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s you... </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="WOODEN BRIDGE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> The sea of Snatchers
                close on the bridge, their HOWLS DEAFENING. As Neville looks on in terror, a fresh
                VOLLEY of ROCKETS lace the night sky, his skin throbbing with a kaleidoscope of
                light: Blood red. Blue moon. Bright sun. He glances up, watching as the bombs strike
                the SHIELD and the SKY SHIVERS like water. Suddenly, his expression changes, faint
                hope displacing dread as... THWACK! ... teeth bared, the first Snatcher runs flat
                into Flitwick’s shield and bounces back. THWACK! THWACK! THWACK! One after another,
                the Snatchers bounce back. A grin blooms on Neville’s face. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Ha! Ha! </sp>
            <stage>Scabior stops short, eyeing the area ahead warily. Neville begins to LAUGH, in
                faint disbelief at first, then harder, almost maniacally, consumed by a fear turned
                to ecstasy. Hoarsely, he bellows at Scabior. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Yeah! You and whose army! </sp>
            <stage>He grins, raises his wand and, with a TRIUMPHANT WHOOP, WHIPS his arm (too)
                VIGOROUSLY into the air and fires a SHOT into the night sky... </stage>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> Woah! Easy up there! </sp>
            <stage>Neville looks down, sees Seamus -- draped in CHARGES -- glaring up at him. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Sorry. <stage>rubbing his elbow</stage> Ow. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="OUTSIDE CHAMBER OF SECRETS - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Ron and
                Hermione reach the SERPENT’S HATCH that bars the way to the chamber. Ron takes out
                his wand. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"><stage>in Parseltongue</stage>Take me inside.</sp>
            <stage>Hermione’s eyes widen in shock. Ron shrugs. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Harry talks in his sleep. Haven’t you noticed? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No. Of course not. </sp>
            <stage>The hatch swings open. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="APPROACH TO CHAMBER OF SECRETS - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Ron and
                Hermione make their way through the shadowy cavern, BONES snapping like fish scales
                under their feet. As they reach a low wall of rocks, waist-high, Ron stops. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> I’ve never got this far before. I’m scared. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron looks at her, then hoists himself through. Me too. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CHAMBER OF SECRETS - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Ron and
                Hermione spill into the soaring cavern and begin to walk the gauntlet of serpents.
                Hermione peers ahead into Salazar Slytherin’s sinister face. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I didn’t expect it to be like this. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What did you expect it to be like? Not this. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> The Grey Lady drifts eerily,
                staring at Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’re the Grey Lady, the ghost ofRavenclaw Tower. </sp>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> I do not answer to that name. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’m sorry. It’s Helena, isn’t it? Helena Ravenclaw. Rowena’s daughter.
                Luna told me. </sp>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> Are you a friend of Luna’s? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. She thought you might be able to help me. </sp>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> You seek my mother’s diadem. </sp>
            <stage>Harry stops, stunned. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes! That’s right -</sp>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> Luna is kind. Unlike so many of the others, but she was wrong. I
                cannot help you. </sp>
            <stage>She begins to drift away. Outside, EXPLOSIONS are heard. The room QUAKES. Harry
                looks desperate. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Wait! Please! </sp>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> Many have sought my mother’s diadem. Its powers are legendary... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But I don’t care about its powers! Honestly -</sp>
            <stage>But she is drifting away. Harry watches in desperation. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I don’t seek it for myself! You have to believe me! </sp>
            <stage>But she only drifts on. Helplessly, Harry watches her go, then... decides: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I want to destroy it. </sp>
            <stage>She stops. Turns. He sees this has hooked her in some way. Begins walking back
                toward her, nodding. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> That’s what you want, isn’t it, Helena? You want it destroyed. </sp>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY">
                <stage>vague, drifting</stage> She thought I took it to hurt her. 
             But I only wanted to be more like her,
                clever and wise. She wore it so beautifully, but on me... I grew to hate it... the
                pain I felt... the pain I feel even now... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’ll end your pain, Helena. Tell me where it is and I’ll destroy it, I
                swear, on my mother’s memory -</sp>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> Another swore to destroy it, many years ago, a strange boy with
                a strange name... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Tom Riddle -</sp>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> But he lied. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He’s lied to many people -</sp>
            <stage>Suddenly, her eyes blaze with anger, her face contorting horribly and Harry can’t
                help but take a step back. </stage>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> I know what he’s done! I know who he is! He defiled it! With
                Dark Magic! </sp>
            <stage>Harry stares at her, watching as her eyes drift and her face resolves itself
                again, vacant but beautiful. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. That’s right. But I can undo that, Helena. I can destroy it once
                and for all. But only if you tell me where he hid it. You know where he hid it,
                don’t you, Helena? You just have to tell me. Please. <stage>stepping toward
                    her</stage> Trust me.</sp>
            <stage>She looks at him, standing so close now, only inches apart, lost in his eyes for
                a moment. </stage>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> Strange... you remind me of him a bit... </sp>
            <stage>Harry stares at her, stung, suddenly looking a bit lost himself. EXPLOSIONS sound
                again, faintly this time and for a moment it’s as if he’s forgotten why he’s come
                here. Then, her voice brings him round: </stage>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY"> It’s here. In the castle. In the place where everything is
                hidden...</sp>
            <stage>Harry probes her eyes, baffled. </stage>
            <sp who="#THEGREYLADY">If you have to ask, you’ll never know. If you know, you need only
                ask... </sp>
            <stage>Slowly, Harry’s expression changes. Then, he is backing away. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Thank you...</sp>
            <stage>... then turning... </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Thank you...</sp>
            <stage>... then running. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Harry careens down the
                staircase, buffeted by the chaos that surrounds him, swept forward by the tide of
                people screaming and shouting as they deploy to different parts of the castle. It’s
                madness. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CHAMBER OF SECRETS - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Ron emerges from the
                shadows, basilisk fang in hand, and joins Hermione on Slytherin’s altar. She reaches
                into the beaded bag and removes the cup. He extends the fang to her. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> You do it. </sp>
            <stage>She starts to speak, to object, when Ron speaks: </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yes, you can. </sp>
            <stage>She reaches out, her hand trembling, and takes the fang from his fingers. She
                raises her arm -- still as glass for a moment -- then knifes down... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Voldemort HOWLS, his eyes
                burning scarlet... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Harry STAGGERS, ROARING
                in agony, his IRISES BLOOMING RED in the reflected glow of the guttering torch on
                the wall he steadies himself against as... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... impulsively,
                violently, Voldemort draws his wand -- the Elder Wand --then stops --briefly --
                studying it. A strange mixture of awe and ambivalence darkens his face. Then,
                suddenly, it vanishes and he points the wand to the sky. His arm SWEEPS forth. And a
                CRACK OF THUNDER shakes the grounds. The sky turns white. For a moment, everything
                is FROZEN, STILL... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... and then an ERUPTION
                of sound and fury rolls over the grounds. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="WOODEN BRIDGE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Neville stares to the sky,
                his face bleached white. Ginny’s pupils contract. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> McGonagall studies the trembling
                shield above. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="BATTLEMENTS - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Tonks reaches for Lupin’s
                hand, but is unable to bridge the few inches that separate their fingers. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="BATTLEMENTS - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Stricken, Fred and George and
                Dean stare at the night sky. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="VIADUCT - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> An ARMORED WARRIOR STATUE stares
                impassively. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="OTHER PART OF VIADUCT - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Flitwick turns,
                stares up at the castle, standing dark as ink against the sky. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> And then Voldemort’s arm
                drops and... ... Flitwick’s shield shatters. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Harry staggers against
                the wall as the pain loosens its grip; the scarlet in his eyes ebbs as the flames
                flickering in the sconces gutter... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... the SCARLET FIRE
                BLAZING in Voldemort’s eyes recedes... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CHAMBER OF SECRETS - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... the cup tumbles
                into the water, SIZZLING as it makes contact, sending a WRAITH of WATER spewing
                forth, tortured and writhing. It hangs, suspended tremulously in the air,
                horrifying... then EXPLODES, raining over Ron and Hermione. They stand, utterly
                still, as the water runs off their bodies and pools at their feet. For a moment,
                they stay like this, unmoving, as if amazed to have survived, then their eyes shift,
                find each other. They do not blink, the moment fraught. Then Hermione -- almost
                imperceptibly -- nods. Finally, they move, closing the space between them, and kiss.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS - GROUNDS/VIADUCT - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> SIZZLING PLUMES
                strafe the night sky, raining down on the knights arrayed along the bridge and onto
                the castle itself. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> The PLUMES RICOCHET madly,
                shattering the tracery as the Knights struggle to defend the castle. McGonagall
                looks up: more PLUMES light up the sky, begin to plummet. </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Fall inside! Everybody! Fall inside!</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT/EXT" where="BATTLEMENTS - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Windows shatter, pierced
                by PLUMES, which MATERIALIZE into DEATH EATERS. Instantly, students and staff engage
                the dark wizards, standing shoulder to shoulder as they defend the school against
                the onslaught. Fred and George fall in on either side of Arthur, wands BLAZING,
                while Lupin, Tonks and Shacklebolt battle only yards away, the fighting swift and
                lethal. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="WOODEN BRIDGE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Neville’s eyes rake the
                fiery nightscape before him, then shift to the more immediate vicinity. He goes
                still. Scabior. The Snatchers. Are rising. Moving forward. Toward... him. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Not good. </sp>
            <stage>Neville starts to back up slowly, then turns heel and pelts back up the bridge.
                Plumes rain down from the sky. Enemy spells skitter at Neville’s feet. He looks
                back, sees Scabior and the others closing like a herd of wildebeests. </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Ready!? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Are you bloody joking?! </sp>
            <stage>She lifts her wand, ready to DETONATE the SPELLS, when Seamus pops up beside her,
                a rather maniacal gleam in his eye. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"><stage>to himself</stage> Oh God -</sp>
            <stage>KA-BLAAAAAM! Neville sets off the charges. Instantly, one bridge section after
                another EXPLODES, rolling up like a carpet. Snatchers fall from sight, plummeting
                into the darkness. Neville looks over his shoulder, sees Scabior closing on him,
                then looks back towards Ginny, who stands frozen, wand raised, never fired, looking
                at... ... Seamus, his face blooming with fanatical ecstasy as he watches the charges
                detonate. As Seamus HOWLS with pleasure, Neville, WHEEZING PAINFULLY at this point,
                glances back and sees that Scabior has closed the distance, is coming fast when --
                KA-BLAM! -- Scabior is catapulted into the air. Neville looks momentarily relieved,
                then realizes, to his evident dismay, that the bridge is falling away with
                increasing speed. Alarmed, Ginny looks to Seamus. </stage>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> He’s good...</sp>
            <stage>The remainders begin to discharge, tripping off like firecrackers, one section
                after another vanishing... </stage>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> He’s good... </sp>
            <stage>... including the section under Neville’s feet... And he is gone. Ginny GASPS,
                hands to her face. Seamus frowns. The moment hangs. Seemingly forever. Then CHARRED
                FINGERNAILS appear over the final remaining section of the bridge, followed by
                Neville himself, teeth blackened, a patch of hair lost, scalp smoldering. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"><stage>sarcastically</stage> Well done, Seamus! </sp>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"><stage>grinning</stage> Told yeh I’d bring ‘er down. As Neville
                glowers at him, Ginny reaches out, hoists him onto what’s left of the bridge.
                Neville shakes some ASHES from his head and then... GRINS unexpectedly. </sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> What? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> That was kind of exciting. </sp>
            <stage>Seamus grins and winks knowingly. Ginny shakes her head. </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Mad. The both of you. </sp>
            <stage>Just then, a thundering RUMBLE almost sends Neville tumbling off the bridge
                again. As Ginny steadies him, they all peer into the distance: GIANTS. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Not good.</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="VIADUCT/ENTRANCE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Giants crash over the
                viaduct, laying waste to the Knights as more PLUMES rocket overhead.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD/VIADUCT - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Death Eaters run
                roughshod over the grounds. Giants step on anything in their path, including the
                occasional Death Eater, crushing skulls, snapping spines.</stage>
            <stage>In the midst of the mayhem, Draco appears, his face bearing the small gashes he
                suffered at Malfoy Manor. Slipping past the nastiest players in the fray, he enters
                the castle. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="DUNGEON CORRIDOR - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> A grinning Filch regards
                the terrified run of Slytherin faces peering from within the dank cages before him. </stage>
            <sp who="#FILCH"> Night-tee night. </sp>
            <sp who="#PANSYPARKINSON"> You let us out of here, you filthy squib!</sp>
            <stage>Filch grins, shaking the ring of keys in his hand, then turns away. We STAY WITH
                him as he walks away, then -- gently at first -- the chamber begins to TREMBLE,
                until -- with each step -- it shakes more and more VIOLENTLY. Finally, Filch stops,
                glancing apprehensively about when... ... KA-BOOM! Plaster RAINS DOWN and a RAGGED
                HOLE opens in the CEILING, followed by another and then another. A HUGE EYE peers
                down FROM ABOVE; a MASSIVE NOSE sniffs stupidly. It’s... ... a GIANT. As the
                Slytherins scream, the giant’s FIST drops heavily through the hole, fingers probing
                the cell clumsily. As Filch watches in horror, the cell falls to pieces and the
                Slytherins spill forth. Goyle is ruthless, flingingHousemates aside while Blaise
                follows in his wake. As they reach the safety of the corridor, a hand --this one of
                human scale --reaches out of the darkness, grabs Goyle: Draco. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Harry, still feeling the
                effects of Voldemort’s Shield shattering, stumbles forward as spells fly and bodies
                fall. Like a man possessed, he veers on, fighting his way toward the archway
                opposite when he sees a Death Eater drawing a bead on him. With nary a thought,
                Harry drops him with a Stunning Spell just as Ginny and Neville appear. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ginny! Neville! You alright? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Never better! Feel like I could spit fire! Haven’t seen Luna, have
                you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Luna -- ? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> I’m mad for her! Think it’s about time I told her, seeing as there’s
                a pretty good chance we’ll both be dead by dawn! </sp>
            <stage>Harry and Ginny watch him dash off, then turn quickly back to each other. Their
                eyes catch. An instant, a moment of meaning in the midst of madness. </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> I know. </sp>
            <stage>Then she is off, running, gone. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="WOODEN CORRIDOR - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> As Harry pelts down the
                corridor, an EXPLOSION DETONATES and the windows running the length of the corridor
                EXPLODE -- one after another -- showering Harry in glass. Then the wall itself falls
                away, rubble falling into the night and below. Harry never breaks stride. As the
                BILLOWING SMOKE thins, Malfoy appears, flanked by Blaise and Goyle. They follow.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> ... Ron and Hermione, flying
                out of the bathroom, still soaking wet. Taking the Marauder’s Map from the beaded
                purse, they look. It is SWARMING WITH DOTS. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell. We’ll never find him </sp>
            <stage>on this. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> There he is. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What? </sp>
            <stage>As Hermione points to Harry’s name amidst the ant colony on the parchment, Ron --
                unbeknownst to her -- regards her with naked appreciation. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Brilliant. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> He vanished. Just now. I saw it. </sp>
            <stage>Ron glances at MAP -- then: </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> He must’ve gone into the Room of Requirement. It doesn’t show on the
                map, remember? You said so last year. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"><stage>amazed he remembered</stage> That’s right. I did. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Let’s go. </sp>
            <stage>As Ron dashes off, Hermione -- unbeknownst to him -- regards him with naked
                appreciation, then follows. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Brilliant. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="DESTROYED WOODEN CORRIDOR - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Ron and
                Hermione race through the SHATTERED GLASS, the smoke thinner now. We TRACK them TO
                the end of the corridor and INTO another, where TAPESTRIES BURN and PORTRAITS hang
                askew. Suddenly, Hermione grabs Ron’s hand, gestures ahead, where Draco, Blaise and
                Goyle are slipping around a corner. Ron and Hermione follow. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR OUTSIDE ROOM OF REQUIREMENT - NIGHT"> Draco stops,
                turns to face the wall and CLOSES HIS EYES. As the window behind EXPLODES, filling
                the corridor with SMOKE, Goyle and Blaise jump, but Draco never flinches. </stage>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> Take my hand. <stage>as they hesitate</stage> Now. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR TO CORRIDOR - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Ron and
                Hermione creep carefully to the end of their corridor, peer slowly round the corner. </stage>
            <stage>THEIR POV - AN EMPTY CORRIDOR swirling with smoke. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="ROOM OF REQUIREMENT - NIGHT"> Harry continues on, almost running
                now, then WINCES, faltering as he’s struck by a spike of PAIN, his fingers tracing
                his scar as he resumes his pace, knowing he’s getting closer, feeling it, his head
                HUMMING with the Horcrux’s sinister siren song, the sound growing LOUDER and LOUDER
                as he turns down yet another aisle and... Stops. A vein THROBS VISIBLY at Harry’s
                temple. Hand trembling, he reaches out, pushes aside a STACK OF DECAYING SPELLBOOKS
                and finds a PAIR OF EYES looking at him over the rim of a DUSTY CANISTER. He pushes
                the canister aside and reveals a POCKMARKED STONE BUST of a WARLOCK with GLASS EYES.
                Perched atop its head, dulled by time, is ROWENA RAVENCLAW’S DIADEM. He reaches
                out... </stage>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> Well, well, what brings you here, Potter? </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks slowly over his shoulder. Draco -- Blaise and Goyle at his side --
                steps INTO VIEW, his face bisected by light. He holds a wand on Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I could ask you the same. </sp>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> I virtually lived here last year. Remember? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I remember. </sp>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> You have something of mine. I’d like it back. </sp>
            <stage>Draco gestures to the wand sticking out of Harry’s pocket. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What’s wrong with the one you have? </sp>
            <sp who="#DRACO"><stage>studying it</stage> It’s my mother’s. It’s very powerful, but
                it’s not the same. It doesn’t... understand me. <stage>looking up</stage> Know what
                I mean? Just then, over Draco’s shoulder and several yards beyond, a SHADOW FLICKERS
                (Ron). Harry looks down, notices a DROP of WATER fall from the PANT CUFF, cuts his
                eyes away. He reaches for the wand in his pocket. </sp>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> Easy. </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks up, sees Draco watching him closely. He studies Draco’s face. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Why didn’t you tell her? </sp>
            <stage>Draco doesn’t respond. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Bellatrix. You knew it was me. But you didn’t say anything. </sp>
            <stage>Blaise and Goyle, confused by this, regard Draco dimly from either side. Draco
                fidgets, his hand twitching on the wand. </stage>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> Give me my wand. </sp>
            <stage>Harry continues to study Draco’s face. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. I don’t think so... </sp>
            <stage>With blithe disregard, Harry removes the wand in his own pocket, ponders it. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Besides, its allegiance is to me now. If you want it, you’ll have to
                win it back. Perhaps even kill me... </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks up. He and Draco lock eyes. </stage>
            <sp who="#GOYLE"> C’mon, Draco. Don’t be a prat. Just do ’im.</sp>
            <stage>Draco’s hand twitches, his brow conflicted, then his eyes shift -- catch sight of
                Hermione, in SILHOUETTE, far beyond Harry’s shoulder, her wand pointed... at him. He
                blinks, as if she were a mirage... then... a BALL of SCARLET LIGHT bursts from her
                wand, briefly illuminating her face, and strikes his hand. As his wand flies free,
                Goyle steps into the breach and fires back at Hermione.</stage>
            <sp who="#GOYLE"> Avada Kedavra!</sp>
            <stage>The spell caroms off the stone bust instead, sending the diadem spinning into the
                air. Ron fires a flurry of spells at Goyle, but he manages to elude them all by
                crashing through the wall of junk. As it TEETERS, Ron pelts through the hole made by
                Goyle and gives chase. Ting! Harry looks up, sees the diadem bounce off the top of a
                BIRDCAGE, skitter along the top of the highest shelf and bounce... out of sight.
                Gone. Turning back, he finds Blaise taking aim at him. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Expelliarmus! </sp>
            <stage>Blaise’s wand flies free and he scarpers. An instant later, Hermione steps INTO
                VIEW. A MASSIVE GROAN echoes and the walls of towering junk SHUDDER. Harry looks up.
                Hermione looks up. Then at each other. The sky is falling. </stage>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - HIGH One after another, the towering walls spill like dominos. </stage>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE -GROUND LEVEL Harry and Hermione run side by side as the world comes
                crashing down. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Did you see where it went? The diadem! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s gone! We’ll never -</sp>
            <stage>Ting! Ting! Ting! The diadem drops from the sky and hops, skips and jumps down
                the aisle in front of them. Harry and Hermione exchange a glance and pelt after it.
                Harry nearly has it in grasp when a small AVALANCHE of MOLDY BOOKS bars his path.
                Hermione leaps over the books, reaches out and... grabs it. Harry comes panting up. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well done. Let’s find Ron and get out of here.</sp>
            <stage>Harry wheels, sees Ron running towards them chased by aRIVER of SCARLET
                FLAMES.</stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> RUN! Goyle’s set the bloody place on fire! </sp>
            <stage>As one, the trio dashes through the remaining aisles as the towers of junk turn
                to ash all around them. The flames draw closer, mutating into a pack of fiery
                beasts: SERPENTS, CHIMAERAS, DRAGONS -- all nipping at their heels. No matter which
                way they turn, the flames follow them. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Split up! </sp>
            <stage>Each goes a separate way, but it’s no use. The fire simply divides, the serpent
                slithering after Harry, the chimaera after Hermione, the dragon after Ron. Harry
                glances up, sees Malfoy and Blaise scaling a mountain of burning junk, doomed. He
                takes one turn after another until he comes to a clearing and nearly runs into...
                Ron and Hermione as they arrive from separate paths. They glance around frantically.
                No free path exists. The flames ROAR, racing toward them. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Do we climb! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No, it’ll just follow us! </sp>
            <stage>Harry glances around once more and sees them: HALF A DOZEN ANCIENT BROOMSTICKS. </stage>      
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Here! Take one!</sp>
            <stage>He tosses Ron and Hermione broomsticks then takes one for himself. As Hermione
                slips the diadem atop her head, the flames EXPLODE into the clearing, ENGULFING them
                as they... ... SOAR FREE, just barely eluding the snap of the dragon’s fiery jaws.
                As they race away, a HORRIBLE SCREAM pierces the clamor and they all look below, see
                the flames devour Goyle. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Serves him right. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> C’mon! This way!</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Wait! What about Malfoy and Blaise! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"><stage>to Hermioine</stage> He’s joking, right? Then Harry sees them,
                perched atop a fragile, crumbling tower. Harry whips his broom around and jets
                forth. Ron shakes his head, then jets after, BELLOWING: </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> IF WE DIE FOR THEM, I’LL KILL YOU, HARRY!</sp>
            <stage>Harry sweeps down, grips Malfoy’s hand while Ron takes Blaise’s. The instant
                Draco’s foot leaves the mountain of junk, it collapses into a great billowing cloud
                of ash, mushrooming upward and blinding Harry and Ron. Unable to get their bearings,
                they swerve dangerously, squinting and choking when... ... a GIANT BEAM of LIGHT
                shimmers in the distance, like a beacon. It’s Hermione, hovering on her broom, wand
                raised. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Brilliant. </sp>
            <stage>Harry turns, catches Ron marveling Hermione. Ron turns, sees Harry looking at
                him. Then, as one, they fly pellmell toward Hermione’s beacon. As they draw close
                the light burns so bright all goes white and they burst... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR -CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> ... through the wall,
                tumbling into the corridor. Malfoy lands face down, retching. As Hermione rolls
                over, the diadem SPINS MADLY on the ground. Harry snatches it quickly, as if it
                might run away and Hermione tosses him the basilisk fang. He stares down at the
                smoking diadem and briefly pauses, reading the words etched there: Wit Beyond
                Measure Is Man’s Greatest Treasure. Then, without hesitation, he drives the fang
                into the blackened crown and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... Voldemort freezes,
                BELLOWING in PAIN as his eyes burn RED and he GLARES toward the castle in the
                distance, where... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... Harry GRIMACES IN AGONY and
                ROARS with PAIN, the veins at his TEMPLE THROBBING, his KNUCKLES BURNING WHITE as he
                grips the basilisk fang. FISSURES SURFACE IN HIS FINGERNAILS and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... Voldemort’s pale hand
                grips the Elder Wand so fiercely hairline cracks craze the wand’s veneer.
                Voldemort’s stricken face wheels toward the black sky above, eyes scanning the dull
                stars with despair as he RELEASES a MOURNFUL SHRIEK and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... the fang CRUMBLES in Harry’s
                fist and Harry, staring toward the ceiling, GASPS DESPERATELY, purging himself of
                the pain. He looks down, regarding the diadem with a kind of mournful horror, then
                Ron kicks it back into the Room of Requirement, where it EXPLODES in a VORTEX of
                FLAMES and the Room re-seals itself as... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS ROCK -SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... Voldemort’s eyes glitter
                with madness, his gaze lost, adrift in the dark constellations above. When he
                speaks, finally, his VOICE is HOARSE, oddly TENDER: </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Nagini. Come. </sp>
            <stage>Voldemort begins to slip away, BLASTING anyone who stands in his way. Pius
                Thicknesse comes INTO VIEW. His eyes widen. Voldemort raises his wand and, with
                callous disregard, executes him as well. As those ahead part for him and Nagini, we
                return to... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... Draco, staring fearfully at
                Harry. Blaise scrambles up and off. Draco lingers briefly, then finally rises and
                follows, but as he reaches the end of the corridor, he looks back. He begins to say
                something, then continues on. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> You’re bloody well welcome! <stage>looking away</stage> Prat. Ron looks
                back, to Hermione, and follows her gaze to Harry, who stares into the distance, his
                face still bearing traces of the agony he’s just endured. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron, you once asked me if I thought he felt it -- Voldemort -- when we
                destroy a Horcrux, when we destroy a piece of his soul. </sp>
            <stage>Ron and Hermione wait. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He does. </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks up then, meets their eyes: </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s the snake. She’s the last one. The last Horcrux. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Where will he take her? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Someplace safe. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. He’ll keep her close. </sp>
            <stage>As Harry wipes his brow, grazing his scar, trying to dispel the pain he feels --
                Ron studies him intently. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Look inside him, Harry. </sp>
            <stage>Hermione turns, looks at Ron. Then Harry does as well. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Find out where he is. If we find him, we find the snake. Then we’re one
                step closer to ending this.</sp>
            <stage>Hermione studies Harry and Ron as they stare silently atone another. Finally,
                Harry closes his eyes. For a moment: nothing. Then: his eyelids dance with movement,
                his scar SPASMS. He winces. Finds himself... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="SCOTTISH LANDSCAPE - FLYING - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> ... soaring
                over dark fields, past unspeakable devastation. The Quidditch Pitch rolls INTO VIEW, ABLAZE...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="BOAT HOUSE -SAME TIME - NIGHT"> A CLOAKED FIGURE (Voldemort)
                sweeps eerily forward, Nagini slithering at his feet. A FIGURE (Lucius Malfoy) looks
                up... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="BOAT HOUSE -SAME TIME - NIGHT"> The walls shimmer oddly,
                reflecting the water’s surface. Here, the assault on Hogwarts is muted, distant. A
                haggard LUCIUS MALFOY nervously eyes Nagini whileVoldemort paces with a strange
                energy, glancing at the wand in his fingers -- the Elder Wand -- then to the lake
                itself, where a reflected Hogwarts burns in a beautiful blur. Suddenly, his eyes
                shift to Lucius. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Stop looking at her. She smells your fear. It agitates her. Be
                grateful she’s just eaten. </sp>
            <stage>Lucius glances nervously to the weathered floor, to the BLOOD smeared there. He
                closes his eyes to blot out the image when an EXPLOSION detonates in the distance.
                He jumps. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> Forgive me, my Lord, but wouldn’t it be more prudent to call
                off this battle and seek the boy yourself? </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> I do not need to seek the boy! Before the night is out, he will
                come to me! Do you understand! </sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> Of c-course, my Lord. </sp>
            <stage>Lucius trembles, staring into Voldemort’s scarlet eyes. Voldemort steps forward,
                voice more measured. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> How do you live with yourself, Lucius? <stage>eyeing him with
                    disgust</stage> Go. Find Severus. Tell him I need to see him immediately.</sp>
            <stage>Lucius rises quickly, exits. Voldemort fixes his eyes on the wand once again. The
                snake HISSES. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="CORRIDOR (OUTSIDE ROR) - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Harry
                TWITCHES. His eyes flutter open. The sounds of battle no longer distant. Hermione
                and Ron wait expectantly. Harry nods. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I know where he is. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="AERIAL SHOT - EPIC VIEW OF HOGWARTS - NIGHT"> The battle rages
                on. Hogwarts in flames. We DESCEND INTO the... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD -NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> ... courtyard, where students
                and staff trade spells withDeath Eaters, among them PADMA PATIL; Neville and Seamus;
                Sprout, and Kingsley. From an upper balcony, PROFESSOR TRELAWNEY raises her wand,
                draws a bead on a Death Eater and with a forceful flick, sends him flying through
                the air. Seamus regards her with amazement. </stage>
            <sp who="#TRELAWNEY"> There’s more to me than incense and tea leaves, Mr. Finnegan. </sp>
            <stage>Dean trades spells with a Death Eater, while Luna STUNS a QUARTET of Death Eaters
                -- one-two-three -- and watches the fourth fall before she can fire. She turns, sees
                Neville standing behind her, wand smoking. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUNA"> Thanks. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Don’t mention it. </sp>
            <stage>As the trio pelts through the madness, Hermione GASPS, catching sight of LAVENDER
                BROWN as she falls to the ground. Hermione’s eyes shift, spy FENRIR GREYBACK, lips
                still glistening with Lavender’s blood, staring at her. He smiles, starts forward... </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> NO!</sp>
            <stage>Hermione’s wand flashes. A DEAFENING BLAST. Greyback takes it straight to the
                chest, pitches up into the air and drops. Unmoving.</stage>
            <stage>The trio races away from the burning castle. In the distance part of the Dark
                Forest BURNS, trees shedding SPARKS into the sky like scarlet feathers. SHADOWS do
                battle in the distant dark. SCREAMS shatter the night.</stage>
            <stage>A THUNDEROUS SHOCK WAVE as a MONSTROUS GIANT lurches INTO VIEW, swinging one of
                the QUIDDITCH GOALS, the golden ring dripping BLOOD. Seeing the trio, it whips the
                ring down, strafing them with threads of blood, but missing them, narrowly, scooping
                out a massive CHUNK of earth instead. It GROANS in anger, lumbers stupidly off. The
                trio races on.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="STEPS/CLIFF/BOAT HOUSE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER)"> The trio race
                down the steps toward the Boat House. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="BOAT HOUSE - NIGHT"> Harry, Ron and Hermione pick their way
                forward, moving quietly through the eerie light, then stopping within the safety of
                the shadows. They watch:</stage>
            <stage>Voldemort steps INTO VIEW and extends the wand. In the mercurial light, it looks
                like a living thing.</stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Why doesn’t it work for me? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> You have performed extraordinary magic with this wand, my Lord. In the
                last few hours alone -</sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> No! I am extraordinary! But the wand resists me! </sp>
            <stage>Snape studies Voldemort in the half-light, then his eyes shift to Nagini, who
                skims slowly over the wooden floor, circling the two wizards. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> There is no wand more powerful. Ollivander himself said it. Tonight,
                when the boy comes to you, it will not fail you, I am sure. It answers to you and
                you only. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Does it? </sp>
            <stage>Voldemort holds the wand to the wavering light again, his eyes on Snape. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> My Lord? </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> The wand. Does it truly answer tome? </sp>
            <stage>Snape says nothing. For a moment, he and Voldemort stand perfectly still, two
                faces in the darkness, the only sound the lapping of the lake. Harry studies Snape’s
                face -- calm, composed -- then notes the hand concealed behind his back, twitching
                with tension. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> You’re a clever man, Severus. Surely you must know. </sp>
            <stage>Snape remains silent. His gaze shifts to Nagini, still skimming slowly over the
                floor. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Where, Severus? Where does its loyalty lie? </sp>
            <stage>Snape looks away from Nagini, sees Voldemort staring at him. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> With you, of course, my Lord. </sp>
            <stage>Voldemort stares long at Snape, then, finally speaks: </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> The Elder Wand cannot serve me properly, Severus, because I am not
                its true master. VOLDEMORT <stage>CONT'D</stage> The Elder Wand belongs to thewizard who
                killed its last owner. Ollivander was quite explicit about that. You killed
                Dumbledore, Severus. While youlive, the Elder Wand cannot be truly mine. Snape
                stares at Voldemort, then his eyes shift to Nagini, still circling. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> My Lord -</sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> You have been a good and faithful servant, Severus.</sp>
            <stage>Voldemort raises the wand, points it at Snape’s throat. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> But only I can live forever...</sp>
            <stage>Voldemort sweeps his arm away, turning the wand on Nagini. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Kill.</sp>
            <stage>Snape’s eyes shift... meet the snake’s. The snake strikes. Harry’s SCREAM is
                swallowed by Snape’s own. Voldemort runs a finger along the wand, eyeing it with
                wonder, transfixed, then turns away. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Nagini! Come!</sp>
            <stage>He sweeps from the room, toward the lake’s quivering darkness, the giant snake
                slithering after. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="BOAT HOUSE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Harry rushes forward,
                into the strange, wavering light, then stops in horror, watching Snape’s blood run
                like syrup over the weathered boards toward him. Ron bumps past, heading in the
                direction Voldemort took. Hermione pauses by Harry. Harry kneels by Snape. He lays
                his fingers upon the bloody wound at his neck, but it’s no use. Snape’s eyes shift
                and, briefly, look deep into Harry’s. And then he begins to... Cry. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Take them... </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks confused, hesitant. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Take them!</sp>
            <stage>Snape’s face SHUDDERS softly and his tears TRANSFORM, from clear water to SILVERY
                BLUE. Harry reacts to the color. He’s seen it before... Suddenly Snape grabs his
                collar, pulls him close. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Please.</sp>
            <stage>Snape holds Harry captive briefly, then drops back to the floor. Harry blinks,
                shaken. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Give me something! Quickly! A flask! Anything. </sp>
            <stage>Instantly, Hermione CONJURES a flask from thin air. Hands trembling, Harry
                presses it to Snape’s ashen cheek, letting the fluid flow within. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> They are the same... </sp>
            <stage>Harry searches Snape’s face, trying to decipher his words. Snape stares at Harry
                in wonder, lost in his eyes, then his pupils dilate, his voice trailing off. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> You have your mother’s eyes... </sp>
            <stage>Snape’s face goes slack. Harry shivers. Ron reappears. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> He’s gone. The snake too. </sp>
            <stage>Just then the sound of THUNDER, like a GATHERING STORM, engulfs them. The joists
                of the shack GROAN, as if in agony. The entire room begins to tremble. Ron yanks
                aboard from the window and the trio peers out. As in the Enchanted Ceiling before, a
                face appears in the dark clouds above. And then VOLDEMORT’S VOICE ECHOES: </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT "><stage>V.O.</stage> You have fought valiantly... but in vain. I do
                not wish this. Every drop of magical blood spilled is a terrible waste. I therefore command my forces to
                retreat. In their absence, dispose of your dead with dignity. Treat your injured.
                    <stage>a beat</stage> Harry Potter, I speak now directly to you. On this night
                you have allowed your friends to die for you rather than face me yourself. There is
                no greater dishonor. Join me in the Forbidden Forest and confront your fate. Should
                you do so I give my word that no other life will be lost on this night. You have one
                hour. If, at the end of that time, you have not given yourself up, then I shall
                punish every last man, woman and child who tries to conceal you from me. The joist
                trembles one last time, then the ambient sounds of the night return. The clouds
                separate, become just clouds. Ron YELLS: </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Never! Do you hear me! NEVER! </sp>
            <stage>Hermione places her hand on the nape of his neck, glances at Harry. He gazes down
                at Snape’s still body one last time, then at the FLASK in his hand. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS -GROUNDS - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> SMOKE drifts from the
                battered castle. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD - SAME TIME - NIGHT"> Deserted. The flagstone stained
                with blood, strewn with broken wands. The trio stands looking. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Where is everyone? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="ENTRANCE HALL - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> TRACKING BEHIND the trio.
                Ron walks ahead, toward the Great Hall. Puts his hands to the doors... pushes them
                open. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GREAT HALL - REVERSE ON TRIO - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> ...
                poised on the threshold, looking in. </stage>
            <stage>THEIR POV Triage. The House tables have been pushed to the walls. The injured
                stand in groups, arms slung over one another, waiting to be treated by MADAM
                POMFREY. Filch’s arm gushes blood. Flitwick’s face is laced with GASHES.</stage>
            <stage>Harry stands in the doorway, taking it all in, as if some invisible force
                prevents him from going further, his face a mask as he views the DEAD laid out in
                the middle of the Hall, among them Remus and Tonks, their blood-stained fingers
                clumsily intertwined. A heartbreaking SOB draws his gaze to George, who kneels over
                a familiar body, tears dripping from his eyes. Beside Harry, he hears a GASP --
                Hermione -- but he doesn’t turn, his eyes instead lost on Ginny, puffy-eyed and
                pale, standing alongside a distraught Arthur and Molly. Ron comes INTO VIEW then,
                having left Harry in the entryway to join his family. As he drapes his arm over
                George, drawing his brother into a limp embrace, the lifeless body comes INTO VIEW:
                Fred.</stage>
            <stage>Hermione glances back at Harry briefly before joining the Weasleys. Seeing her,
                Ginny begins to cry, burying her face in Hermione’s shoulder. Gently, slowly,
                Hermione strokes Ginny’s copper hair, over and over, murmuring something
                softly.</stage>
            <stage>For a moment, Harry stands, hung in the doorway, then theGreat Hall seems to fly
                away from him, to grow smaller, to shrink as he reels backward, stumbling
                away...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="HEADMASTER’S OFFICE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Harry flings open
                the cabinet, snatches the PENSIEVE and slams it onto Dumbledore’s old desk. He pries
                the cork from the flask with his teeth, tips the silvery-blue liquid into the basin.
                As the Pensieve swirls, Harry looks up, at the PORTRAITS of PAST HEADMASTERS hanging
                above. All the frames are empty. Harry frowns, disturbed by this, but looks away and
                PLUNGES his FACE into the basin, falling into...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="GODRIC’S HOLLOW - NIGHT (YEARS PAST)"> ... DARKNESS. A JERKY
                POV, MOVING TOWARD the DARK VILLAGE in the distance. FRANTIC BREATHING. We stop.
                Still. A BABY’S CRY separates briefly from the breeze. We CIRCLE ABOUT, leaving the
                POV, and LOCATE a FACE HOVERING in the darkness. It is Snape, chest rising and
                falling. Stricken. Concerned. We GO TO BLACK... </stage>
            <stage>Then... Lily...</stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE "><stage>O.S.</stage> Lily! </sp>
            <sp who="#PETUNIAEVANS "><stage>O.S.</stage> Come out of there! Now! FADE IN: </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="WEEDY FIELD - DAY"> LILY EVANS emerges from some brush, a FLOWER
                upon her palm, opening and closing its petals like some bizarre oyster. Her sister
                PETUNIA stares, then KNOCKS the flower away. </stage>
            <sp who="#PETUNIAEVANS"> We’re going home.</sp>
            <stage>Petunia takes Lily’s arm, turns -- and stops. A SKINNY BOY (YOUNG SNAPE) sits
                beneath a tree, watching them. Without a word, he opens his hand and a LEAF FLUTTERS
                from his palm like a butterfly, circling Lily once, then drifting up and away. Lily
                smiles, charmed. Petunia eyes the boy fearfully, then pulls Lily away. The boy
                watches them go. As Lily glances back... We GO TO BLACK...FADE IN</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="POTTER HOUSE - GODRIC’S HOLLOW - NIGHT (YEARS PAST)"> Snape
                moves through a dark garden, his face like stone. He eyes the door ahead, hanging
                from its hinges. He peers up to the WINDOW above. The baby’s CRY rises again. His
                eyes glitter. He moves on, disappears inside.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="RIVER (SPINNER’S END) - DAY"> Lily and the boy lie together,
                staring up at the sky. </stage>
            <sp who="#YOUNGSNAPE"> She’s jealous. Because she’s ordinary and you’re special. </sp>
            <sp who="#LILYEVANS"> That’s mean. </sp>
            <sp who="#YOUNGSNAPE"> It’s true. You know so yourself.</sp>
            <stage>Snape turns his head, notes the frown knitted across Lily’s brow. He peers back
                up, staring hard at the tree limb above. The leaves begin to TREMBLE, then BURST
                FREE, fluttering like a cloud of butterflies. Lily watches impassively and then --
                slowly -- smiles, shifting her gaze to another branch. Seconds later, those leaves
                burst free and the two fluttering veils pass back and forth high overhead, merging
                briefly, then separating, again and again. Lily LAUGHS --a beautiful sound -- and
                the HISS of a TRAIN ENGINE is heard. The leaves turning, we - DISSOLVE TO: </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="PLATFORM NINE AND THREE-QUARTERS - MORNING"> ... SMOKE, drifting
                from the Hogwarts Express. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="HOGWARTS EXPRESS - COMPARTMENT - MORNING"> The boy peers out the
                window, watching Lily and Petunia on the platform ARGUING, their VOICES MUTED.
                Finally, Lily turns, dashing for the train in tears. The boy straightens up, running
                the flat of his hand over his lank hair. Moments later... Lily comes up the aisle,
                eyes stinging. She stops, seeing him. They stare at one another and then, finally,
                she steps inside the compartment, and sits down. The boy reaches over, pulls down
                the blind, WIPING the SCREEN and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GREAT HALL - NIGHT"> ... we emerge from the darkness of the
                SORTING HAT, sitting upon a stool in the candlelit Hall, House tables aglow with a
                sea of rapt faces. Two boys --SIRIUS BLACK and JAMES POTTER --sit together at the
                Gryffindor table, watching as... A YOUNGER McGONAGALL sweeps the hat from the stool
                and calls out a name. James Potter watches Lily smile nervously at the boy next to
                her (Snape), then rise and make her way to the top of the Hall. As McGonagall lowers
                the hat over Lily’s brow, James watches intently, waiting. Finally, McGonagall
                speaks and all those around James CHEER. He merely smiles, watching Lily approach.
                He gives Sirius a nudge, to move over, making a space forLily. As she takes her
                seat, she glances across the hall to the boy, who watches impassively as James
                reaches out his hand to introduce himself to Lily. We GO TO BLACK... FADE IN:
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="POTTER HOUSE - STAIRCASE -NIGHT (YEARS PAST"> Snape mounts the
                stairs, peering upward in the darkness to the landing above and the open bedroom
                door beyond. As his eyes become level with the next floor, he sees a WAND lying
                there. As he reaches the top and turns, he sees JAMES POTTER -- the man -- lying
                dead in the middle of the hallway. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD - DAY"> SNOWFLAKES FALL LIKE BUTTERFLIES. Lily walks,
                hugging her books, as the boy harangues her. He looks driven by desperation and
                perhaps because of it, says something too sharp. She looks up at him, eyes stinging
                with tears, then turns away. The boy starts to call after her, regret in his eyes,
                then sees James waiting on the other side of the courtyard. As she reaches him, they
                turn and together exit the courtyard. The boy turns away, his own eyes stinging with
                tears, then closes his eyes and all goes... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HILLTOP - NIGHT"> ... BLACK... dotted by stars. A windswept
                hilltop comes INTO VIEW, desolate but for a few LEAFLESS TREES. The adult Snape
                turns on the spot, breathing heavily, his expression haunted and cheerless as his
                gaze sweeps the darkness. The WIND RISES suddenly and a JAGGED JET of WHITE LIGHT
                stitches the night, sending Snape’s wand flying and dropping him to his knees. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> No! Don’t kill me! </sp>
            <stage>A SNAPPING of ROBES precedes Dumbledore as he APPARATES INTO VIEW. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> That wasn’t my intention. </sp>
            <stage>Snape stares fearfully at him. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Stand up, Severus. I haven’t much time. What message do you bring
                from Lord Voldemort this time? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"><stage>rising</stage> None. I come on my own account. I come with a...
                request. Dumbledore’s eyes flicker briefly with interest. He studies Snape’s fearful
                face. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Is this about the Prophecy? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> How much did you relay? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Only what I heard. But now... he thinks it refers to her. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> The Prophecy did not refer to a woman. It spoke of a boy born at
                the end of July -</sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Yes! But he thinks it’s her son! He intends to hunt them down now! To
                kill them! </sp>
            <stage>Dumbledore eyes Snape craftily. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> If she means so much to you, surely Lord Voldemort would spare
                her in exchange for the boy. I have asked. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You disgust me. You would sacrifice the life of an innocent child
                over a schoolboy crush? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> She’s more than that! She’s different! Beautiful. Kind. <stage>looking
                    away</stage> Hide them all. I beg you. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> And should I do so, what will you give me in return, Severus?
                Anything. </sp>
            <stage> The wind rises again, the TREES TREMBLING and...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="HEADMASTER’S OFFICE - LATE AFTERNOON"> ... Snape’s FIST STRIKES
                Dumbledore’s desk, upsetting a tiny TIN METRONOME. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> You said you would keep her safe! </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Lily and James put their faith in the wrong person. Rather like
                you, Severus. Snape reels, staring miserably at the SLATE SKY beyond the windows.
                Dumbledore studies him cunningly. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> The boy survives. Snape’s eyes shift. Regard Dumbledore. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> He has her eyes. DON’T! </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> If you loved Lily Evans, Severus. If you truly loved her. Then
                your way is clear. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> He doesn’t need protection. The Dark Lord has gone -</sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> The Dark Lord will return. And the boy will be in terrible danger
                when he does. </sp>
            <stage>Snape stares once more at the sky beyond. Then, softly: </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> No one can know. Your word. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> My word that I shall never reveal the best of you, Severus? If
                you insist. </sp>
            <stage>Snape continues to stare at the sky. We DRIFT TO it. It FILLS the SCREEN and we
                TILT DOWN... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - DAY"> ... TO Snape and Dumbledore walking. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> He exhibits no measurable talent. His arrogance rivals even his
                father’s. And he seems to relish his fame. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Sometimes we see what we expect to see, Severus. Other teachers
                indicate the boy is modest, likeable and while no prodigy, possesses above-average
                gifts. Personally, I find him rather engaging. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> You see what you want to see. </sp>
            <stage>Severus walks on. Dumbledore smiles with amusement. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Perhaps. Oh. Severus. <stage>as he stops</stage> Keep an eye on
                Professor Quirrell, won’t you?</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="HEADMASTER’S OFFICE - NIGHT"> A FEVERISH, SEMICONSCIOUS
                Dumbledore raises his left hand and tips a GOBLET of GOLDEN POTION over his lips
                while Snape ministers to his right hand, which is BLACKENED. A RING lies upon the
                desk before them. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Why did you put it on? Surely you realized it carried a curse. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I was... foolish... greedy... </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Drink the rest. It will contain the curse to the hand for the time
                being. </sp>
            <stage>Dumbledore’s eyes open, examine his damaged fingers. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> For the time being? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> It will spread. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> How long? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Maybe a year. </sp>
            <stage>Dumbledore nods, smiles. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Well, this makes matters much more straightforward. </sp>
            <stage>Snape studies Dumbledore briefly, looks away. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Do not ignore me, Severus. Was it not you who told me of Lord
                Voldemort’s plan to have the Malfoy boy murder me? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> It is not expected that he will succeed. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> But should he fail, one would presume the Dark Lord will turn
                to... you. </sp>
            <stage>Snape does not respond. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You must agree. </sp>
            <stage>Snape stares in horror at Dumbledore. Dumbledore nods. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Yes. You must be the one to kill me, Severus. It is the only way.
                Only then will the Dark Lord trust you completely. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> You ask too much. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"><stage>thundering</stage> Too much! Nothing I could ask is too
                much. You know what is at stake! You more than anyone! Snape says nothing.
                Dumbledore sits back, painfully studies his hand. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> There will come a time when HarryPotter must be told something.
                But you must wait until Voldemort is at his most vulnerable. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Tell him what? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> On the night Lord Voldemort went to Godric’s Hollow to kill
                Harry, and Lily Potter cast herself between them, the curse rebounded. When that
                happened, a part of Lord Voldemort’s soul latched itself onto the only living thing
                it could find: Harry himself. </sp>
            <stage>Snape stares in disbelief. Dumbledore nods. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> There’s a reason Harry can speak with snakes. There’s a reason he
                can look into Lord Voldemort’s mind. A part of Lord Voldemort lives inside him. </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> So when the time comes, the boy must die. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Yes. And Voldemort himself must do it. That is essential.</sp>
            <stage>Snape nods, pondering all of this. His voice is bitter. </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> You’ve kept him alive so that he can die at the proper moment. You’ve
                been raising him like a pig for slaughter. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> But this is touching, Severus. Don’t tell me you’ve grown to care
                for the boy?</sp>
            <stage>Snape eyes Dumbledore fiercely, then: </stage>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Expecto Patronum!</sp>
            <stage>A blast of LIGHT bursts from his wand, soars out the window: a SILVER DOE. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Lily. After all this time? </sp>
            <sp who="#SNAPE"> Always... </sp>
            <stage>We GO TO BLACK...</stage>
            <stage>FADE IN: </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="PORTER HOUSE - BEDROOM - NIGHT (YEARS PAST"> In the f.g., a BABY
                FIDGETS in its crib. We see Snape enter the room, glance at the baby, then down
                toward the floor. He stands, utterly still... then his face creases with pain. Lily
                lies in profile, eyes open but empty, staring toward the ceiling. Her chest is
                still. Snape leans down and, cradling her, begins to weep... </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "><stage>V.O.</stage> The irony of course, Severus, is that -- in
                the end -- you and the boy desire the same thing...</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="HEADMASTER’S OFFICE - NIGHT"> Harry emerges, dripping, from the
                Pensieve and stares at his REFLECTION in the window opposite, watching as the liquid
                runs like tears from his face, then evaporates. Gently, he touches the center of his
                chest. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> The castle is eerily
                quiet as Harry walks, the PORTRAITS he passes EMPTY. As he reaches the end of the
                corridor, he turns and stops. In the SHADOWS of an ALCOVE, Hermione murmurs to Ron,
                their faces close. For a long moment, Harry simply watches them. Then, as if sensing
                his presence, Hermione turns. Instantly, she runs to him. Ron follows. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Where’ve you been? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> We thought you’d gone to the forest, we thought you might be -</sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’m going there now. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Are you mad! No! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s... meant to be. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Rubbish! You can’t just give yourself up to him -</sp>
            <stage>Hermione squeezes Ron’s arm, silencing him. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What is it, Harry? What is it you know?</sp>
            <stage>Ron studies her face, then looks back to Harry.</stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> There’s a reason I can... hear them -- the Horcruxes. </sp>
            <stage>Hermione begins to shake her head, not wanting to believe. Harry simply nods,
                touches the center of his chest. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I think I’ve known for awhile. <stage>studying her</stage> I think
                you’ve known too. Hermione stands still, miserable. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I’ll go with you. I’ll -</sp>
            <stage>She falters hopelessly as a single tear traces her cheek. Harry reaches out,
                wipes it away. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Kill the snake. Kill the snake and then it’s just him. Then it will be
                over. </sp>
            <stage>He turns then, leaving them. Ron and Hermione stand silently, watching every step
                he takes until he reaches the end... and is gone. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="ENTRANCE HALL - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> As Harry descends,
                Neville and Oliver Wood appear in theEntrance Hall far below, carrying the body of a
                smallish boy: Nigel. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLIVERWOOD"> I’ll take him from here. </sp>
            <stage>Oliver throws Nigel over his shoulder, enters the Great Hall. Neville watches
                them go, looking, for a moment, very old. Then, wearily, he turns, heading back
                outside. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS -GROUNDS - NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> In the distance,
                SHADOWS collect the dead, too occupied with their grim task to notice Harry. He
                stares straight ahead, just walking, until a VOICE tugs his ear: </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> It’s all right. We’re going to get you inside.</sp>
            <stage>Ginny crouches over the tiny Ravenclaw girl, who is CRYING. </stage>
            <sp who="#YOUNGGIRL"> I kept calling. No one came. </sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Don’t worry. I won’t leave you. I promise.</sp>
            <stage>Ginny strokes the sobbing girl’s hair, her own face haunted by sorrow. Harry
                studies her, moved, then continues on. A moment later, Ginny turns, looks to the
                place where he was standing... but finds only darkness. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="FORBIDDEN FOREST - NIGHT"> Harry reaches the Forest’s edge.
                Within, further on, he can see Dementors drifting within the trees. Harry starts to
                enter, then pauses, reaches into his pocket and removes the Snitch. Eyes the words
                etched upon it: “I open at the close.” Harry frowns, then closes his eyes, brings
                the metal orb to his lips. His fingers tremble, then lowers his hand, watching as
                the metal shell FALLS AWAY to reveal... the RESURRECTION STONE. A JAGGED CRACK runs
                down its center, along the line representing the Elder Wand. The TRIANGLE and
                CIRCLE, representing the Cloak and Stone, are faintly visible. Harry stares at it,
                then closes his eyes and begins to roll the Stone over in his hand. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"><stage>murmuring</stage> Once. Twice. Thrice... Harry stands for a
                moment and then, slowly, opens his eyes. Reacts. FOUR PEOPLE stand within the
                Forest: JAMES POTTER, SIRIUS BLACK, REMUS LUPIN and LILY POTTER. Lily eyes him
                lovingly and beckons him forth. As if in a dream, Harry drifts through the trees,
                stops before her. </sp>
            <sp who="#LILYPOTTER"> You’ve been so brave, sweetheart. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Why are you here? All of you? </sp>
            <sp who="#LILYPOTTER"> We never left, dear. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Does it hurt? Dying? </sp>
            <sp who="#SIRIUSBLACK"> Quicker than falling asleep. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> And he will want it to be quick. </sp>
            <sp who="#JAMESPOTTER"> You’re nearly there, son. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’m sorry. I didn’t want any of you to die for me. And Remus, your
                son... </sp>
            <sp who="#LUPIN"> Others will tell him what his mother and father died for. Someday
                he’ll understand... </sp>
            <stage>A CHILL BREEZE shakes the trees. Harry looks ahead. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You’ll stay with me? </sp>
            <sp who="#JAMESPOTTER"> Until the end. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He won’t be able to see you? </sp>
            <stage>Sirius shakes his head, gestures to Harry’s heart. </stage>
            <sp who="#SIRIUSBLACK"> No. We’re here, you see. </sp>
            <stage>Harry turns to his mother. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Stay close to me. </sp>
            <sp who="#LILYPOTTER"> Always... </sp>
            <stage>Harry glances back, toward the Forest’s Edge, takes a last look at the castle in
                the distance, then sets off. Dozens of DEMENTORS drift amongst the smoking trees,
                but his guides insulate him, and they merely peel away. Harry walks on, his legs
                driving him, until LIGHT splinters the trees ahead, and a CLEARING comes INTO VIEW.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="FORBIDDEN FOREST - CLEARING - NIGHT"> A FIRE burns, its light
                flickering over the throng ofDEATH EATERS present. Lucius and NARCISSA MALFOY, weary
                with fear, sit apart. BELLATRIX paces in and out of the shadows, MUTTERING madly.
                And then there is Voldemort, who stands with his head bowed, his skeletal hands
                folded over the Elder Wand. Nagini lays in a heavy coil at his feet. Yaxley enters
                the clearing. </stage>
            <sp who="#YAXLEY"> No sign of him, my Lord. </sp>
            <stage>Voldemort nods, unmoving. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> I thought he would come. I was, it seems... mistaken. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You weren’t. </sp>
            <stage>All eyes shift to Harry, standing at the clearing’s edge. He lets the
                Resurrection Stone tumble from his fingers and James, Sirius, Lupin and, lastly,
                Lily --all vanish. Harry steps into the firelight. </stage>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> HARRY! NO! WHAT’RE YEH DOIN’ ‘ERE! </sp>
            <stage>HAGRID is trussed to a tree. The branches shake violently as he tries to break
                free. </stage>
            <sp who="#YAXLEY"> Quiet!</sp>
            <stage>He flicks his wand and Hagrid slumps, goes silent. A CACKLING LAUGH rises on the
                air and Harry turns, sees Bellatrix glancing eagerly from Harry to Voldemort.
                Voldemort takes a step forward and the flickering flames wash over his pale skin. He
                tilts his head to the side. A smile curls on his mouth. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Harry Potter. The Boy Who Lived. Come to die.</sp>
            <stage>Nagini HISSES behind her protective guard of Death Eaters. Harry’s gaze shifts to
                her when Voldemort raises his wand. Scarlet flickers in his eyes. Then a BOLT of
                GREEN LIGHT shatters the night and all is...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="KING’S CROSS - DAY"> Gone. All but a BRIGHT WHITE MIST.</stage>
            <stage>Harry lies face down. For a long moment. Finally, he stirs, sits up. Touches his
                face. His glasses are gone. He peers into the mist. Nothing. But somewhere, out
                there, in the mist, is a SOFT THUMPING.</stage>
            <stage>He stands. Peers up. A DOMED GLASS ROOF hovers -- familiar. The THUMPING
                persists. Unnerving. Harry squints into the mist.</stage>
            <stage>Moving, the THUMPING growing LOUDER. Up ahead, a SMALL MASS quivers. Harry
                slows... recoils. A thing -- like a small naked child -- lies SHUDDERING on the
                ground, its skin raw and rough. Harry leans close... </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You cannot help. </sp>
            <stage>Harry spins, finds Dumbledore standing within the mist. At the sight of Harry,
                Dumbledore beams and spreads his arms wide. His hand is whole, no longer damaged. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Harry. You wonderful boy. You brave, brave man. Let us walk. </sp>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - HARRY AND DUMBLEDORE Walking. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir, this, is this... I mean, forgive me, but you are dead, aren’t
                you, sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Oh, yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Then... I’m dead too? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Ah. That is the question, isn’t it? On the whole I think not. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Not? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Not. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But I didn’t defend myself. I let him kill me. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> And that will, I think, have made all the difference. I suspect
                you now realize that you and Voldemort have been connected by something other than
                fate since that night in Godric’s Hollow all those years ago, Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It’s true, isn’t it, sir? A bit of him lives in me, doesn’t it? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Did. It was just destroyed only moments ago by none other than
                Voldemort himself. </sp>
            <stage>Harry plays his fingers over his sternum. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You were the seventh Horcrux, Harry; the Horcrux he never meant
                to make. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And you knew this? That’s why you were certain I wouldn’t die? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Certain? No. Little is certain in this world, Harry. Call it an
                educated guess. </sp>
            <stage>Dumbledore smiles. Harry ponders this, then, deep in the mist, the THUMPING
                returns. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Professor, is that -- ? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Something beyond either of our help. </sp>
            <stage>Harry ponders his surroundings. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Exactly where are we, sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I was going to ask you that. Where would you say that we are? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It looks like King’s Cross station -- only a lot cleaner. And without
                the trains. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> King’s Cross! Is that right? Well, this is, as they say, your
                party. </sp>
            <stage>Harry looks perplexed by this, but Dumbledore only smiles. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir, why didn’t you just tell me about the Deathly Hallows? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You will have to forgive me, Harry. You see... I didn’t trust
                you.</sp>
            <stage>Harry stares at him. looks troubled. For the first time, Dumbledore </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I feared that you would make the same mistake I made, that you
                would be intoxicated by the power the Hallows promise their possessor. But I crave
                your pardon, Harry. It’s clear to me now, as it should have been all along, that you
                are the better man. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir -</sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You are the worthy possessor of the Hallows, Harry, not me. I was
                fit to own the Elder Wand, because I took it not for gain, but to save others from
                it. But I took the Stone because I longed to recall someone who has long been at
                peace and for that I paid with my life. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You wanted to see Ariana again, didn’t you, sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Yes. </sp>
            <stage>Harry ponders this, then frowns. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I used the Stone as well, sir, only a little while ago when I entered
                the Forest. I saw my mum and dad, and Sirius and Lupin... </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> True. But ask yourself this: were you calling them? Or were they
                calling you? </sp>
            <stage>Harry studies Dumbledore, whose expression remains serene. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>looking him in the eye</stage> You are the true master of death, Harry,
                because the true master does not seek to run away from death. He accepts that he
                must die, and understands that there are far, far worse things in the living
                world.</sp>
            <stage>For a moment, they stand in silence. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’ve got to go back, haven’t I? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> That is up to you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I’ve got a choice? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Oh yes. We are in King’s Cross, you say? I think, should you so
                decide, you would be able to, let’s say, board a train. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And where would it take me? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> On. </sp>
            <stage>Harry nods. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Voldemort’s got the Elder Wand. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> True. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And the snake lives. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> And I’ve nothing to kill it with. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> ‘Help will always be given at Hogwarts to those who ask for it.’ </sp>
            <stage>Harry glances at him. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I have always prized my ability to turn a phrase -- words are, in
                my not so humble opinion, our most inexhaustible source of magic, capable both of
                inflicting injury and remedying it. But I would --in this case -- amend my original
                statement to this: <stage>leaning close</stage> Help will always be given at
                Hogwarts to those who most deserve it... <stage>leaning back</stage> Assuming
                circumstances in the main are favorable to such an outcome, of course. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> With all due respect, sir, I think what we need here is a miracle. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I’ve never put much stock in miracles, Harry. On the other hand,
                I can attest wholly to the extensive advantages of a related phenomenon. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Which would be, sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Luck.</sp>
            <stage>Harry studies Dumbledore’s face, then peers back into the mist again. The
                THUMPING continues, more faintly. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Do not pity the dead, Harry. Pity the living and, above all,
                those who live without love. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir, my mother’s Patronus. It was a doe, wasn’t it? Just like
                Professor Snape’s. Curious, don’t you think? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Actually, if I think about it... it doesn’t seem curious at all.
                    <stage>a smile</stage> I’ll be going now, Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Professor. </sp>
            <stage>As Dumbledore stops, Harry gestures vaguely. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Is this real? Or has this been happening inside my head? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Of course it is happening inside your head, Harry. But why should
                that mean that it is not real? </sp>
            <stage>Dumbledore beams as the mist thickens around him, then swallows him altogether... </stage>
            <sp who="#NARCISSA "><stage>O.S.</stage>
                <stage>in a whisper</stage> Is he alive...? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="FORBIDDEN FOREST - CLEARING - NIGHT"> Harry lies facedown,
                glasses askew. He OPENS his eyes a millimeter, finds Narcissa’s face swimming in the
                dawn’s muted light, eyeing him with a strange intensity: the question, he realizes,
                was posed to him. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> My lord, let me help you -</sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> I do not require assistance.</sp>
            <stage>Across the clearing, Voldemort rises shakily, Bellatrix at his elbow. The Death
                Eaters watch, stirring uncertainly. Voldemort glances toward Narcissa, toward Harry.
                Bellatrix detects the wary glint in his eyes. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> The boy. Is he dead?</sp>
            <stage>Harry’s eyes shift, meet Narcissa’s once again. Something in her expression... He
                closes his eyes. She places her fingers over his heart, WHISPERS: </stage>
            <sp who="#NARCISSA"> Is he alive? Draco? </sp>
            <stage>Harry hesitates and then... nods -- so subtly it’s barely perceptible. Narcissa
                withdraws her hand, turns to where Bellatrix stands alongside Voldemort. Nods. The
                Death Eaters CHEER. Hagrid HOWLS in misery. The news seems to rejuvenate Voldemort.
                A fierce glint returns to his eyes. His stature grows. He eyes the Elder Wand... and
                smiles. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD -NIGHT (MOMENTS LATER"> Neville, battle-scared and
                weary, perches atop a fallen statue in the chill morning air. Reaching into his
                pocket, he removes his WAND, holds it to the light... and watches the TIP drop like
                the head of a drowsy child. BROKEN. He tosses it away. </stage>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - NEVILLE - NIGHT Neville kicks through the rubble. One could
                reconstruct the history of Hogwarts from the detritus before him: spell books,
                trophies, potion boxes. But Neville’s expression remains stoic, unsentimental. He’s
                seen too much in the last 12 hours. CLOSE ON THE PEAK OF A HAT Neville crouches
                down, studies it. Reaching out, he wiggles it free, slaps it against his thigh to
                chase the dust. The Sorting Hat. He ponders it, regarding its ragged surface, singed
                and torn, then pops it on his head, a beaten jester. Again, his face remains blank.
                He squints, peering vaguely into the distance. As he gaze falls on the bridge, he
                stops. An odd procession approaches.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="VIADUCT - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Hagrid lurches forward
                awkwardly, CLUTCHING a BODY in his arms, ropes extending in three directions from
                his neck as a trio of Death Eaters -- one in front, two behind -- jerk him along
                like a tethered beast. From Hagrid, Neville’s gaze drifts to Bellatrix and Narcissa
                and then to Voldemort himself -- dark, fierce --before settling on the most
                unnerving sight: a giant wending snake. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD - CONTINUOUS ACTION - NIGHT"> Suddenly a WHISPER fills
                Neville’s ears. </stage>
            <sp who="#SORTINGHAT"> Don’t despair, Longbottom. I put you in Gryffindor for good
                reason... </sp>
            <stage>The Hat COUGHS then, raining dust over Neville’s brow and he whips it off,
                studies it warily. </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY "><stage>O.S.</stage> Who’s that? Neville turns, sees that Ginny has
                come out onto the broken steps and is staring at the procession. </sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> ... Hagrid’s carrying? </sp>
            <stage>Neville just stares, mute. Her eyes shift then, to him, and he sees they are
                glistening faintly. Her voice, when she speaks, nearly gets lost in the morning
                breeze. </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Neville, who is that? </sp>
            <stage>Before he can answer, others begin to spill out of the castle. Luna and Seamus.
                Cho. Arthur Weasley. Ron and Hermione emerge and, seeing the procession... know.
                Hermione draws a sharp breath and something about it -- the unadulterated sense of
                loss contained within it -- causes those around her to look and know as well. </stage>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> What’s going on here, Neville?</sp>
            <stage>Neville starts to speak but falters and then, simply because he can’t bear to
                look at Ginny’s face and the faces of the others looking to him for something,
                anything, he turns his gaze to the Hat dangling in his hand. And as he does,
                something GLINTS within. As he stares... we - CUT TO: </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="VIADUCT - PROCESSION - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAWN"> ... Voldemort
                and the others, moving with them, as they draw near. Voldemort surveys the ruins of
                the castle and the beaten posture of the throng assembled upon its steps. He smiles
                faintly, with cruel satisfaction. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Behold, Nagini. Our work is done. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAWN"> Ron, Hermione, Ginny and
                the others stand silently as the procession comes to a halt before them. All eyes
                drift to Hagrid and what lays in his arms. </stage>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> No... NO! </sp>
            <stage>Ginny’s primal cry echoes over the grounds as she rushes towards Voldemort, but
                Arthur steps between and wraps his daughter in his arms, letting her struggle
                briefly before pulling her tighter, closer, safer. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> SILENCE! </sp>
            <stage>Voldemort points his wand to the sky with a CRACK. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Stupid girl. You cry for that? </sp>
            <stage>Voldemort gestures to the body lying still in Hagrid’s arms. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"><stage>addressing all</stage> Tell me. These last few hours -- as
                you collected the dead and tended your wounded -- was he by your side? Voldemort
                surveys the throng, who stand mute. He nods, as if their silence were answer enough. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> While your hands ran dark with the blood of mothers and sons,
                fathers and daughters, brothers and sisters, his were clasped in prayer -- but it
                was a prayer for one and one only. While you battled courageously, until you could
                no longer will yourself to stand, he had long since fallen to his knees. While you
                cursed me until your voices grew ragged, he begged me for mercy in a voice as meek
                as a child’s.</sp>
            <stage>Voldemort’s eyes narrow.</stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT">So do not cry for that. He’s not worthy of your tears. And do not
                despair of his betrayal. You were never in his heart. Not for one single solitary
                beat. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Liar!</sp>
            <stage>Voldemort flicks his wand and Ron drops to his knees, grimacing in pain.
                Voldemort gestures to him. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Did you not hear me! Harry Potter is dead! From this day forward,
                you put your faith in me or suffer the consequences. HARRY POTTER IS DEAD!</sp>
            <stage>Nagini HISSES MADLY as Voldemort, looking a touch mad himself, rakes his eyes
                over the students and staff. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Now is the time to declare yourself.</sp>
            <stage>There is a nervous MURMUR among the crowd. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> Draco... </sp>
            <stage>Draco looks up, sees his father summon him forth with a short nod. He hesitates.
                Lucius smiles thinly. </stage>
            <sp who="#LUCIUS"> Draco, don’t be stupid -</sp>
            <sp who="#NARCISSA"> Come, Draco. </sp>
            <stage>Her tone is quiet, but absolute. Draco looks into her eyes, then ducks his head
                and steps forward, avoiding the baleful glances directed his way as he crosses the
                gulf between factions. Ron mutters poisonously as he passes. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> He saved your life. </sp>
            <stage>Draco falters briefly, stung, then joins his mother. She hands him a WAND,
                Harry’s wand. He stares at it bleakly. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Well done, Draco. Who will be next? Hm? Come now, don’t be
                shy.</sp>
            <stage>We TRAVEL OVER FACES, weary but resolved, eyes burning with defiance, then LAND
                ON Neville, chin on chest, gaze to the ground. As the Sorting Hat rocks gently in
                his hand, something GLINTS within again, and a QUIVERING PARABOLA OF REFLECTED LIGHT
                dances above his brow. He steps forward. Stunned, the others watch Neville --
                blackened with soot, Sorting Hat in hand -- limp to a halt in front of Voldemort,
                who regards him with amusement. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Well, I must say, I’d hoped for better. Is this truly the best
                Hogwarts has to offer? </sp>
            <stage>The Death Eaters laugh. Bellatrix grins in cruel amusement. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Who might you be, young man? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Neville Longbottom. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Well, welcome, Neville. I’m sure we can find a place for you in
                our ranks. </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Someone has to do the washing. </sp>
            <stage>The Death Eaters ROAR. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Now, now, Bellatrix. Let’s not underestimate our young friend. By
                stepping forward, he lives to see another day... </sp>
            <stage>Voldemort’s eyes shift, regard those standing before him. The implication of his
                statement is not lost on them. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> I’d like to say something.</sp>
            <stage>Voldemort’s brow furrows vaguely. As he studies Neville, we - CUT TO: HARRY... as
                his eyelids separate ever-so-slightly. HARRY’S POV OF NEVILLE He studies his face
                when... the CURIOUS REFLECTION QUIVERS once again. Harry watches it dance briefly
                across Neville’s cheek before vanishing. Harry’s gaze shifts to the Sorting Hat in
                Neville’s hand, then shifts again, to Nagini. </stage>
            <stage>BACK TO SCENE </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Very well, Neville. I’m sure we’d all be fascinated to hear what
                you have to say. </sp>
            <stage>Neville turns to the others, their weary faces regarding him with confusion,
                suspicion. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> It doesn’t matter that Harry is gone.</sp>
            <stage>A troubled MURMUR ripples through the crowd. </stage>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"><stage>angrily</stage> Stand down, Neville!</sp>
            <stage>Seamus tries to push forward but Ron grips his arm, holds him back, though not
                happily. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> People die every day. Friends. Family. Yes, we lost Harry tonight.
                But he’s still with us, here - <stage>tapping his heart</stage> And so is Fred and
                Remus and Tonks and... all of them. They didn’t die in vain. <stage>turning to
                    Bellatrix</stage> But you will. <stage>to a trio of DeathEaters</stage> And you
                and you and you will. <stage>to Voldemort</stage> And so will you. Because you’re
                wrong. Harry’s heart did beat for us. All of us... </sp>
            <stage>Neville takes a step forward, looks Voldemort in the eye and SPITS. Then he
                reaches into the Sorting Hat. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> This isn’t over.</sp>
            <stage>SCARLET glints in Voldemort’s eyes and he smiles, raising the Elder Wand when
                Neville -- in keen anticipation -- reaches into the Sorting Hat and pulls forth...
                The Sword of Gryffindor. As Voldemort’s wand FIRES, Neville parries and the curse
                REBOUNDS, taking out the QUARTET of DEATH EATERS flanking Bellatrix -- only she is
                quick enough to deflect the curse. As she SCREAMS in FURY, Harry spills from
                Hagrid’s arms. Voldemort wheels wildly in Harry’s direction when: </stage>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> Potter!</sp>
            <stage>Harry turns. Draco’s hand whips forward and -- to Harry’s shock -- tosses him his
                wand. Ron GRINS. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well done, Malfoy! <stage>to himself</stage> Can’t believe I just said
                that.</sp>
            <stage>Wand in hand, Harry turns and -- in one continuous motion -- FIRES on Voldemort.
                Voldemort blocks the spell, eyeing Harry with mild disbelief, then anger.</stage>
            <stage>NAGINI HISSES --as if attuned to Voldemort’s emotions -- and RIBBONS toward
                Harry. As she STRIKES, Harry sidesteps her -- by inches -- then stumbles back and
                counters. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Confringo!</sp>
            <stage>FLAMES run the length of Nagini -- with no effect -- then climb the back of a
                nearby Death Eater and consume him.</stage>
            <stage>Enraged that Harry has attacked Nagini, Voldemort FIRES a VOLLEY of CURSES. Harry
                parries the first, then falls back into a cloister. The stonework EXPLODES all
                around him, creating THREE RAGGED HOLES. He pelts away.</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT/EXT" where="COURTYARD/GREAT HALL ENTRANCE - DAWN"> As Harry arrives at
                the doors to the Great Hall, he finds Ron and Hermione there. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The snake! We’ve got to kill the snake! </sp>
            <stage>Neville, only a few yards off, sword in hand, OVERHEARS. As his eyes shift to
                Voldemort and Nagini. </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Harry! Look out!</sp>
            <stage>Harry wheels, sees Voldemort drawing a bead on him. As Harry begins to raise his
                wand, Neville steps between, brandishing the sword... ... just as Voldemort’s WAND
                BLAZES and Neville’s world explodes. Taking the full brunt of it all, Neville
                grimaces, watching as Voldemort’s spell -- like a CURRENT OF ELECTRICITY --races up
                the sword’s blade to the hilt... ... and PITCHES off his feet and fifty feet back
                into the Great Hall. Harry exchanges a glance with Ron and Hermione. Their faces say
                it all: no one could have survived that. The Entrance Hall EXPLODES with
                COUNTER-FIRE as members of the Order, students and staff return fire. Voldemort
                FLICKS his WAND, the AIR PRICKLING with DISTURBANCE as he SUMMONS a SHIELD of AIR
                insulating himself from attack. As he sweeps forward, he responds with a DEVASTATING
                SERIES of SPELLS and the Entrance Hall QUAKES. Harryturns and dashes... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - DAWN (MOMENTS LATER"> ... up the stairs,
                picking his way through the rubble and limp bodies strewn upon the steps, attempting
                to drawVoldemort -- and Nagini -- away from the others. It works.</stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Nagini! With me!</sp>
            <stage>Voldemort, his cloak swirling like water, the great snake at his heel, strides
                toward the stairs and FIRES. Harry flinches as SHARDS of MARBLE rain down upon him.
                Wheeling, he fires back. Voldemort parries Harry’s spells with frightening ease,
                mounting the steps and firing again and again. Eyes darting frantically, Harry
                blocks the spells with a mixture of skill, instinct and pure luck. He stumbles back,
                FIRING WILDLY. One of his spells skitters down the steps and strikes Nagini. The
                snake HISSES, unharmed but ANGRY. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Leave her!</sp>
            <stage>Voldemort’s eyes glitter with RAGE, as if he himself had been struck by the
                spell. Harry FIRES again, purposely aiming for the snake this time. Voldemort
                counters with palpable FURY, spells CAROMING MADLY up and down the staircase. Harry
                shields his eyes briefly, then looks down and sees... ... a CLOUD OF SMOKE hanging
                over the stairs from Voldemort’s spells, but Voldemort himself is... gone. Harry
                glances about frantically, then WHOOSH! The hairs on the back of Harry’s neck rise.
                He turns. Voldemort materializes at the top of the stairs, fires a RIBBON of FIRE at
                him. Harry counters it, but it is so powerful he can’t deflect it. He stands,
                connected to Voldemort by the rippling ribbon of fire. He stumbles back, the muscles
                in his forearm twitching in pain. He hears a HEAVY ROLLING SOUND, like meat slapping
                a marble table and looks over his shoulder, downwards. Nagini is undulating upward,
                over the steps, toward Harry. As the snake HISSES an oddly SIMILAR SOUND escapes
                Voldemort’s lips as he pushes his advantage. The ribboning flames grow more intense,
                begin to lick the flesh of Harry’s wand hand. Harry glances once more at Nagini who
                draws closer, then back at Voldemort, who stares fiercely at Harry, willing the
                FLAMES down the ribbon of light toward Harry. Harry winces as the flames SINGE the
                HAIR on his knuckles. Then, summoning every bit of strength he’s got, Harry... ...
                breaks the spell, staggering away, as the ribbon of light shoots upward and the
                ceiling above gives way, raining debris onto Nagini. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> I said LEAVE HER!</sp>
            <stage>Harry peers down at the wreckage below, then watches Nagini slither free, her
                thick braids oozing with lacerations, but otherwise unharmed. WOOSH! Harry turns and
                Voldemort VANISHES again, only to... ... reappear seconds later on Harry’s blind
                side. Harry wheels and, in a sweeping motion, sends a CLUSTER of DEBRIS hurling at
                Voldemort. Instantly, Voldemort reaches out his hand and the debris grows smaller as
                it flies toward him, until, as it reaches his hand, it appears to vanish altogether.
                Then he turns his palm upward. SAND runs between his fingers to the floor. Harry
                stands watching, stunned. His eyes meet Voldemort’s. Voldemort’s eyes narrow eerily
                -- in a most unhuman way -- and he... HISSES. Harry stumbles back, freaked out,
                when: </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT">
                <stage>in Parseltongue</stage> Now, my sweet. Now.</sp>
            <stage>Harry turns, sees Nagini, only yards away, rising to strike. He fires
                instinctively, then dashes for the balustrade and leaps... ... into the air... ...
                falling... ... and falling... ... until... ... he lands, on the stone floor below,
                awkwardly, painfully. He glances up, sees Voldemort’s face. Instantly, Voldemort
                flicks his wand and the stone floor around Harry explodes, the surface dancing like
                water. He turns, glances around desperately, then spies... ... a DOOR. Without
                thinking, he pelts towards it and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="THE OXFORD CORRIDOR - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAWN"> ... through,
                into a corridor TEEMING with SMOKE. In the distance, a PATCH of LIGHT drifts oddly
                in the swirling mist, glowing weakly, then is swallowed by the smoke. Far off
                SCREAMS --the cries of battle -- HANG in the air, hollow and distant. Harry moves
                through the mist, feeling his way. The walls shimmer like skin on his periphery,
                barely discernible, melting, lost in shadow. A LOW BEATING rises in Harry’s ears,
                RAPID at first then growing slower and slower as it increases in volume and all
                ambient sound drifts away, revealing the low beating to be... ... the THRUMMING of
                Harry’s heart. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - SAME TIME - DAWN"> Voldemort sweeps down to
                the lower landing and pauses, eyeing the DOOR AHEAD. He glances up, in the direction
                of Nagini --conflicted. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Nagini! </sp>
            <stage>He waits, sees the giant snake begin to wend its way down. Then passes through
                the door. </stage>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - NAGINI - MOVING ... flowing like water ever downward when --THWACK!
                -- a BIT of RUBBLE bounces off her slithering tail. She HISSES, coiling in on
                herself, blunt head darting about warily. </stage>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - LOWER STAIR Hermione stands, watching. Rearing back, she hurls
                another SHARP FRAGMENT. As the fragment hits its mark, Nagini strikes blindly,
                furious, then spies Hermione. Instantly she begins to slither toward her. As
                Hermione stands her ground, we DOLLY LEFT and REVEAL Ron, clutching a BASILISK FANG
                in his FIST. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="OXFORD CORRIDOR - SAME TIME - DAWN"> Harry pushes himself
                forward, blindly, silently. He squints. Up ahead, DARK COILS of IMPOSSIBLY THICK
                smoke corkscrew from the stone floor. WHOOSH! Harry wheels, watches a FIGURE
                materialize back at the doorway. The smoke shifts, revealing Voldemort. He raises
                his wand, pointing it directly at Harry as the smoke thickens once again, concealing
                him. Seconds later... ... a RIBBON of FIRE erupts through the mist, stitching its
                way through the smoke towards Harry. Harry watches -- transfixed for a moment --
                then flings himself aside, narrowly eluding the sizzling ribbon of fire. WHOOSH!
                Voldemort vanishes, becoming one with the smoke, and Harry feels a RUSH OF AIR
                rocket past him. He spins, blindly, and watches a disturbance of smoke several
                yards. WHOOSH! ... the air TREMBLES WITH DISTURBANCE once more, but violently this
                time, the SMOKE WHIRLING crazily up and down the corridor. Harry spins in a circle
                -- wand raised -- paranoid. A second ribbon of fire comes from the blackness
                narrowly missing Harry. Harry staggers on, tripping over the BODIES that litter the
                stone floor, desperately gulping for air as the SMOKE grows thicker, CHOKING HIM, a
                rag doll in the eye of aTORNADO, the LIGHT ahead BLOOMING more BRILLIANTLY as he
                rushes on, BLINDING him as his HEART THRUMS MADLY and VOLDEMORT’S VOICE RISES IN HIS
                EARS... </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Die! Die! </sp>
            <stage>Voldemort’s face FLICKERS before him briefly, insanely, and HARRY SCREAMS,
                pitching himself forward and then he is IN THE LIGHT, passing through, beyond the
                archway and... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="STAIRCASE - DAWN (MOMENTS LATER)"> ... onto a shattered
                staircase, the sound of Voldemort -- in pursuit -- thrumming in his ears as he races
                desperately on before... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="BATTLEMENTS - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAWN"> ... staggering out onto
                the battlement, gulping air. He stops, looks around. Realizes he is trapped. He
                turns as Voldemort emerges, begins to raise his wand but... Too late. Voldemort’s
                spells BLAST him off his feet. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - LOWER STAIR - SAME TIME - DAWN"> Nagini
                ribbons forth rapidly, flowing effortlessly through the rubble that obstructs her
                path. Suddenly, up ahead, Hermione comes INTO VIEW, wand extended. She FIRES. Nagini
                HISSES, continuing on. Hermione lowers her wand, standing perfectly still as... Ron
                PELTS INTO VIEW, FANG IN HAND. He lifts the tusk when -- Nagini spies him and --
                wicked fast -- uncoils her tail, knocking the fang from his hand. He watches it
                clatter down the stone steps, then looks back at the great snake. It begins to
                move... toward him. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="BATTLEMENTS - SAME TIME - DAWN"> As Harry climbs to his feet,
                Voldemort sends a RIBBON OF DARK MATTER snaking through the air. Harry blocks it,
                DEFLECTING IT DOWNWARD, where it EXPLODES VIOLENTLY. As the walkway beneath his feet
                gives way, HARRY DROPS, just as another of Voldemort’s spells sails over his head
                and... ... Harry drops to a walkway below. Harry glances up, sees Voldemort’s SHADOW
                begin to move forward. He glances around, then dashes for a DOORWAY ahead. He is
                almost there when: WHOOSH! TENDRILS of FABRIC encircle his ankle, arm and neck and
                SPIN HIM ROUND. Harry looks: Voldemort stands upon the walkway now, CLOAK SWIRLING
                MADLY as the hem UNRAVELS and CLOTH VIPERS slither across the walkway and up Harry’s
                body. Before Harry can react, Voldemort flicks his wand and SNAPS the cloth tight,
                reeling Harry toward him. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Why do you live! </sp>
            <stage>As Voldemort’s face looms close, eyeing Harry like a curious specimen, Harry
                looks up. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Because I have something worth living for.</sp>
            <stage>Angrily, Voldemort poises the Elder Wand over HARRY’S SCAR. The flesh there
                begins to color with blood, the lightning bolt turning white as ice. And then...
                Voldemort’s HAND BEGINS TO TREMBLE. He stares at the wand and watches --in horror --
                as a CRACK APPEARS and begins to expand along its length. For a moment, he only
                stares, as if betrayed... Harry looks too, mind racing. The TENDRILS encircling him
                begin to FRAY, loosening their grip on him ever-so slightly. He wiggles his hand
                free and LASHES OUT, striking Voldemort across the cheek. Voldemort’s eyes shift,
                glaring at Harry, when he looks down, watches a DROP of BLOOD strike the fabric
                encircling Harry’s wrist. He reaches up, fingers his cheek: BLOOD. Instantly, Harry
                steps back. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Confringo!</sp>
            <stage>The tendrils of fabric BURST INTO FLAMES. Voldemort falls back and -- with his
                fractured wand --slices the burning ribbons. As they turn to ash, Harry stumbles
                back and Voldemort picks him up and hurls him INTO A WALL. As he rises, Voldemort
                fires again. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GREAT HALL - DAWN"> </stage>
            <stage>A PAIR OF EYES... OPEN. BLINK.</stage>
            <stage> BLURRY POV SHADOWS streak across our PLANE OF VIEW, like warriors in an ancient
                shadow play. SOUND SURFACES SLOWLY, ODDLY, as if our EAR DRUMS were numb and swollen
                and gradually returning to normal. We return to the EYES, unblinking, slowly
                drifting in their sockets, taking in the sound and fury that dances across the
                irises. We PULL BACK and REVEAL... Neville. Bruised but unbowed. In an instant, it
                all comes clear -- to him and us -- that the Hall is full of WIZARDS, fighting.
                Something glimmers in Neville’s periphery: The Sword of Gryffindor. Bellatrix LAUGHS
                MADLY as she stands upon a table, wand in hand, spraying the room with spells. As
                she pivots, one BOLT just misses Ginny. </stage>
            <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> NOT MY DAUGHTER, YOU BITCH!</sp>
            <stage>Mrs. Weasley pitches her cloak, wand raised. Bellatrix ROARS with laughter at
                sight of her. </stage>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Come on, granny, give us your best.</sp>
            <stage>Mrs. Weasley fires a volley of spells and Bellatrix’s smile fades. As she
                counters, JETS of LIGHT fly back and forth, skittering off the tables and overturned
                benches. Just then... Neville comes INTO VIEW, clutching the Sword of Gryffindor
                now, bumping past McGonagall and Dean Thomas as they battle a pair of Death Eaters,
                his gaze fully forward and oddly intent. As Mrs. Weasley parries a ferocious BLAST
                from Bellatrix, George, Bill and Mr. Weasley leap into the breach, raise their
                wands... </stage>
            <sp who="#MRSWEASLEY"> Back off, boys! She’s mine! <stage>glaring at
                Bellatrix</stage>You will never touch my children again! </sp>
            <sp who="#BELLATRIX"> Be thankful we only took one. Besides... <stage>indicating
                    George</stage> It’s not like you don’t have a spare.</sp>
            <stage>As Bellatrix GRINS, a MASSIVE GREEN BOLT of LIGHT spits from Mrs. Weasley’s wand,
                striking Bellatrix directly in the sternum. Bellatrix’s smile curdles, then she
                topples to the floor, still. A BLOOD-CHILLING SCREAM fills the air... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - LOWER STAIR - SAME TIME - DAWN"> Nagini
                writhes forward angrily as Ron dashes away. Seconds later, Hermione COMES INTO
                FRAME, running alongside. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Hermione! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Yes! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I need to tell you something! </sp>
            <stage>She glances at him, then looks straight ahead, still running. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I don’t want you to say anything you wouldn’t say if we weren’t
                about to be killed by a giant snake! It’ll just ruin it!</sp>
            <stage>Ron starts to respond, then says... nothing. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="BATTLEMENTS - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAWN"> Harry rises and
                Voldemort fires again, but Harry simply rises again. Furious, Voldemort steps
                forward and points the wand only inches from Harry’s forehead, seething. Harry
                glances behind, his vision spinning. Nothing is behind him. Only a void beyond the
                blasted battlement. Only sky and a great fall. He turns back to Voldemort. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You were right.</sp>
            <stage>Voldemort’s eyes glitter curiously. Harry’s eyes drift to the wand in Voldemort’s
                hand.</stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> When you told Professor Snape it was failing you. It will always fail
                you. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> It belongs to me! I killed Snape! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"><stage>taunting him</stage> But what if the wand never belonged to him?
                What if the wand’s allegiance was to someone else? Voldemort stares at him.
                Confused. And suddenly, in this moment, it is Harry, beaten and bloody, who seems in
                control. He smiles, then presses even closer, his voice quiet, vaguely taunting: </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Come on, Tom. Let’s end this the way we started it... </sp>
            <stage>Harry grabs Voldemort’s cloak in both hands. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Together. </sp>
            <stage>And then he falls back, pulling them both... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="CASTLE FACE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAWN"> ... into the void...
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - CONTINUOUS ACTION - DAWN"> Hermione and Ron
                dash down the stairs. Nagini closes on them. And then -- suddenly -- Nagini HISSES
                MADLY, twisting crazily on the steps, tail SNAPPING BACK and forth, shattering
                stairs and walls. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What’s the matter with her? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="CASTLE FACE -SAME TIME - DAWN"> Harry and Voldemort plummet,
                twisting crazily, when suddenly a CRACK fills the sky and they APPARATE into a 
               PLUME. </stage>
            <stage>NEW ANGLE - HARRY AND VOLDEMORT ... entwined, morphing monstrously in and out of
                one another, a single screaming beast one minute, adversaries the next, hurtling
                downward, toward the courtyard below... </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MARBLE STAIRCASE - SAME TIME - DAWN"> Hermione and Ron watch
                Nagini THRASH. As rubble rains down, they begin to run for the Great Hall,
                skirtingFlitwick and Hagrid, who battle a pair of Death Eaters on the stairs.
                Further up the marble stairs, PROFESSOR TRELAWNEY raises her wand, draws a bead on a
                Death Eater and with a forceful flick, sends him flying through the air. Seamus
                regards her with amazement. </stage>
            <sp who="#TRELAWNEY"> There’s more to me than incense and tea leaves, Mr. Finnegan.
            </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="COURTYARD - SAME TIME - DAWN"> The fighting wizards stop, peer
                upward at the plume above. As it STREAKS TOWARD THE GROUND, another CRACK fills the
                sky and Harry and Voldemort burst apart as they meet the ground, rolling onto their
                feet facing one another across the courtyard. Chests heaving, they stare at one
                another, then Voldemort’s eyes shift. Harry follows his gaze and watches the Elder
                Wand roll to a rest. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I told you: it’s useless to you.</sp>
            <stage>Just then, Ron and Hermione burst INTO VIEW, followed byNagini. Nagini rises,
                ready to strike. Harry turns, wand in hand, but he’s too late. Ron reaches out...
                and takes Hermione’s hand. Voldemort grabs the Elder Wand... Nagini’s head drops
                toward Ron and Hermione... Harry watches in horror as... Neville -- appearing out of
                nowhere -- steps into the breach, sword in hand, and with one mighty swing... ...
                SEVERS NAGINI’S HEAD. Voldemort freezes, watching Nagini’s body thrash madly for a
                time before going still. The great snake’s head tumbles end-over-end and then, as it
                comes to a rest... VOLDEMORT BELLOWS IN PAIN and turns, firing on Harry.
                Instinctively, Harry raises his wand, countering... ... and the Elder Wand sails
                from Voldemort’s hand, turning end-over-end, the spell... ... ricocheting back on
                him. He stands, utterly still for a moment, his eyes on Harry, then drops. Dead.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS CASTLE - DAY (LATER"> A light breeze blows over the
                damaged grounds. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="GREAT HALL -SAME TIME - DAY"> Quiet now. They’re all here, some
                huddled together in small groups, nursing their wounds. There are no tears, just
                quiet LAUGHTER and low conversation. Harry stands at the top of the Hall, surveying
                it all, then begins to walk. The Weasleys huddle together, Ginny’s head resting on
                her mother’s shoulder, her eyes distant. The Malfoys sit in the shadows, avoiding
                eye contact. McGonagall steps into the aisle, gives him a hug, lightly touches his
                face, then turns away, eyes glistening. Aberforth and Oliver Wood sit around goblets
                of something strong. Aberforth gives him a stoic nod. Dean and Seamus LAUGH together
                at a table. Filch communes with Mrs. Norris. Flitwick and Sprout sit quietly, dazed.
                Cho looks up from a group of Ravenclaws, smiles faintly. Neville sits wearily, the
                Sword of Gryffindor still clutched limply in his hand. Luna sits down beside him.
                Close. Smiles. And then Harry looks up and sees Hagrid filling the aisle. Tears in
                his eyes. He steps forward, wraps Harry in his massive arms. Harry WINCES, then
                Hagrid releases him, cuffs him on the arm and hobbles away, blowing his nose in a
                GIANT HANDKERCHIEF. Harry watches him go, then turns, sees: Hermione and Ron.
                Standing by the doorway. Watching him. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="VIADUCT -DAY (LATER"> The trio walk together, then stop, look
                back at the battered castle in the distance. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Not exactly leaving the place better than we found it, are we? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Can’t make an omelette without breaking a few eggs. </sp>
            <stage>Ron gives her a screwy look. She shakes her head wearily, frowns. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Something my mum used to say. </sp>
            <stage>Harry studies her, absently playing his fingers over the Elder Wand. She looks
                over, nods to it. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Why didn’t it work for him? The Elder wand. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Because it answers to another. </sp>
            <stage>Ron and Hermione study him. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> When he killed Snape, he thought the wand would become his. But the
                thing is... it never belonged to Snape. </sp>
            <stage>Harry turns the wand in the light, eyeing its brutish surface as he speaks. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It was Draco who disarmed Dumbledore that night on the Astronomy
                Tower. From that moment on, the wand answered to him. Until the other night...
                    <stage>looking up</stage> ... when I disarmed Draco. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> But that means... </sp>
            <stage>Harry nods. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It answers to me. </sp>
            <stage>Hermione stares at Harry. Ron stares at the wand. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> What do you reckon we should do with it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> We? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I’m just saying. That’s the Elder Wand! It’s the most powerful bloody
                wand in the world! With that, we could, we could -</sp>
            <stage>Hermione raises her hand and Ron stops, sees that her eyes are fixed on Harry,
                who is staring at the wand, his concentration total. She studies his face for a long
                moment, and then --as if coming to understand something -- begins to nod. As Harry
                peers down at his hands, Ron and Hermione do as well, watching as he takes the ends
                of the wand and... Snap! ... breaks it in two. Ron stares, stunned. Hermione smiles.
                Harry, his face a mask, simply turns and... Pitches the pieces over the edge of the
                viaduct. For a moment, the trio stand in silence, as if words would bring the bridge
                crashing down. Finally, Harry glances off at the ruins of the castle, smoldering in
                the distance. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well, it wasn’t boring, was it?</sp>
            <stage>Ron turns, ready with a reply, but whatever words were there -- briefly -- are
                gone before he can utter them. They all stare into the distance, giving themselves
                over to the silence. Then -- tentatively, tenderly -- fingers reach out --
                Hermione’s -- and brush Ron and Harry’s. They look over. See that her eyes are
                closed, as if she were committing the moment to memory. They glance briefly at one
                another and then -- tentatively, tenderly -- interlace their own fingers with
                Hermione’s, looking off and -- like her -- closing their eyes. Gradually, the
                BIRDSONGS lilting in the BREEZE give way to CAR HORNS...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="KING’S CROSS -MORNING (19 YEARS LATER)"> Two PARENTS, pushing
                TROLLEYS, shepherd their THREE CHILDREN toward the great sooty station. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="PLATFORM -MORNING (MOMENTS LATER"> Commuters stare curiously as
                the family weaves its way to a BARRIER between platforms nine and ten. As they come
                to a halt, the parents’ faces come clear: Harry, now years old, and Ginny, now 35.
                Beside them are their children: JAMES (12), ALBUS (11) and LILY -- the youngest.
                James, mischief in his eyes, looks back at his brother just before he runs through
                the barrier. And... VANISHES. Albus grips the handle of his trolley nervously,
                finding it hard to follow. Harry appears behind him, smiles tenderly, sees his son’s
                nervousness. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLDERHARRY"> Together?</sp>
            <stage>Albus nods and, side by side, they run the trolley at the barrier and...</stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="PLATFORM 9 3/4 - CONTINUOUS ACTION - MORNING"> ... emerge onto a
                new platform where a SCARLET STEAM ENGINE pours WHITE SMOKE into the air. Seconds
                later, Ginny and Lily appear. Albus peers about anxiously. There is a riot of
                activity, as wizarding parents see off their children and trunks are loaded. There
                are lots of first years like ALBUS, looking equally nervous and being given a final
                send-off. ALBUS looks at it all with trepidation. LILY races off chasing a paper
                bird that flies through the crowd. Up ahead ALBUS sees FOUR PEOPLE through the
                steam: Ron, Hermione and their two children, ROSE (11) and little HUGO, as ROSE’S
                luggage is packed onto the train -- gentle goodbyes. RON waves over to HARRY. OLDER
                HERMIONE gives her daughter ROSE one last hug. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLDERHERMIONE"> Don’t forget to give Professor Longbottom our best.</sp>
            <stage>ALBUS looks at the train, then back to HARRY. Then he disappears...</stage>
            <stage>HARRY and GINNY share a knowing look, and then as GINNY takes charge of the
                trolley, HARRY returns to ALBUS, who is now kneeling down, struggling with his
                shoelace. HARRY leans down and joins him. </stage>
            <sp who="#ALBUS"> Will there really be thestrals pulling the carriages?</sp>
            <stage>Harry eyes his son warmly. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLDERHARRY"> There’s nothing scary about thestrals. They’re gentle things.
                Anyway, you won’t be going up to school in the carriages. You’ll be going in the
                boats, remember?</sp>
            <stage>Albus nods, looks down. </stage>
            <sp who="#ALBUS"> Dad? </sp>
            <sp who="#OLDERHARRY"> Yes? </sp>
            <sp who="#ALBUS"> What if I’m put in Slytherin? </sp>
            <stage>Harry studies his son long and hard. Leans close. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLDERHARRY"> Albus Severus Potter. You were named after two Headmasters of
                Hogwarts. One of them was a Slytherin. And he was probably the bravest man I ever
                knew. </sp>
            <stage>Albus nods, thinks for a moment... then frowns. </stage>
            <sp who="#ALBUS"> But just say I am --</sp>
            <sp who="#OLDERHARRY"> Then Slytherin House will have gained a wonderful wizard. But
                listen, if it means so much to you, you can choose Gryffindor. The Sorting Hat takes
                your choice into account. </sp>
            <sp who="#ALBUS"> Really? </sp>
            <sp who="#OLDERHARRY"> Really. </sp>
            <stage>The TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS and Albus’ eyes go wide. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLDERHARRY"> Ready? </sp>
            <sp who="#ALBUS"> Ready.</sp>
            <stage>They stand, consider each other for a moment, then HARRY leans over and gives his
                son a big hug. ALBUS settles into his seat opposite ROSE, looks around him, a
                chocolate frog jumps up the window, a Weasley Firework caroms down the train
                corridor beyond. This is going to be quite a journey. ALBUS smiles and looks out to
                his Dad. Raises a hand to wave. And the train jolts to a start. HARRY, GINNY, RON,
                and HERMIONE watch with affection. LILY looks like all she wants to do is to jump on
                the train and leave with it. The train heads off. We SLOWLY MOVE INTO HARRY as he
                waves, pride, and more than a little nostalgia clear in his face, as the train slips
                away. </stage>
            <stage>FADE TO BLACK.</stage>
            <stage>THE END</stage>
        </scene>
    </script>
</xml>
