<?xml-model href="potterScripts.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
    <header>
        <!--metadata in here -->
        <title>Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</title>
        <screenWriter>Steve Kloves</screenWriter>
        <productionStart date="yyyy-mm-dd"/>
        <!--Optional: if available. -->
        <release date="2005-11-08"/>
        <!--Look this up and verify -->
        <digitalProject>
            <editor who="bca">Bianka Alexander</editor>
            <advisor who="ebb">Elisa Beshero-Bondar</advisor>
            <span from="2020-10-01" to="2021-05-06"/>
            <desc>.......</desc>
            <sourceText>
                <siteName>.....</siteName>
                <link><!--Website URL --></link>
                <dateRetrieved>yyyy-mm-dd</dateRetrieved>
            </sourceText>
        </digitalProject>
    </header>
    <script>
        <scene>
            <stage>We hone in on a snake crawling through the undergrowth. TITLES</stage>
        </scene>

        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DARK ROOM - NIGHT TIME"> An old man lights a gas oven with a
                match, he is preparing food. He notices a light on in the large house opposite, he
                stops what he's doing and walks to the door. </stage>
            <sp who="#OLDMAN"> Bloody kids.<stage> He leaves the house and heads towards the light.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" DARKNESS"> The old man is wandering up to the house carrying a
                lit torch. He opens the front door, inside is just as dark. He begins climbing the
                stairs, we hear whispers and hushed voices coming from upstairs. The old man waits
                outside the room where the conversation is taking place and listens on. </stage>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> Oh no no no my Lord Voldemort. I only meant... perhaps if we were
                to do it without the boy.. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> NO! The boy is everything, it cannot be done without him and it
                WILL be done exactly as I say. </sp>
            <sp who="#UNKNOWNMAN"> I will not disappoint you my lord. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Good. First, gather our old comrades. Send them a sign.<stage> A
                    snake slithers past the old man and into the room. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Nagini tells me the old caretaker is standing outside the
                    door.<stage> Wormtail stands in the doorway and looks at the old man. The old
                    man looks terrified. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Step aside so I can give our guest a proper greeting. </sp>


            <stage>A loud spell is cast and Harry wakes up in a flash of panic.</stage>


        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BEDROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry!<stage> Harry is flustered and still panicing. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Are you alright? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione. Bad dream. When did you get here? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Just now. You? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Last night.<stage> Hermione goes over to Ron's bed. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Wake up. Wake up Ronald! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Honestly. Get dressed, and don't go back to sleep. Come on Ron!
                Your mother says breakfast's ready. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" GRASSLAND"> </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Where are we actually going? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Don't know. Hey Dad! Where are we going? </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Haven't the foggiest, keep up! </sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> Arthur! It's about time son. </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Sorry Amos. Some of us had a bit of a sleepy start. This is Amos
                Diggory everyone, he works with me at the ministry. And this strapping young lad
                must be Cedric, am I right? </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Yes sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> Merlin's beard, you must be Harry Potter. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes sir. This way. </sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> Great great pleasure.<stage> They shake hands. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Pleasure to meet you too sir.<stage> They walk on up the hill.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> That's it sir, just over there. </sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> Shall we? We don't want to be late.<stage> Camera homes in on a boot on
                    top of the hillside. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Why are they all standing around that manky old boot? </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> That isn't just any old manky boot mate. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> It's a portkey.<stage> Everyone is in a circle putting their hands on
                    the boot. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> Time to go. Ready? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What's a 'portkey'? </sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> After 3. One... Two... </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Harry!<stage> Harry rushes over and puts his hand on the boot.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> Three!<stage> There's a white flash and suddenly they're all flying
                    through the air. Everyone cheers. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Let go kids! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What?? </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Let! Go!<stage> Harry, Hermione and the young Weasleys crash to
                    the ground with a thump. Arthur, Amos and Cedric come down more gracefully.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> I bet that cleared your sinuses eh?<stage> Cedric helps Harry to
                    his feet. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Thanks.<stage> They walk across the field and we see there's a massive
                    crowd gathered and cheering, tents are set up all over. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Well kids, welcome to the Quidditch World Cup!<stage> They walk
                    into the crowd, taking in the sights. Music is playing and people fly about
                    overhead on brooms. They approach a small tent. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> Parting of the waves I think old chap, see you at the match.<stage>
                    Amos and Cedric separate and walk off. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> See ya later Cedric. </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Home sweet home. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT"> They enter the tent, the inside is many times bigger
                than the outside. </stage>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Girls. Choose a bunk and unpack. Ron, get out of the kitchen we're
                all hungry. </sp>
            <sp who="#TWINS"> Yeah get out of the kitchen Ron. </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Feet off the table. </sp>
            <sp who="#TWINS"> Feet off the table.<stage> They take their feet off the table and put
                    them back on as soon as Arthur has walked past. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>Smiling</stage> I love magic. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HILLSIDE"> We pan up the hillside onto a large stadium which
                seems to have a huge number of floors. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" STADIUM"> The Weasleys and Harry are finding their seats. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Blimey Dad, how far up ARE we?<stage> Lucius Malfoy and Draco are
                    walking below them. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Well put it this way, if it rains... you'll be the first to
                know </sp>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> Father and I are in the minister's box, by personal invitation of
                Cornelius Fudge himself. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> Don't boast Draco. There's no need with these people. Do enjoy
                yourself won't you. While you can.<stage> The ceremonies begin. Balloons fly and
                    fireworks go off. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Come on up, take your seats. I told you these seats would be worth
                waiting for. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Come on! </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> It's the Irish!<stage> Five green and white figures fly through the air
                    on their brooms leaving a colored trail behind them. A glittering leprechaun
                    appears in the sky and starts dancing. Everyone is excited. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Here come the Bulgarians!<stage> Five red figures this time, one of
                    them performs a stunt on his broom. One of them appears on the large screen. The
                    crowd begins to chant 'Krum, Krum, Krum'. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#WEASLEYS"> Krum!!! </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Yes!<stage> Viktor Krum waves to the crowd. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#ANNOUNCER"> Good evening! It gives me great pleasure to welcome each and every
                one of you to the final of the 422nd Quidditch World Cup. Let the match begin! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT"> </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> There's no one like Krum. He's like a bird the way he rides the wind.
                He's more than an athlete, he's an artist.<stage> The twins are bumbling about in a
                    comical way muttering 'KRUMMMM'. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> Think you're in love Ron? </sp>
            <sp who="#TWINS">
                <stage>Singing</stage> Viktor I love you! Viktor I do!<stage> Harry joins in.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BOYS"> When we're apart my heart beats only for youuu! </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Sounds like the irish have got their pride on. </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Stop! Stop it. It's not the irish. We've gotta get out of here.
                Now. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" OUTSIDE THE TENT"> </stage>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Get back to the portkey everybody, and stick together. Fred,
                George... Ginny is your responsibility.<stage> Some figures in pointed hoods
                    carrying flaming torches are walking across the campsite chanting ominous
                    noises. The crowd is paniced and rushing all over. Harry is trampled
                    unconscious. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" OUTSIDE - TIME PASSED"> The crowds have all gone. A man walks
                through the rubble kicking at things. He casts a spell which causes a bright flash
                and a large ghostly skull forms in the sky with a snake crawling from it. The man
                grins evilly, clearly demented. Harry stirs and witnesses the man standing there.
                Harry runs. The familiar voices of Ron and Hermione are calling for him. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Been looking for you for ages. Thought we lost you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What is THAT?<stage> They look at the monstrous thing in the sky,
                    Harry holds his head in pain. Suddenly they are fired on. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Stop! That's my son.<stage> Arthur and others approach.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Ron, Harry, Hermione are you alright? </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Which of you conjured this? </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> You can't possibly.. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Do not lie! You have been discovered at the scene of the crime! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Crime? </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Barty, they're just kids. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What crime? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry it's his mark. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Those people tonight, in the masks... they're his too aren't they?
                they're his followers. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Follow me. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> There was a man. Before. There. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> All of you, this way. </sp>
            <sp who="#MRWEASLEY"> Harry, who? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I dunno. I didn't see his face. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TRAIN CARRIAGE"> Harry, Ron and Hermione are seated on a train.
                A voice calls out. </stage>
            <sp who="#LADY">
                <stage>OFFSCREEN</stage> Anything from the trolley? Anything from the
                    trolley?<stage> The lady appears at their door. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#LADY"> Anything from the trolley dears? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Packet of drewbals and a liquorice wand.<stage> Ron sees he hasn't
                    enough money. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> On second thought, just the drewbals. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It's alright I'll get it. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Just the drewbals, thanks.<stage> Cho Chan walks up to the trolley.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Two pumpkin pasties please.<stage> Harry and Cho look at each other and
                    smile. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Thank you. </sp>
            <sp who="#LADY"> Anything sweet for you dear? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Oh no thank you I'm not hungry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> This is horrible, how can the ministry not know who conjured it.
                Isn't there any security or? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Loads according to Dad, that's what worried them so much. Happened right
                under their noses.<stage> Hermione sees Harry rubbing his head. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It's hurting again isn't it, your scar. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I'm fine. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You know Sirius will want to hear about this. What you saw at the
                world cup, and the dream.<stage> Harry has written a letter, he marks Sirius Black
                    on an envelope and gives it to an owl. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS"> We see four flying horses flying through the air
                pulling a carriage coming in to land at Hogwarts. The crowds cheer. </stage>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Clear the runway. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well there's something you don't see every day.<stage> A large ship
                    emerges from under the water and approaches too. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Now we're all settled in and sorted, I'd like to make an
                announcement. This castle will not only be your home this year but home to some very
                special guests as well. You see Hogwarts has been choosen...<stage> A man runs up
                    the aisle limping in a comical way, he whispers something to Dumbledore and
                    leaves in the same fashion. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> So Hogwarts has been choosen to host a legendary event. The
                Tri-Wizard tournament. Now for those of you who do not know, the tri-wizard
                tournament brings together three schools for a series of magical contests. From each
                school a single contestant is selected to compete. Now let me be clear, if choosen
                you stand alone. And trust me when I say these contests are not for the faint
                hearted, but more of that later. For now please join me in welcoming the lovely
                ladies of the Beauxbatons Academy of magic and their headmistress Madam
                    Maxime.<stage> A group of girls dressed in blue dance up the aisle and release
                    butterflies into the air. They bow and everyone applauds. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#STUDENT"> Blimey, that's one big woman. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> And now our friends from the north, please greet the proud sons
                of Durmstrang and the high master Igor Karkaroff.<stage> A series of older boys walk
                    up the aisle brandishing bo staffs, twirling them around and periodically
                    stabbing them into the ground with a spark effect. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Blimey it's him, Viktor Krum!<stage> The boys breathe some fire.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> Albus! </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Igor.<stage> They embrace. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS - STORMY - NIGHT"> </stage>
            <sp who="#MADAMEMAXIME"> Professor Dumbledore, my horses have travelled a long way. They
                will need attending to. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Not to worry Madame Maxime, our gamekeeper Hagrid's more than
                capable of seeing to them. </sp>
            <sp who="#MADAMEMAXIME"> But you know Monsieur Hagrid, they drink only single malt
                    whiskey.<stage> The man seated next to Hagrid yelps. Hagrid has stabbed a fork
                    into his hand. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MAN"> You idiot! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ASSEMBLY ROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Your attention please! I would like to say a few words. Eternal
                glory, that is what awaits the student who wins the tri-wizard tournament. But to do
                this that student must survive three tasks. Three extremely dangerous tasks. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Wicked. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> For this reason the ministry has seen fit to impose a new rule.
                To explain all this we have the head of the department of international magic
                cooperation Mister Bartimus Crouch.<stage> Thunder roars overhead, rain begins
                    leaking through the roof and screams break out. A strange man stands in the
                    doorway, he casts some magic upwards and seals the roof. Peace is restored.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell, it's Mad-Eye Moody. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Alastor Moody? The aura. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> He was a catcher. Half the cells in Azkaban are full thanks to him. He's
                supposed to be mad as a hatter though these days.<stage> This character enters the
                    room and begins walking. We see Harry through his mechanical eye. He limps,
                    breathing heavily as he goes. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> My dear old friend, thanks for coming. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> That stupid roof.<stage> Mad-Eye takes a drink. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PUPIL"> What's that he's drinking do you suppose? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I don't know but I don't think it's Pumpkin Juice. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> After much deliberation the ministry has concluded that for their own
                safety no student under the age of seventeen shall be allowed to put forth their
                name for the tri-wizard tournament. This decision is final.<stage> The crowd is
                    unsettled, people are booing. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> That's rubbish! You don't know what you're doing! </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Silence!<stage> Dumbledore casts magic over a box which melds
                    into a goblet containing a blue flame. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> The goblet of fire. Anyone wishing to submit themselves for the
                tournament merely write their name upon a piece of parchment and throw it in the
                flame before this hour on Thursday night. Do not do so lightly, if choosen there's
                no turning back. As from this moment the tri-wizard tournament has begun. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ASSEMBLY ROOM - NIGHT"> We see a suspicious character enter the
                room where the goblet is still burning and close the door behind him. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CLASSROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Alastor Moody.<stage> He writes his name on the board. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Ministry malcontent. And your new defence against the dark arts
                teacher. I'm here because Dumbledore asked me, end of story, goodbye, the end. Any
                questions? When it comes to the dark arts, I believe in a practical approach. But
                first, which of you can tell me how many unforgivable curses there are? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Three sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> And they are so named? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Because they are unforgivable. Use of any one of them will... </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Will earn you a one way ticket to Azkaban. Correct. Now the ministry
                says you're too young to see what these curses do. I say different! You need to know
                what you're up against, you need to be prepared, you need to find somewhere else to
                put your chewing gum other than the underside of your desk Mr Finnigan! </sp>
            <sp who="#PUPIL"> Aw no way, the old codger can see out the back of his head.<stage>
                    Mad-Eye throws the chalk in anger. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> So, which curse shall we see first? WEASLEY! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yes... </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Give us a curse. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well, my dad did tell me about one... The imperious curse. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Ahhh yes, your father would know all about that. Gave the ministry
                quite a bit of grief a few years ago. Perhaps this will show you why.<stage> Mad-Eye
                    pops open a jar with a spider in it. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Hello. What a little beauty.<stage> He uses his wand to send it around
                    the class. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Don't worry. Completely harmless.<stage> The class is unsettled.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> But if she bites... she's lethal!<stage> Draco laughs. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> What are you laughing at?<stage> Mad-Eye sends the spider onto Draco's
                    face. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Talented isn't she? What shall I have her do next? Jump out the
                window? Drown herself?<stage> Mad-Eye has the spider over a bucket of water, it's
                    wriggling. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Scores of witches and wizards have claimed that they only do did
                you-know-whose bidding under the influence of the imperious curse. But here's the
                rub, how do we sort out the liars? Another.. another.. Come on come on. Longbottom
                is it? Up.<stage> Neville Longbottom stands. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Professor Sprout tells me you have an aptitude for herbology. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> There's the um... The cruciatus curse. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Correct! Correct! come come. Particularly nasty. The torture
                    curse.<stage> Mad-Eye begins torturing the spider with magic, it squeals.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Stop it! Can't you see it's bothering him, stop it!<stage> Mad-Eye
                    stops. Neville is disturbed. Mad-Eye picks up the spider which is still making a
                    noise. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Perhaps you could give us the last unforgivable curse Miss
                    Granger.<stage> Hermione shakes her head. He casts a spell and the spider
                    disintegrates. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> The killing curse. Only one person is known to have survived it. And
                he's sitting in this room.<stage> He approaches Harry's desk and takes a drink.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" STAIRS"> </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Brilliant isn't he! Completely demented of course. Terrifying to be in
                the same room with, he's really BEEN there you know. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> There's a reason those curses are unforgivable, and to perform them
                in a classroom. I mean did you see Neville's face.<stage> They see a boy on the
                    stairs facing the window. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Neville?<stage> Mad-Eye approaches Neville and pats him on the
                    shoulder. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Son. You alright?<stage> Neville nods. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Come on, we'll have a cup of tea. I want to show you something. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" GOBLET ROOM"> Older students are placing their names into the
                flame and others are applauding, Cedric is one of them. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Eternal glory, be brilliant wouldn't it? In three years from now we'll
                be old enough to be choosen. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah well rather you than me.<stage> The twins come up cheering.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Thank you thank you, well lads we've done it. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Cooked it up just this morning. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It's not going to work. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Oh yeah? And why's that Granger. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You see this? This is an age line. Dumbledore drew it himself. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> So? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> So a genius like Dumbledore couldn't possibly be fooled by
                something pathetically dimwitted such as an age potion. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> That's why it's so brilliant. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Ready Fred? </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Ready George?<stage> They jump inside the age line, and cheer. They put
                    their names in the flame and do a high-five. The flame fires up and they're
                    flung across the room onto the floor. When they get up they have full heads of
                    grey hair and beards. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> You said..<stage> Fred You said.. They roll around fighting on the
                    floor and the crowd cheer. The room suddenly becomes silent as Viktor Krum walks
                    in and puts his name in the flame. He looks at Hermione and she smiles.
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" GOBLET ROOM - THURSDAY NIGHT"> </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Sit down please. And now the moment you've all been waiting for,
                the champions selection!<stage> Dumbledore approaches the blue flame and it glows
                    red. A name comes out. Everyone looks on anxiously. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> The Durmstrang champion is ... Viktor Krum!<stage> The Durmstrang
                    crowd cheer. Another name comes out. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> The champion from Beauxbatons... Fleur Delacour<stage> The
                    Beauxbatons girls cheer as Fleur walks up. Another name comes out. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> The Hogwarts champion... Cedric Diggory.<stage> Hogwarts pupils
                    cheer as Cedric takes the stage. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Excellent! we now have our three champions! But in the end only
                one will go down in history. Only one will hoist this chalice of champions, this
                vessel of victory the tri-wizard cup!<stage> People cheer, but the goblet glows red
                    once more and another name flies out. Dumbledore takes it and reads...
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Harry Potter. Harry Potter? </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> No... No. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Harry Potter! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Go on Harry. Harry for goodness sake.<stage> Harry slowly walks up.
                    Dumbledore gives him the paper. Voices in the crowd shout out. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOICE"> He's a cheat! He's not even seventeen yet. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ROOM"> Harry is in a room with the other champions. Dumbledore
                bursts in and grabs Harry. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Harry! Did you put your name in the goblet of fire? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Did you ask one of the older students to do it for you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You're absolutely sure? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#MADAMEMAXIME"> Well of course he is lying. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> The hell he is. The goblet of fire is an exceptionally powerful
                magical object, only an exceptionally powerful conjurer could have hoodwinked it.
                Magic way beyond the talents of a fourth year. </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> You seem to have given this a fair bit of thought Mad-Eye. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> It was once my job to think as dark wizards do Karkaroff perhaps you
                remember? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> That doesn't help Alastor. Leave this to you Barty. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> The rules are absolute, the goblet of fire constitutes a binding
                magical contract. Mr Potter has no choice, he is as of tonight... a tri-wizards
                champion. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DARKENED TOWER ROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> This can't go on Albus. First the dark mark, now this? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> What do you suggest Minerva? </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Put an end to it. Don't let Potter compete. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> You heard Barty the rules are clear. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Well the devil with Barty and his rules. And since when did you
                accomodate them... </sp>
            <sp who="#SEVERUS"> Master I too find it difficult to believe this mere coincidence, if
                we are to truly discover the meaning of these events perhaps we should for the time
                being let them unfold. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Do nothing?? Offer him up as bait? Potter is a boy not a piece of
                meat. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I agree with Severus. Alastor, keep an eye on Harry will you? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> I can do that. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Don't let him know though, he must be anxious enough as it is...
                knowing what lies ahead. Then again, we all are. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BEDROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> How did you do it?<stage> Harry is silent. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Never mind. Doesn't matter. You could have let your best friend know
                though. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Let you know what? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You know bloody well what. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I didn't ask for this to happen Ron. Okay? You're being stupid. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah that's me, Ron Weasley... Harry Potter's stupid friend. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I didn't put my name in that cup. I don't WANT eternal glory I just
                wanna be.. Look, I don't know what happened tonight and I don't know why, it just
                did ok. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Piss off. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HOGWARTS"> A woman appears in a puff of smoke. She's well
                groomed and dressed colorfully. </stage>
            <sp who="#RITA"> What a charismatic quartet. Hello!<stage> The four tri-wizard champions
                    are stood together in a group. She walks over to them and shakes each of their
                    hands. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> I'm Rita Skeeter, I write for the daily prophet. But of course you know
                that don't you. It's you we don't know, you're the news. What quirks lurk beneath
                those rosy cheeks? what mysteries do the muscles mask? does courage lie beneath
                those curls? In short, what makes a champion tick. Me, myself and I want to know.
                Not to mention my rabid readers. So, who's feeling up to sharing? Mmm? Shall we
                start with the youngest. Lovely.<stage> She takes Harry by the hand into a closet.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> This is cosy. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It's a broomcupboard. </sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> You should feel right at home then. Don't mind if I use the quill do
                you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Oh, no. </sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> So Harry, here you sit, a mere boy of twelve.. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I'm fourteen. </sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> ...about to compete against three students. Not only vastly more
                emotionally mature than yourself but have mastered spells that you wouldn't attempt
                in your dizziest daydreams. Concerned? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I dunno I haven't really thought about it. </sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> Course you're not just any ordinary boy of twelve are you... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Fourteen. </sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> The story's legend. Do you think it was the trauma of your past that
                made you so keen to enter such a dangerous tournament. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No I didn't enter. </sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> Course you didn't. Everyone loves a rebel Harry. <stage>to the
                    quill</stage> Scratch that last. Speaking of your parents, were they alive, how
                do you think they'd feel? proud? or concerned that your attitude shows at best a
                pathological need for attention, at worst a psychotic deathwish. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>looking at the notepad</stage> Hey, my eyes aren't glistening with the ghosts
                of my past. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ROOFTOP"> An owl flies in with a letter for Harry, he takes it
                and begins to read. </stage>
            <sp who="#SIR">
                <stage>VOICEOVER</stage> Harry. I couldn't risk sending Edward. It was since the
                world cup and the ministry's been intercepting more and more owls and she's too
                easily recognised. We need to talk Harry. Face to face. Meet me in the Griffindore
                common room at one o clock this Saturday night and make sure you're alone.
                    P.S....<stage> The owl nips Harry's finger. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> AGH! </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR">
                <stage>VOICEOVER CONT'D</stage> The bird bites. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" GRIFFINDORE COMMON ROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sirius?<stage> Harry picks up a newspaper, the headline reads "THE
                    CHAMPIONS ARE SELECTED" and reads. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RITA">
                <stage>VOICEOVER</stage> Harry Potter aged 12, suspect entrant in the tri-wizard
                tournament. His eyes swimming with the ghosts of his...<stage> Her voice becomes
                    desperate as he crumples up the newspaper and puts it on the fire. The fire
                    flares up a little, a face appears in it. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sirius?! How... </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> I don't have much time Harry so let me get straight to it. Did you or
                did you not put your name into the goblet of fire? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No! </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> Shh... I had to ask. Now, tell me about this dream of yours. You
                mentioned Wormtail and Voldemort, but who was the third man in the room? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I dunno. </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> You didn't hear a name? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. Umm.. Voldemort was giving him a job to do. Something important. </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> What was that? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He wanted... me. I dunno why, but he was gonna use this man to get to
                me. I mean it was only a dream right? </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> Yes. It's just a dream. Look Harry, the deatheaters at the world cup,
                your name rising from that goblet these are not just coincidences. Hogwarts isn't
                safe any more. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What are you saying? </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> I'm saying the devils are inside the walls. Igor Karkaroff, he was a
                deatheater. And no one, no one stops being a deatheater. Then there's Barty Crouch,
                heart of stone, sent his OWN son to Azkaban. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Do you think one of them put my name in the goblet? </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> I haven't a clue who put your name in that goblet Harry but whoever did
                it is no friend to you. People die in this tournament. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I'm not ready for this Sirius. </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> You don't have a choice. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Someone's coming! </sp>
            <sp who="#SIR"> Keep your friends close Harry.<stage> Ron enters the room. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Who you talking to? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who says I was talking to anyone. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I heard voices. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Maybe you're imagining things, wouldn't be the first time. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You're probably just practicing for your next interview I expect.<stage>
                    Ron leaves. Harry goes to the fire again but Sirius is gone. The newspaper in
                    the fire has the headline "TEENAGE TRAGEDY". </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" LAKESIDE"> </stage>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Amazing. Amazing. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Neville! You're doing it again! </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Oh, right sorry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>reading a book</stage> Magical water plants of the highland Lochs? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Moody gave it to me. That day we had tea.<stage> Neville waves.
                    Hermione and Ron are walking up to them. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>Whispering to Ron</stage> We've already been through enough people why don't
                you just go and do it yourself? Ughh. What do you want me to say again?<stage> Ron
                    whispers some words to Hermione. It's clear Ron and Harry are not on speaking
                    terms. Hermione walks up to Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ronald would like me to tell you that Seamus told him that Dean was
                told by Parvati that Hagrid was looking for you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Is that right? Well.... what? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Uhhh...<stage> She walks back to Ron for more whispering and comes
                    back. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Dean was told by Parvati that... Please don't ask me say it again.
                Hagrid's looking for you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well you can tell Ronald... </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I'm NOT an owl! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" FOREST"> Harry and Hagrid are walking through a dark forest. </stage>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Did you bring your father's cloak like I asked you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah I brought the cloak. Hagrid where are we going? </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> You'll see soon enough. Pay attention this is important. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What's with the flower? Hagrid have you combed your hair?<stage>
                    Hagrid is looking more dapper than usual and is carrying a big red flower.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> As a matter of fact I have. You might like to try the same thing now
                and again.<stage> We hear animal noises. Madame Maxime calls out to Hagrid.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MADAMEMAXIME"> Hagrid? </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Oh, the cloak. Put the cloak on.<stage> Harry does as he's told.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Bonsoir Olympe. </sp>
            <sp who="#MADAMEMAXIME"> Oh Hagrid. I thought you weren't coming, I thought perhaps...
                you had... forgotten me. </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Couldn't forget you Olympe. </sp>
            <sp who="#MADAMEMAXIME"> What is it you want to show me? When we spoke earlier you
                sounded so exhilirated. </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> You'll be glad you came. Trust me.<stage> A dragon nearby gives a
                    loud roar. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MADAMEMAXIME"> Ahh, c'est magnifique!<stage> In an opening we see people are
                    running about, dragons are roaring and breathing fire. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MADAMEMAXIME"> Can we get closer? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dragons? That's the first task? You're joking. </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Come on Harry. They're seriously misunderstood creatures.<stage> A
                    huge flame fires up. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Although, I have to admit that horntail is a right nasty piece of
                work. Poor Ron nearly fainted just seeing him you know. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron was here? </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Oh sure. His brother Charlie helped bring him over from Romania.
                Didn't Ron tell you that? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No he didn't. He didn't tell me a thing. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS - DAYTIME"> We're zoomed in on a badge, it depicts
                Cedric on a bright yellow background. Then the badge spins and shows Harry on a
                green background with the words "Potter Stinks" on it. As Harry walks along other
                pupils aim insults at him saying he stinks. A young boy runs past. </stage>
            <sp who="#BOY"> Cedric rules! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Thanks.<stage> Harry gets to a doorway, two pupils stand in his way.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BOY"> Like the badge? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Excuse me..<stage> They laugh, Harry pushes his way through. He
                    approaches Cedric who is standing around with his friends. Cedric's friends hurl
                    off more insults. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>to Cedric</stage> Can I have a word? </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Alright.<stage> They walk away some distance. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Dragons. That's the first task. They've got one for each of us. </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Are you serious? And Fleur and Krum, do they...? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Right. Hey listen, about the badges. I've asked them not to wear
                them. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Don't worry about it.<stage> Ron and Seamus are walking along. Harry
                    approaches them. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>To Ron</stage> You're a right foul git you know that? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> You think so? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I know so. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Anything else? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah. Stay away from me. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Fine.<stage> Draco calls out, he's sitting up a tree. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> Why so tense Potter? My father and I have a bet you see. I don't think
                you're gonna last ten minutes in this tournament. He disagrees. He thinks you won't
                last </sp>
            <sp who="#FIVE."> </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I don't give a damn what you or your father thinks Malfoy. He's vile
                and cruel, and you're just pathetic.<stage> Harry walks away and Draco angrily tries
                    casting a spell. Mad-Eye appears and quickly turns Malfoy into a ferret.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> I'll teach you to cast when someone's back is turned. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Professor Moody what are you doing? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Teaching. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Is that a student? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Technically it's a ferret.<stage> Mad-Eye is making the ferret hover
                    around. He sends it up the trouser leg of one of Draco's friends. He squirms and
                    looks uncomfortable. Everyone else is laughing. Mad-Eye winks to Harry and he
                    laughs. Eventually it comes back out and McGonagall turns Draco back to normal.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DRACO"> My father will hear about this! </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Is that a threat!<stage> Draco runs away. Mad-Eye shouts after him.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> I could tell you stories about your father that would curl even your
                greasy hair boy! It doesn't end here! </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> We never use transfigration as a punishment, surely Dumbledore
                told you that. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> He might've mentioned it. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Well you will do well to remember it. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY">
                <stage>To Harry</stage> come with me.</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="MAD-EYE'S ROOM"> Mad-Eye takes off his prosthetic leg and takes
                a seat.</stage>


            <sp who="#MOODY"> That's a foal glass. Lets me keep an eye on my enemies. If I can see
                the whites of their eyes they're standing right behind me.<stage> A noise emerges
                    from a trunk on the floor and it shakes. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Wouldn't even bother telling you what's in ther. You wouldn't believe
                it if I did. Now... what are you going to do about your dragon? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Oh... um... You know I just thought I'd... </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Sit. Listen to me Potter. Your pal Diggory, by your age he could take
                a whistle into a watch and have it sing you the time. Miss Delacour, she's as much a
                fairy princess as I am. As for Krum, his head may be filled with sawdust but
                Karkaroff's is NOT. They'll have a strategy, and you can bet that it'll play to
                Krum's strengths. Hmm? Come on Potter. What are your strengths? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Um... I dunno.. I can fly. I mean I'm a fair flyer. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Better than fair the way I heard it. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But I'm not allowed a broom. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> You're allowed a wand.</sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where="ARENA - TOURNAMENT STAGE 1"> The crowds are cheering, people are
                taking bets.</stage>


        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" WAITING TENT"> Harry is pacing nervously. Hermione is standing
                by the tent door whispering in. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Pssst! Harry? Is that you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> How are you feeling? OK? The key is to concentrate. After that you
                just have to... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Battle a dragon.<stage> Hermione enters the tent and they hug. A
                    bright camera flashes, Rita Skeeter the journalist approaches. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> Young love! Ohh how.. stirring. If everything goes unfortunately today
                you might make the front page. </sp>
            <sp who="#VIKTOR">
                <stage>To Rita</stage> You have no business here. This tent is for champions and
                friends. </sp>
            <sp who="#RITA"> No matter. We've got what we wanted.<stage> Rita leaves and Dumbledore
                    enters. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Good day champions. Gather round please. Now you've waited,
                you've wondered and at last the moment has arrived. The moment only four of you can
                fully appreciate.<stage> The champions gather around him in a circle. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> What are you doing here Miss Granger? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Oh um.. Sorry I'll just go. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Barty. The bag. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Champions, in a circle around me. Miss Delacour over here, Mr Krum,
                and Potter over here. Right. Miss Delacour, if you will...<stage> Barty holds up a
                    bag. Fleur takes out a little green dragon. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> The welsh green. Mr Krum...<stage> Viktor takes another out
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> The chinese fireball. Oooooh.<stage> Cedric picks one. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> The swedish short-snout. Which leaves... </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The horntail... </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> What's that boy? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Nothing.<stage> Harry puts his hand in the bag and pulls out the
                    dragon. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> The hungarian horntail. These represent very real dragons, each of
                which has been given a golden egg to protect. Your objective is simple, collect the
                egg. This you must do, for each egg contains a clue without which you cannot hope to
                proceed to the next task. Any questions? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Very well. Good luck champions. Mr Diggory the sound of the
                    cannon...<stage> The cannon fires immediately. Transcribed by IMSDb.com
                </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" TENT"> Harry is sitting alone nervously. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>VOICEOVER THE LOUDSPEAKER</stage> Three of our champions have now faced their
                dragons and so each one of them will proceed to the next task. And now our fourth
                and final contestant.<stage> Harry enters the rocky arena. The crowd are cheering
                    his name. He sees the golden egg sitting alone, he makes a run for it but the
                    dragon appears. Harry's forced to retreat behind a rock as the dragon flames
                    him. Harry stumbles and falls around the arena. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Your wand harry! Your wand!<stage> Harry summons a broom. He jumps
                    on and flies off, the dragon gives chase. The dragon bursts through the crowd
                    and they look stunned. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS SKY"> Harry is flying at high speed around the
                Hogwarts buildings. The dragon cuts him off and whips him off his broom, he lands on
                the roof of Hogwarts, hanging on for dear life. The dragon is clambering across the
                roof, strewing tiles as it goes. Harry reaches his broom but it's stuck. He jerks it
                loose and lets go of the roof just in time before the dragon swipes at him. He falls
                a long way but regains control. He flies on to an area with a bridge, he flies
                through a gap in the bridge but the dragon crashes into it and falls into the water.
            </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ARENA"> The crowds are mostly silent. We see Harry flying
                towards us and the crowd erupts. He goes straight for the golden egg. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HOGWARTS"> Harry is lifting the golden egg, people around him
                cheering. The Weasly twins have Harry sitting on their shoulders. </stage>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> We knew you wouldn't die Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Lose a leg. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Or an arm. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Pack it in altogether. </sp>
            <sp who="#TWINS"> NEVER! </sp>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> Go on Harry, what's the clue?<stage> Seamus hands Harry the golden
                    egg. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who wants me to open it? You want me to open it?<stage> He opens the
                    egg and a loud horrific screech comes out, he closes it again. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What the bloody hell was that?<stage> Ron appears in the doorway.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> Alright everyone, go back to your knitting. This is gonna be
                uncomfortable enough without all you nosey sods listening in. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I reckon you'd have to be barking mad to put your own name in the goblet
                of fire. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Caught on have you. Took you long enough. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Wasn't just me who thought you'd done it. Everyone was saying it behind
                your back. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Brilliant. That makes me feel loads better. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> At least I warned you about the dragons. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hagrid warned me about the dragons. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Oh no no, I did. Don't you remember? I told Hermione to tell you that
                Seamus told me that Parvati told Dean that Hagrid was looking for you. Seamus never
                actually told me anything, so it was really me all along. I thought you'd be
                alright, you know, after you figured that out. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who could possibly figure that out? That's completely mental. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah it is isn't it. Suppose I was a bit distraught. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Boys. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CLASSROOM"> Harry is looking at Cho. When she looks back he
                spills drink from his mouth. They laugh at him. </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE">
                <stage>Reading a newspaper</stage> Look at this! I can't believe it she's done it
                again. Miss Granger a plain but ambitious girl seems to be developing a taste for
                famous wizards. Her latest prey sources report is none other than the Bulgarian
                bon-bon Viktor Krum. No word yet on how Harry Potter's taking this latest emotional
                    blow.<stage> A young boy walks up holding a package. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#NIGEL"> Parcel for you Mr Weasley. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Thank you Nigel.<stage> Nigel is gazing at Harry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Not now Nigel. Later. Go on.<stage> Nigel leaves. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I told him I'd get him Harry's autograph. Oh look mum's sent me
                something. Mum sent me a dress?? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well it does match your eyes. Is there a bonnet? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Ginny these must be for you. </sp>
            <sp who="#GINNY"> I'm not wearing that it's ghastly.<stage> Hermione laughs.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What are you on about? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> They're not for Ginny they're for you! Dress robes. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Dress robes? for what? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ASSEMBLY ROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> The yule ball has been a tradition of the tri-wizard tournament
                since its inception. On Christmas eve night we and our guests gather in the great
                hall for well mannered frivolity. As representitives of the host school I expect
                each and every one of you to put your best foot forward, and I mean this literally
                because the yule ball is first and foremost... a dance.<stage> Groans emerge from
                    the boys who are listening on. The girls seem a lot more excited. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Silence. The house of Godrick Griffindore has commanded the
                respect of the wizard world for nearly ten centuries. I will not have you in the
                course of a single evening besmirching that name by behaving like a babbling,
                bumbling band of baboons. </sp>
            <sp who="#FRED">
                <stage>Whispering to George</stage> Try saying that five times faster.<stage> They
                    try. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">
                <stage>Continued</stage> Now to dance is to let the body breathe, inside every girl
                a secret swan slumbers longing to burst forth and take flight. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>Whispering to Seamus</stage> Something's about to burst out of Hilary but I
                don't think it's a swan. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Inside every boy a lordly lion prepared to prance. Mr Weasly,
                will you join me.<stage> She grabs Ron and pulls him up to dance. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Now, place your right hand on my waist. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Where? </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> My waist.<stage> He does so and a wolf whistle comes from the
                    crowd. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Now bend your arm. Mr Filch...<stage> The music starts.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> One two three, one two three, one two three. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY">
                <stage>To the Weasly twins</stage> Oi! Never gonna let him forget this are you? </sp>
            <sp who="#TWINS"> Never. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Everybody come together.<stage> The girls instantly stand and
                    walk forward, the boys are all still seated. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Boys, on your feet.<stage> Neville stands. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS - DAYTIME"> </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Why do they always have to travel in packs? How are you supposed to
                get one alone to ask them... </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Blimey Harry, you slayed dragons. If you can't get a date who can? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I think I'd take the dragon right now.<stage> Groups of girls are
                    giving them icy looks and turning their backs. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HOGWARTS"> Hagrid and Madame Maxime are walking together. </stage>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> I take after my mum. Though I didn't know her very well, she left
                when I was about three. No, not the maternal sort her, broke my dad's heart though.
                You know he was a tiny little fellow my dad, I could pick him up with one hand by
                the age of six and put him up in the dresser.<stage> They laugh together and have a
                    moment. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> And then he died when I was still in school. So I had to make me own
                way as it were. But enough of me, what about you! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" LAKESIDE"> Viktor Krum is training, a group of girls are
                following him around. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CLASSROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> This is mad. At this rate we'll be the only ones in our year without
                    dates.<stage> Severus Snape walks past and slaps Ron over the head.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well, us and Neville! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But then again he can take himself. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It might interest you to know that Neville's already got
                    someone.<stage> Ron gasps. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Now I'm really depressed.<stage> Fred hands Ron a note, it reads "GET A
                    MOVE ON OR ALL THE GOOD ONES WILL HAVE GONE!". </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well Hermione, you're a girl. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Oh well spotted. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Come on. It's one thing for a bloke to show up alone. For a girl it's
                just sad. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I won't be going alone because believe it or not someone's asked
                me. And I said yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell.<stage> Hermione storms off. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Look. We've just got to grit our teeth and do it. Tonight when we get
                back to the common room, we'll both have partners. Agreed? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Agreed. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS - SNOWY"> Harry is walking up some steps. He reaches
                the top and bumps into Cho who has come around the corner. </stage>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Harry! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Cho! </sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Watch yourself on the stairs, it's a bit icey at the top. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ok thanks. Cho? </sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Yes? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Um. <stage>Mumbling</stage> I just wondered if maybe you wanted to go
                to the ball with me? </sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Sorry? I didn't catch that. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Um. I was just wondering if maybe you wanted to go to the ball with
                me. </sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Oh. Um. Harry I'm sorry but someone's already asked me. And well I've
                said I'll go with him. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ok. Great. Fine. No problem. Good. </sp>
            <sp who="#CHO"> Harry I really am sorry. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" COMMON ROOM"> Ron is being helped into the room, he looks
                shaky. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What happened to you? </sp>
            <sp who="#GIRL"> He just asked Fleur Delacour out. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What did she say? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No of course.<stage> Ron shakes his head. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> She said yes?? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Don't be silly. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> There she was walking by. You know I like it when they walk. I couldn't
                help it, it just sort of slipped out. </sp>
            <sp who="#GIRL"> Actually he sort of screamed at her, it was a bit frightening. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What did you do then? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What else? I ran for it. I'm not cut out for this Harry. I don't know
                what got into me.<stage> The Patil twins walk past. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PATILS"> Hi Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hey! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DANCEHALL"> Soft music plays and everyone is well dressed,
                gathered in the hall. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where="ELSEWHERE"> Ron is getting dressed in front of a mirror. He
                looks paniced and uncomfortable in his ridiculous dress robes. </stage>
            <sp who="#RON"> Bloody hell.<stage> Harry walks in, he's dressed in a more conventional
                    suit. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> What are those?? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> My dress robes. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well they're alright. No lace, no dodgy little collar. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well I expect yours are more traditional. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Traditional?? They're ancient! I look like my great aunt Tessie.<stage>
                    He sniffs at his clothes. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> I smell like my great aunt Tessie. Murder me Harry. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DANCEHALL"> Harry and Ron are walking down the stairs into the
                hall. Ron is fidgeting with his outfit. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Leave it alone. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Poor kid, bet she's alone in her room crying her eyes out. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Hermione of course. Come on Harry, why'd you think she wouldn't tell us
                who she's coming with? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Because we'd take the mickey out of her if she did. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Because nobody asked her. I would have taken her myself if she weren't
                so bleeding proud.<stage> The boys approach the Patil twins. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PARVATI"> Hello boys. Don't you look...<stage> She looks at Ron. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PARVATI"> ... dashing. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Here you are Potter. Are you and Miss Patil ready? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Ready professor? </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> To dance. It's traditional that the three champions or in this
                case four are the first to dance. Surely I told you that. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No. </sp>
            <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Oh well now you know. Oh, as for your Mr Weasly you may proceed
                into the great hall with Miss Patil.<stage> Hermione enters the room all dressed up.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PARVATI"> She looks beautiful. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah she does.<stage> Hermione walks down the stairs. Viktor Krum
                    takes her hand and they walk together. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PADMA">
                <stage>To Ron</stage> Is that Hermione Granger? With Viktor Krum?? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No. Absolutely not.<stage> Loud music plays as the champions head to the
                    dancefloor with their partners. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PARVATI"> Harry. Take my waist. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What? </sp>
            <sp who="#PARVATI"> Now.<stage> They dance. Soon others are joining in, Dumbledore and
                    McGonagall, Mr Filch and his cat, Hagrid and Madame Maxime. Mad-Eye sits on the
                    sidelines drinking. The scene changes, the music is now rock played by the Weird
                    Sisters fronted by Jarvis Cocker from Pulp. Cool!. The crowd is jumping. Harry,
                    Ron and their dates are sitting some distance away looking miserable. Hermione
                    comes up after a great time with Viktor. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Hot isn't it? Viktor's gone to get drinks. Care to join us? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No, we'd NOT care to join you and Viktor. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What's got your wand in a knot? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> He's a Durmstrang. You're fraternising with the enemy. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> The enemy?? Who was it wanting his autograph? Besides, the whole
                point of the tournament is international magical cooperation, to make friends. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Hrmph, I think he's got a bit more than friendship on his mind.<stage>
                    Hermione walks off. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#PADMA"> Are you going to ask me to dance or not? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> No. </sp>
            <sp who="#LATER"> </sp>
            <sp who="#RON">
                <stage>To Hermione</stage> He's using you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> How dare you! Besides I can take care of myself. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Doubt it. He's way too old. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> What? What? That's what you think? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Yeah that is what I think. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You know the solution then don't you. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Go on. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Next time there's a ball pluck up the courage and ask me before
                somebody else does, and not as a last resort. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well that's completely off the point. Harry...<stage> Harry walks up.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Where have you been? Nevermind! Off to bed both of you.<stage>
                    Harry and Ron walk away. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> They get scary when they get older. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Ron you spoil everything! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BEDROOM"> NIGHTMARE SEQUENCE We're back in the old house. </stage>
            <sp who="#VOLDERMORT"> Let me see it again.<stage> A sleeve is rolled up and a marking
                    of a skull and snake in on the arm. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Ah yes, the time is close now. Harry! At last! Step aside Wormtail
                so I can give our guest a proper greeting!<stage> Harry wakes up. The floorboards
                    are creaking, someone is walking up to his bed. It's Neville. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> You alright Harry? I just got in. Me!<stage> He chuckles and dances
                    off. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" A BRIDGE OUTSIDE HOGWARTS"> </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry you told me you'd figured the egg out weeks ago. The task is
                two days from now. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Really? I had no idea. I suppose Viktor's already figured it out. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I wouldn't know, we didn't actually talk about the tournament.
                Actually we didn't really talk at all, Viktor's more of a physical being. I just
                mean he's not particularly... Mostly he watches me study. It's a bit annoying
                actually. You are trying to figure this egg out aren't you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> What's that supposed to mean? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> I mean these tasks are supposed to test you, in the most brutal way
                they're almost cruel. And um, I'm scared for you. You got by the dragon mostly on
                nerve, I'm not sure it's going to be enough this time. </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Hey Potter. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Cedric. </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> How are you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Spectacular. </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Look I realise I never really thanked you properly for tipping me off
                about those dragons. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Forget about it. I'm sure you would have done the same for me. </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Exactly. You know the prefects bathroom on the fifth floor?<stage>
                    Harry nods. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> It's not a bad place for a bath. Just take your egg and mull things
                over in the hot water. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BATHROOM"> Harry is taking his clothes off, he gets in the
                bath. He has his golden egg on the side. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I must be out of my mind.<stage> He opens the egg and the horrible
                    screech noise comes out. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MYRTLE"> I'd try putting it in the water if I were you. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Myrtle! </sp>
            <sp who="#MYRTLE"> Long time no see.<stage> The ghostly figure of little Myrtle flies
                    around. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MYRTLE"> I was circling a blocked drain the other day and could swear I saw a
                bit of polyjuice potion. Not being a bad boy again are you Harry? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Polyjuice potion! Kicked the habit. Myrtle, did you say try putting it
                in the water?<stage> Myrtle flies around again and gets in the water. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MYRTLE"> Well. That's what he did. The other boy, the handsome one.
                    Cedric.<stage> Harry takes the egg and puts it under the water. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MYRTLE"> Well go on, open it.<stage> Harry does so and goes underwater
                    himself. He hears a voice singing. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOICESINGING"> Come seek us where our voices sound. We cannot sing above the
                ground. An hour long you'll have to look, to recover what we took. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Myrtle, there aren't Merpeople in the black lake are there? </sp>
            <sp who="#MYRTLE"> Ahhh, very good. Took Cedric ages to riddle it out. Almost all the
                bubbles were gone...<stage> Myrtle laughs and Harry is embarrassed. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" COMMON ROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry, tell me again. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Come seek us where our voices sound. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> The black lake, that's obvious. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> An hour long you'll have to look. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Again obvious, though I must admit potentially problematic </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Potentially problematic? When was the last time you held your breath
                under the water for an hour Hermione? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Look Harry, we can do this. The three of us can figure it
                    out.<stage> Mad-Eye Moody appears in the doorway. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Hate to break up this scholar session but Professor McGonagall would
                like to see you in her office. Not you Potter, just Weasly and Granger. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> But sir, the second task is only hours away and... </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Exactly. Presumably Potter is well prepared by now and could do with a
                good night's sleep. Go. Now! Longbottom!<stage> Neville appears from behind a
                    bookcase. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Why don't you help Potter put his books back. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> You know, if you're interested in plants you'd be better with
                Gorshok's Guide to Herbology. Do you know there's a wizard in Nepal whose growing
                gravity resistant trees? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Neville. No offense, but I really don't care about plants. Now if
                there's a Tibetan turnip that will allow me to breathe underwater for an hour then
                great. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> I don't know about a turnip but you can always use gilliweed. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" LAKESIDE"> The Weasly twins are shouting, busy taking bets.
                Harry is walking along with Neville, he has some green plantlife in his hand. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You're sure about this Neville. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Absolutely. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> For an hour. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Most likely. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Most likely? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Well there is some debate among herbologists as to the effects of
                freshwater versus saltwater. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> You're telling me this now? You must be joking. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> I just wanted to help. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Well that makes you sight better than Ron and Hermione. Where are they
                anyway? </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> You seem a little tense Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Do I? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>Over a loudspeaker</stage> Welcome to the second task. Last night something
                was stolen from each of our champions. A treasure of sorts. These four treasures,
                one for each champion, now lie on the bottom of the black lake. In order to win each
                champion need only find their treasure and return to the surface. Simple enough.
                Except for this, they will have one hour to do so and one hour only. After that
                they'll be on their own. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY">
                <stage>To Harry</stage> Put that in your mouth.<stage> Harry puts the gilliweed in
                    his mouth and starts choking. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>Continued</stage> You may begin at the start of the cannon.<stage> The cannon
                    fires and the champions enter the water, three of them dive in while Harry is
                    pushed. Underwater the effects of gilliweed take hold, Harry's hands and feet
                    become webbed. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ABOVE WATER"> </stage>
            <sp who="#SEAMUS"> What's the matter with him? </sp>
            <sp who="#FRIEND"> I don't know I can't see him. </sp>
            <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Oh my god I've killed Harry Potter!<stage> Harry flies into the air
                    like a dolphin and the crowd cheer. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" UNDERWATER"> Harry swims among the fish and rocks. Singing
                voices start echoing. We see Fleur get trapped, she screams. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ABOVE WATER"> </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>Over the loudspeaker</stage> The Beauxbatons champion Miss Delacour has
                unfortunately been forced to retire. She will take no further part in this task.
            </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" UNDERWATER"> Harry is still searching around. He hears muffled
                screams. He finds Ron, Hermione, Cho Chan and a blonde girl from Beauxbatons tied in
                place by their ankles. Cedric is there, he takes Cho with him. Harry sets about
                freeing Ron and Hermione but vicious merpeople appear. </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> But she's my friend too! </sp>
            <sp who="#MERPERSON"> Only one.<stage> What looks like a shark approaches at high speed.
                    We see that it has legs and it's Viktor. He takes Hermione and heads for the
                    surface. Harry frees Ron. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ABOVE WATER"> Cedric and Cho emerge, the crowd cheers. Viktor
                and Hermione next, the crows chants 'Krum, Krum, Krum'. The Beauxbatons girls look
                worried. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" UNDERWATER"> Harry looks over and sees the blonde girl that
                Fleur was unable to rescue. He loosens her rope too and starts heading for the
                surface with the both of them. He's attacked and gets held down, he pushes Ron and
                the girl towards the surface. </stage>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ABOVE WATER"> Ron and the girl come up, they are coughing but
                safe. They're helped out of the water by a girl from Beauxbatons. Underwater Harry
                casts a spell which propels him towards the surface, he flies out and lands on the
                decking where the crowd are. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Harry! </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Get him another towel. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I want all the judges over here now. </sp>
            <sp who="#FLEUR">
                <stage>To Harry</stage> You saved her, even though she wasn't yours to save. My
                little sister!<stage> Fleur kisses Harry on the face. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FLEUR"> Thank you! And you... <stage>Looks to Ron</stage>. You helped! </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well... yeah... a bit<stage> Fleur kisses him too. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Merci.<stage> Hermione comes up to Harry with a towel. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Hermione </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Are you alright? You must be freezing! Personally I think you
                behaved admirably.<stage> Hermione kisses Harry on the head. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I finished last Hermione. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Next to last. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Attention! Attention! The winner is... Mr Diggory!<stage> Cedric
                    and his friends cheer. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> For showing unique command of the bubblehead shark. The way I see
                it, Mr Potter would have finished first had it not been for his determination to
                rescue not only Mr Weasly but the others as well. We've agreed to award him second
                place! For outstanding moral fibre.<stage> As they're walking away from the lake
                    Harry's friends are cheering him. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FRED"> All that moral fibre eh? </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Blimey even when you go wrong it turns out right. </sp>
            <sp who="#GEORGE"> Well done 'moral fibre'.<stage> Barty Crouch is waiting for Harry.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Congratulations Potter, fine achievement. Well done boy. I'm sorry we
                haven't spoken, after all your story is one I've heard many times. Quite remarkable.
                Tragic of course, to lose one's family. Never whole again are we? Still, life goes
                on. And here we stand. I'm sure your parents would be very proud today
                    Potter.<stage> Mad-Eye approaches them. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Bartimus! Not trying to lure Potter into one of the ministry's summer
                internships are we? Last boy who went into the department of ministries never came
                    out!<stage> Barty walks away from him. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> And they say I'm mad. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" DARK FOREST"> </stage>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> So I remember, I remember when I first met you all. Biggest bunch of
                misfits I've ever set eyes on. Always reminded me of myself a little. And here we
                all are, four years later. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> We're still misfits. </sp>
            <sp who="#HAGRID"> Maybe. But we've all got each other, and Harry of course. Soon to be!
                The youngest! Tri-Wizard champion there's ever been! Hooray!<stage> They walk on
                    singing the Hogwarts song. Harry holds his head in pain. On the ground he sees
                    Barty Crouch laying lifeless. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Mr Crouch? </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" HOGWARTS DARK ROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> A man has died here. And he won't be the last, you must take
                action. </sp>
            <sp who="#FUDGE"> I will not. In times like these the wizard world looks to its leaders
                for strength Dumbledore. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Then for once show them some. </sp>
            <sp who="#FUDGE"> The tri-wizard tournament will not be cancelled. I will not be seen as
                a coward. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> But surely that is what's right, no matter what others think. </sp>
            <sp who="#FUDGE"> What did you say? What did you say to me? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Excuse me gentlemen, it may interest you to know that this
                conversation is no longer private.<stage> Mad-Eye points to the door. Harry enters.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FUDGE"> Harry! Harry how good to see you again. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I can come back later Professor. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Oh not necessary Harry the minister and I are done. I'll be back
                in a moment. Minister, after you. Harry do feel free to indulge in a liquorice snack
                in my absence, but I have to warn you they're a little bit sharp.<stage> Harry is
                    left alone in the room. He puts his hand in the snackbowl and takes a handful.
                    It turns into a small creature which nips at his hand. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Agh!<stage> A compartment in the wall opens, there's a glowing blue
                    pool of water there. He looks in. He falls and lands in another time and place.
                    It's a courtroom, the walls have a red glow. Dumbledore is seated next to where
                    Harry is. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" COURTROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Professor?<stage> The man seated next to Dumbledore speaks.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MAN"> Professor.<stage> Dumbledore and the man shake hands. Their handshake
                    goes through Harry's body, he appears to be some kind of ghost with no presence.
                    Proceedings begin, a cage is raised from inside the floor. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Igor Karkaroff, you have been brought from Azkaban at your own request
                to present evidence to this counsel. Should your testimony prove consequential.
                Counsel may be prepared to order your immediate release. Until such time you remain
                in the eyes of the ministry a convicted deatheater. Do you accept these terms? </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> I do sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> What do you wish to present? </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> I have names sir. There was a Rosier, Evan Rosier. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Mr Rosier is dead. </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> Dead? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY">
                <stage>To Dumbledore</stage> Yeah took a piece of me with him though didn't
                    he.<stage> Mad-Eye points to his mechanical eye. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> I didn't know. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> If that is all the witness has to offer... </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> No! No! There was Rookwood, he was a spy. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Augustus Rookwood? Of the department of ministries. </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> Ya ya, the same. He passed information to you know who from inside the
                ministry itself. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Very well. Counsel will deliberate. In the meantime you will be
                returned to Azkaban. </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> NO! WAIT! PLEASE! I have more. Snape, Severus Snape. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> The counsel is very much aware you have given evidence on this
                matter. Severus Snape was indeed a deatheater and prior to Lord Voldemort's downfall
                turned spy for us at great personal risk. Today he's no more a deatheater than I
                    am.<stage> Igor protests loudly. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> It's a lie! Severus Snape remains faithful to the dark lord. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Silence!<stage> Barty hits the gavel repeatedly. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Unless the witness possesses any name of genuine consequence this
                session is now concluded. </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> Oh no no no no no. I heard about one more. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> What's that? </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> The name... </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> Yes? </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> I know for a fact this person took part in the capture, and by means of
                the cruciatus curse, torture of the aurer Frank Longbottom and... </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> The name! Give me the wretched name! </sp>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> Barty Crouch! ... Junior.<stage> Barty Crouch junior begins to run.
                    Mad-Eye zaps him with magic, he falls into the center of the court. The crowd is
                    in uproar. Guards seize Barty junior. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#BARTYJR"> Get your hands off me you pathetic little men. Hello father. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTY"> You are no son of mine. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTYJR"> GAHHHH!<stage> Harry steps out of the blue pool and we're back in
                    the darkened room. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Curiosity's not a sin Harry, but you should exercise caution.
                It's a pensieve, useful if like me you find your mind a wee bit stretched. It allows
                me to see what small things I've already seen. You see Harry I've searched and
                searched for something, some small detail. Something I might have overlooked,
                something that would explain why these terrible things have happened. Every time I
                get close to an answer it slips away, it's maddedning. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Sir, Mr Crouch's son, what happened to him? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> He was sent to Azkaban. Destroyed Barty to do it. But he had no
                choice, the evidence was overwhelming. Why do you ask? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It's just that I had a dream about him. It was in the summer, before
                school. In the dream I was in a house and Voldemort was there only he wasn't quite
                human, and Wormtail was there too and Mr Crouch's son. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Have there been other dreams like this? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. Always the same one. Sir... these dreams, what I see, you don't
                think it's actually happening do you? </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I think it's unwise for you to linger over these dreams Harry, I
                think it's best that you simply...<stage> Dumbledore puts up his wand and pulls a
                    quivering string of magic out from his head. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Cast them away. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR"> Harry is walking along, we hear raised voices from
                inside the herbs store. </stage>
            <sp who="#IGOR"> It's a sign Severus, you know what it means as well as I.<stage> The
                    door opens and they see Harry. He looks at them. Igor leaves. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SEVERUS"> Potter! What's your hurry? Congratulations, your performance in the
                black lake was inspiring. Gilliweed, am I correct? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes sir. </sp>
            <sp who="#SEVERUS"> Ingenious. A rather rare herb gilliweed, not something found in your
                every day garden. Nor is this, know what it is? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Bubble juice sir? </sp>
            <sp who="#SEVERUS"> Veritaserum. Three drops of this and you-know-who himself will spill
                his darkest secrets. The use of this on a student is regrettably forbidden, however
                should you ever steal from my personal stores again, my hand might just slip over
                your morning pumpkin juice. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I haven't stolen anything. </sp>
            <sp who="#SEVERUS"> Don't lie to me. Gilliweed might be innocuous, but boomslang skin?
                lacewing flies? You and your friends are brewing polyjuice potion and believe me I'm
                going to find out why.<stage> Severus closes the door in Harry's face. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ARENA"> Music is playing and a large crowd is gathered. The
                champions emerge. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Earlier today Professor Moody placed the tri-wizards cup deep
                within the maze. Only he knows its exact position. Now as Mr Diggory...<stage> The
                    crowd cheer on hearing his name. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>continued</stage> and Mr Potter tied for first position they will be the
                first to enter the maze. Followed by Mr Krum...<stage> The bulgarian crowd go nuts.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>continued</stage> The first person to touch the cup will be the winner. I've
                instructed the staff to patrol the perimeter, if at any point should a contestant
                wish to withdraw from the task he or she need only send up red sparks with their
                wands. Contestants, gather round. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>To the contestants</stage> In the maze you'll find not dragons or creatures
                of the deep. Instead you'll face something more challenging. You see, people change
                in the maze. Oh find the cup if you can, but be very weary you could just lose
                yourselves along the way. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Champions! Prepare yourselves.<stage> Cedric hugs his father.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> On the count of three... ONE...<stage> The cannon goes off. Mr
                    Filch shrugs comically. Dumbledore groans. Harry and Cedric enter the maze
                    through different entrances. The entrance closes up behind Harry. Heavy mist
                    sets in, we pan out to see the maze is many stories tall. Harry starts
                    traversing the maze, creature noises are all around. Cedric is walking along,
                    the maze walls begin to close in on him. He makes a run for it. Fleur is running
                    around scared, she is attacked and knocked down. Viktor comes along and sees
                    she's unconscious on the ground, he walks on. Harry sees Fleur being swallowed
                    into the undergrowth. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Fleur? Fleur!<stage> He's too late she's disappeared. He sends up a
                    red spark into the air. A heavy wind starts blowing, walls are closing in, Harry
                    runs. Harry sees something shining in the distance and he moves towards it
                    Viktor tries to zap him but misses. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Get down!<stage> Harry ducks and Viktor gets zapped by Cedric. Cedric
                    runs up and kicks the wand out of Viktor's hand. He points his wand at Viktor's
                    body as if to finish him off, Harry runs up and intervenes. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No stop! He's bewitched Cedric.<stage> They struggle. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Get off me! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He's bewitched!<stage> The two of them begin running towards the cup.
                    The undergrowth grabs Cedric and he falls to the ground. Harry looks back.
                    Cedric is pinned down with no means of escape. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Harry! Harry!<stage> Harry zaps the plantlife and Cedric wriggles
                    free. Harry helps him up. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> You know for a moment there I thought you were gonna let it get me. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> For a moment so did I. </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Some game huh? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Some game.<stage> The wind starts blowing again. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Go. Take it, you saved me! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Together, on three. One, two, three! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" GRAVEYARD"> Harry and Cedric have ported to a graveyard. </stage>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> You ok? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah, you? </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Where are we? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I've been here before. </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> It's a portkey. Harry the cup is a portkey. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I've been here before in a dream. Cedric, we have to get back to the
                cup? Now! </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> What are you talking about?<stage> Harry lets out a shout and holds
                    his head, he is in pain. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> What is it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Get back to the cup!<stage> We see Wormtail and Voldemort nearby.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC"> Who are you? What do you want? </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Kill the spare.<stage> Wormtail casts a spell and kills Cedric.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Cedric!<stage> Cedric lays dead on the ground. Wormtail pulls Harry
                    closer, a status grabs hold of Harry and traps him. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Do it, now!<stage> Wormtail drops something into a cauldron, Harry
                    watches on. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> Bones of the father, unwillingly given.<stage> A bone hovers in the
                    air under Wormtail's control, he drops it into the cauldron. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> Flesh of the servent willingly sacrificed.<stage> He takes a knife
                    and slashes his arm over the cauldron. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> Blood of the enemy forcibly taken.<stage> He takes the knife to
                    Harry and cuts at his arm. Harry shouts. Wormtail takes the knife over to the
                    cauldron and lets the drops fall into it. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> The dark lord shall rise again.<stage> The cauldron bursts into
                    flame and a reformed Voldemort emerges. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> My wand Wormtail.<stage> Wormtail hands him the wand and bows
                    deeply. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Hold out your arm. </sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> Master. Thank you master. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> The other arm Wormtail.<stage> Wormtail looks concerned, but does
                    it anyway. Voldemort sticks the wand into Wormtail's arm. The sky changes,
                    others have been summoned. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Welcome my friends. Thirty years it's been, and yet you stand
                before me as though it were only yesterday. I confess myself disappointed, not one
                of you tried to find me.<stage> Voldemort begins slashing angrily at the hooded
                    figures. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Not even you, Lucius. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> My lord. Had I detected any sign or even a whisper of your
                whereabouts. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> There were signs my friend, and more than whispers. </sp>
            <sp who="#LUCIUSMALFOY"> I assure you I never renounced the old ways. The face I have
                been obliged to present each day since your absence, that was my true mask. </sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> I returned. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Out of fear, not loyalty. Still you have proved yourself useful
                these past few months Wormtail.<stage> Voldemort grants Wormtail a new hand.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#WORMTAIL"> Thank you master, thank you. </sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT">
                <stage>To Cedric's corpse</stage> Oh, such a handsome boy. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Don't touch him.<stage> Harry struggles to get free. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Harry! I'd almost forgotten you were here. Standing on the bones
                of my father. I'd introduce you but word has it you're almost as famous as me these
                days. The boy who lived. How lies have fed your legend Harry. Shall I reveal what
                really happened that night thirteen years ago? Shall I divulge how I truly lost my
                powers? It was love. You see when dear sweet Lily Potter gave her life for her only
                son she provided the ultimate protection. I could not touch you. It was old magic,
                something I should have forseen. But no matter, no matter. Things have changed, I
                can touch you now!<stage> Voldemort puts his hand on Harry's head and he screams.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Astonishing what a few drops of your blood will do eh Harry? Pick
                up your wand Potter. I said pick it up, get up. Get up! You've been taught how to
                duel I presume yes? First we bow to each other. Come on now Harry the niceties must
                be observed, Dumbledore would not want you to forget your manners now would he? I
                said bow!<stage> Voldemort forces Harry to bow with magic. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> That's better. And now...<stage> Voldemort casts at Harry and he
                    wriggles in pain. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Atta boy Harry, your parents would be proud. Especially your
                filthy mongrel mother. I'm going to kill you Harry Potter, I'm going to destroy you.
                After tonight no one will ever again question my powers. After tonight if they speak
                of you they'll speak only of how you begged for death, and I being a merciful lord
                obliged. Get up.<stage> Voldemort pulls Harry to his feet, Harry begins to move
                    away. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Don't you turn your back on me Harry Potter I want you to look at
                me when I kill you, I want to see the lights leave your eyes.<stage> Harry takes
                    steps toward Voldemort. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Have it your way.<stage> They both cast and their streams of magic
                    meet. They both struggle. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Do nothing. He is mine to finish. He's mine!<stage> Shapes form in
                    the surrounding magical energy. We hear Dumbledore's voice. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#JAMESPOTTER">
                <stage>voice</stage> Harry when the connection is broken you must get to the
                portkey. We can delay it for a moment to give you time but only a moment, do you
                understand? </sp>
            <sp who="#CEDRIC">
                <stage>voice</stage> Harry take my body back will you? Take my body back to my
                father. </sp>
            <sp who="#LILYPOTTER">
                <stage>voice</stage> Let go. Sweetheart you're ready. Let go! Let go!<stage> The
                    connection breaks, Harry runs over to Cedric's body and summons the cup over to
                    them. In an instant the port out. Voldemort looks angry. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> No! </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" ARENA"> Back at the arena Harry appears with Cedric's body. The
                crowd don't understand what has taken place and they all cheer, triumphant music
                starts to play. Harry weeps on Cedric's body. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Harry! Harry!<stage> Dumbledore tries to prize Harry from
                    Cedric's body. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Tell me what happened! </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> He's back, he's back! Voldemort's back. Cedric, he asked me to bring
                his body back. I couldn't leave him, not there. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> It's alright Harry. It's alright, he's home, you both are. </sp>
            <sp who="#FUDGE"> Keep everybody in their seats. A boy has just been killed. The body
                must be moved Dumbledore, there are... too many people. </sp>
            <sp who="#AMOS"> Let me through! That's my son! My boy!<stage> Amos breaks down wailing.
                    The crowd look on distraught. </stage></sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" DARKENED ROOM"> Mad-Eye Moody enters and closes the door behind
                him. Harry is in the room still sobbing. They sit. </stage>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Are you alright Potter?<stage> Harry nods. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Does it hurt? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Not so much now. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> I'd better take a look at it.<stage> We see Harry's arm, it has a
                    skull and snake marking. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> The cup was a portkey. Someone had bewitched it. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> What was it like? What was he like? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Who? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> The dark lord. What was it like to stand in his presence? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> I dunno. It was like I'd fallen into one of my dreams. One of my
                    nightmares.<stage> Mad-Eye starts shaking and struggling for air, he reaches for
                    his bottle but it's empty. He rushes to a chest with other bottles and struggles
                    to find one. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Were there others? In the graveyard, were there others? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Um. I don't think I said anything about a graveyard Professor. </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Marvellous creatures dragons aren't they? Do you think that miserable
                oaf would have led you into the woods if I hadn't suggested it? Do you think Cedric
                Diggory would have told you to hold the egg under the water if I hadn't have told
                him first myself? Do you think Neville Longbottom the witless wonder could have
                provided you with gilliweed if I hadn't have given him the book that led you
                straight to it? Huh?? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> It was you from the beginning. You put my name in the goblet of fire.
                You bewitched Krum. But...<stage> Mad-Eye makes sobbing noises making fun of Harry.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> You won because I made it so Potter. You ended up in that graveyard
                tonight because it was meant to be so. And now the deed is done. The blood that runs
                through these veins runs within the dark lord. Imagine how he will reward me when he
                learns that I have once and for all silenced the great Harry Potter.<stage> A flash
                    of magic occurs and Mad-Eye is knocked into the wall. Dumbledore and Severus
                    come rushing in. Dumbledore takes Mad-Eye by the neck... </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Severus...<stage> Severus administers some veritaserum. Mad-Eye
                    wriggles demonically. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Do you know who I am? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> Albus Dumbledore. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Are you Alastor Moody? Are ya? </sp>
            <sp who="#MOODY"> No. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Is he in this room? Is he in this room?<stage> We see a nod.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Harry get away from there!<stage> Dumbledore approaches the
                    chest. The chest opens, it contains a series of smaller chests. When the final
                    chest is open we see that there's a pit within holding a man the real Alastor
                    Moody. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Are you alright Alastor? </sp>
            <sp who="#ALASTOR"> I'm sorry Albus. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> That's Moody, but then who's...?<stage> Dumbledore holds up one of
                    Mad-Eye's Bottles. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#SEVERUS"> Polyjuice potion. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Now we know who's been stealing it from your store
                    Severus.<stage> Dumbledore looks into the pit. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> We'll get you up in a minute.<stage> Alastor Moody groans. The
                    Mad-Eye Moody they have captive in a chair begins to twitch about restlessly
                    making strange noises. He appears to be transforming. He rips off his fake
                    eyepiece which falls on the floor, we see that he's transformed into Barty
                    Crouch Junior. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Barty Crouch Junior. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTYJR"> I'll show you mine if you show me yours.<stage> Barty Jr rolls up
                    his sleeve to reveal a skull and snake marking. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Your arm Harry. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTYJR"> You know what this means don't you? He's back. Lord Voldemort has
                returned. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Send an owl to Azkaban, think they'll find they're missing a
                prisoner. </sp>
            <sp who="#BARTYJR"> I'll be welcomed back like a hero. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Perhaps. Personally I've never had much time for heroes. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" ASSEMBLY ROOM"> </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
                <stage>Speaking to all pupils</stage> Today we acknowledge a really terrible loss.
                Cedric Diggory was as you all know, exceptionally hard working, intricately fair
                minded. And most importantly a fierce fierce friend. I think therefore you have the
                right to know exactly how he died. You see, Cedric Diggory was murdered by Lord
                Voldemort. The ministry of magic does not wish me to tell you this. But not to do so
                I think would be an insult to his memory. Now the pain we all feel at this dreadful
                loss reminds me, reminds us that while we may come from different places and speak
                in different tongues, our hearts beat as one. In light of recent events the bonds of
                friendship we made this year will be more important than ever. Remember that and
                Cedric Diggory will not have died in vain, you remember that. And we'll celebrate a
                boy who was kind and honest and brave and true right to the very end. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="INT" where=" BEDROOM"> Harry is sitting on a bed, Dumbledore walks in. </stage>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I never liked these curtains. Set them on fire in my fourth year,
                by accident of course. I put you in terrible danger this year Harry I'm sorry. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Professor, when I was in the graveyard there was a moment... um...
                when Voldemort's wand and mine sort of connected. </sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Priori Incantatem. You saw your parents that night didn't you?
                They reappeared.<stage> Harry nods. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> No spell can reawaken the dead Harry I trust you know that. Dark
                and diffiult times lie ahead. Soon we must all face the choice between what is right
                what is easy. But remember this, you have friends here. You're not alone. </sp>
        </scene>
        <scene>
            <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS"> There's a large crowd gathered, the pupils are going
                home. Viktor Krum gives Hermione a kiss and hands her some paper. </stage>
            <sp who="#VIKTOR"> Write to me. Promise. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Bye.<stage> Ron is sitting alone. The french sisters approach him,
                    they both in turn give him a kiss on the head. </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#FLEUR"> Au revoir Ron.<stage> The Beauxbatons girls leave in uniform, the
                    crowd applauds. The Durmstrang boys leave too, shaking hands as they go.
                </stage></sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Do you think we'll ever just have a quiet year at Hogwarts? </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No. </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> No I don't think so. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Everything's going to change now isn't it? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes. </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Promise you'll write this summer. Both of you. </sp>
            <sp who="#RON"> Well I won't. You know I won't! </sp>
            <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry will won't you? </sp>
            <sp who="#HARRY"> Yeah. Every week.<stage> They look over the balcony, the flying horses
                    pulling a carriage head off into the distance. The Bulgarians' ship goes
                    underwater. </stage></sp>
            <stage>FADE OUT.</stage>
        </scene>
    </script>
</xml>
