<?xml-model href="potterScripts.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<xml>
 <header>
  <title>HARRY POTTER AND THE SORCERER'S STONE </title>
  <screenWriter>Steve Kloves </screenWriter>
  <!-- Based on the novel by J.K. Rowling -->
  <productionStart date="2000-09"/>
  <!--Optional: if available: September 2000 -->
  <!-- <productionEnd date="yyyy-mm-dd"  Optional: if available: March 2001 -->
  <release date="2001-11-16"/>
  <!--Look this up and verify -->
  <digitalProject>
   <editor who="#bca">Bianka Alexander</editor>
   <advisor who="#ebb">Elisa Beshero-Bondar</advisor>
   <span from="2020-10-01" to="2021-05-06"/>
   <desc>.......</desc>
   <sourceText>
    <siteName>.....</siteName>
    <link><!--Website URL --></link>
    <dateRetrieved>2020-10-01</dateRetrieved>
   </sourceText>
  </digitalProject>

 </header>
 <script>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" PRIVET DRIVE NIGHT "> Dark at this hour, except for the STREET LAMPS
    that dot the street, spilling deep pools of light upon the ground. On the far corner, a MAN
    MATERIALIZES out of the darkness. He is tall and thin, with a silver beard long enough to tuck
    into his belt. He wears a PURPLE CLOAK and is roughly one hundred and fifty years old. He is
    ALBUS DUMBLEDORE. Dumbledore removes a small silver object from his cloak-the PUT-OUTER. He
    extends his hand and--CLICK--the nearest street lamp GOES OUT with a soft pop. He continues to
    click the Put-Outer until all the lamps go DARK. He turns, spies a CAT, sitting on the wall of
    Number Four. He smiles knowingly </stage>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I should have known you'd be here, Professor McGonagall.<stage> The cat
     leaps forward, TRANSFIGURES itself into a rather severe-looking woman in an EMERALD CLOAK.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Are the rumors true, Albus? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
    <stage>(smile fading) </stage> I'm afraid so. The good. And the bad. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> And the boy? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Hagrid's bringing him. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> You think it ... wise ... to trust Hagrid with something as important as
    this? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> I would trust Hagrid with my life, Professor. <stage> A LOW RUMBLE
     disturbs the skies. Dumbledore and McGonagall lookup and--suddenly--a HUGE MOTORCYCLE plummets
     through the clouds, hits the ground with a THUNDEROUS ROAR. As the SMOKE clears, a FIGURE
     climbs off. He is HAGRID and is, quite obviously, a GIANT. In his vast, muscular arms, he holds
     a BUNDLE of BLANKETS. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Ev'ning, Professor Dumbledore, sir. Professor McGonagall. </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> No problems, I take it, Hagrid? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> No sir. Little tyke fell ter sleep as we was flyin' o'er Bristol . <stage>
     Hagrid steps forward and Dumbledore takes the bundle, turns toward the doorstep. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Albus, do you really think it best to leave him here; with these people?
    I've been watching them all day. They're the worst sort of Muggles imaginable. They're ... </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> The only family he has. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> But this boy will be famous. There won't be a child in our world who
    doesn't know his name ... </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Exactly. It would be enough to turn any boy's head. Famous before he can
    walk and talk. Famous for something he won't even remember. No. He'll be much better off growing
    up away from all that. Until he's ready. <stage> Dumbledore lays the bundle on the mat. Hagrid
     SNIFFLES. There, there, Hagrid. It' s not really goodbye, after all. Hagrid nods. Dumbledore
     tucks a PARCHMENT the ENVELOPE into blankets and steps back, his face suddenly dark. Serious.
     Good luck, Harry Potter. The CAMERA DOLLIES forward, toward the swaddled baby. A CUT, still
     fresh, gleams on the baby's forehead. It is in the shape of a BOLT of LIGHTNING. SMASH CUT TO
     TEN YEARS LATER. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" CUPBOARD-NUMBER FOUR PRIVET DRIVE - MORNING "> A pair of blinking GREEN
    EYES jerk into the light. </stage>


   <sp who="#WOMAN'SVOICE">
    <stage>(O.S.) </stage> Up! Now! <stage>THUMP! THUMP! ! THUMP! </stage> I said now! </sp>

   <stage>FOOTSTEPS RECEDE and HARRY POTTER, now ten years old, swings his skinny legs to the floor.
    He's small, which is lucky since his room is not really a room at all, but merely a cupboard
    under the stairs . Abruptly, the cupboard begins to SHAKE, DUST spilling from the joists above
    Harry's head. Calmly, Harry takes a pair of EYEGLASSES--taped at the bridge with Sellotape--from
    a nail. </stage>

  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" HALLWAY - DAY  "> Harry comes blinking out the cupboard door, watches
    his enormous cousin, DUDLEY, thunder down the last step. Just then, Harry's Aunt Petunia appears
    in the kitchen ahead. </stage>
   <sp who="#AUNT PETUNIA "> There's the birthday boy! Don't you look smart for your trip to the
    zoo. <stage>(scowling at Harry) </stage> You mind the bacon. And don't dare let it burn. I want
    everything perfect on my Dimplin' s special day . </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Yes, Aunt Petunia. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" KITCHEN - DAY  "> Harry enters, finds his UNCLE VERNON reading the Daily
    Mail behind a monstrous PILE OF PRESENTS. </stage>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Bring my coffee, boy. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Yes, Uncle Vernon. <stage> Dudley enters, stares at the presents .
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> How many are there? </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Thirty-six. Counted them myself. </sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> Thirty-six. But last year ... last year I had thirty-seven ... </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Well now, son, some of these are quite a bit bigger than last year- </sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> I DON'T CARE HOW BIG THEY ARE! </sp>
   <sp who="#AUNT PETUNIA "> Now, now, here's what we'll do. Today, when we're out, we'll buy you
    two more presents. How's that, popkin? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> So then I 'll have ... I' ll have ... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Thirty-eight, popkin. <stage> Aunt Petunia cuffs Harry on the head on her way
     to the RINGING TELEPHONE. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#AUNT PETUNIA "> You just mind that bacon! </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Yes, Aunt Petunia. <stage> As Dudley tears open a BOX of LEAD SOLDIERS, Uncle
     Vernon ruffles his hair. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Want your money's worth, don't you, tiger. Well, look there. Aunt
    Marge's sent you the Fourth Battalion. <stage> Dudley twists the head off one. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> This one's lost its head. </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Well now, son. Remember, we talked about this. They're not meant to
    move ... <stage> As Dudley tosses the damaged soldier aside, Harry studies it closely, then ...
     Aunt Petunia HANGS UP the phone, turns. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#AUNT PETUNIA "> Bad news. Mrs. Figgs' broken her leg. She can't take him. </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> We could phone Yvonne. </sp>
   <sp who="#AUNT PETUNIA "> Don't be silly. She hates the boy. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> You could just leave me here. </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> And come back to find the house in ruins? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> I... Don't... Want... Him... To... Come! He... always... spoils...
    everything! </sp>
   <sp who="#AUNT PETUNIA "> Now, precious, don't cry. He won't spoil anything. What if Mummy buys
    you three more presents. </sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> Three? </sp>
   <sp who="#AUNT PETUNIA "> As many as you want, sweetums. <stage> As Aunt Petunia cuddles him,
     Dudley shoots Harry a nasty grin through the gap in his mother's arms. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" NUMBER FOUR PRIVET DRIVE - A BIT LATER "> As Harry gets in the car,
    Uncle Vernon leans close. </stage>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> I'm warning you now, boy. Any funny business, any at all, and you'll
    have no meals for a week. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" ZOO - DAY "> Happy children walk hand in hand with their parents, as...
   </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" REPTILE HOUSE... LATER - DAY "> Dudley presses his pudgy nose to a
    gleaming plate of glass </stage>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> Make it move. <stage> Uncle Vernon looks over a zoo map at the HUGE BURMESE
     PYTHON curled beyond the glass. RAPS his knuckles. Nothing. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> He's asleep. </sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> He's boring.路 Dudley waddles away and the others follow, all but Harry, who
    steps forward and rubs Dudley's nose print from the glass. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Sorry about him. He doesn't understand what it's like, lying there day after
    day, watching people press their ugly faces in on you... <stage>The snake nods. Harry stops,
     looks off, then back. WHISPERS: </stage> Can you hear me? <stage>The snake cocks its head
     and... winks. </stage> It's just, I've never talked to a snake before. Do you, I mean... do you
    talk to people often? <stage>The snake regards Harry ... then slowly shakes its head no. Harry
     nods, looking a bit unnerved. </stage> So ... you're from Burma, aren't you? Was it nice there?
    Do you miss your family? <stage>(listening) </stage> I see. That's me as well. I never knew my
    parents either... </sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> MUMMY! DAD! COME HERE! You won't what this snake is doing! <stage> Dudley
     JABS Harry hard in the ribs, sending him tumbling to the concrete floor. Angry, Harry looks up
     as Dudley leans against the glass and it... VANISHES. Dudley flops forward, the snake slithers
     out, and people run screaming. Stunned, Harry watches the python slip into the sunshine, then
     glances back to the snake tank. The glass has reappeared and Dudley sits within, face pale,
     eyes frozen in terror. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" NUMBERFOUR PRIVET DRIVE - LATER DAY "> Uncle Vernon, face purple with
    rage, drags Harry by the ear. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I swear, I don't know how it happened! One minute the glass was there and then
    it was gone. It was like magic. <stage> Uncle Vernon hurls Harry into the cupboard, stares hard.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON "> There's... no ... such... thing... as... magic! <stage> The door SLAMS.
     Harry sits quietly. Then, from his pocket, he removes the damaged soldier Dudley had discarded
     earlier. Reaching up, he places it on a dark shelf, next to half a dozen others. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" NUMBERFOUR PRIVET DRIVE MORNING "> A single OWL swoops down onto the
    Dursley's roof. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" KITCHEN MORNING "> Dudley parades about the kitchen in knickerbockers,
    tailcoat and straw boater, tapping the floor with a KNOBBLY STICK, while a teary Aunt Petunia
    snaps a photo with a FLASH CAMERA. </stage>
   <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA "> Oh, Vernon, look at him. To think in only a week he'll be off to
    Smeltings. </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON "> Proudest moment of my life. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(with dread) </stage> Will I have to wear that too? </sp>
   <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA "> You! Go to Smeltings? Don't be stupid. You'll go to state school, where
    you belong. That there'll be yours, once I'm done dying it. <stage> Harry glances at a tub of
     grey mud boiling on the stove. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But that's Dudley's old uniform. It'll fit me like bits of old elephant skin. </sp>
   <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA  "> Fit you fine enough. Now fetch the post. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" FRONTHALL- DAY  "> Three letters lie on the mat. A bill. A postcard. An
    envelope of YELLOW PARCHMENT. Harry takes all, then stops, staring at the envelope, which is
    addressed in EMERALD INK. Mr. H. Potter The Cupboard Under The Stairs 4 Privet Drive Little
    Whinging Surrey Harry turns the envelope over, finds a PURPLE WAX SEAL. It is a COAT OF ARMS,
    surrounding a large letter H. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" KITCHEN - DAY  "> Harry drops the post on the table and sits, staring in
    quiet wonderment at his envelope. Uncle Vernon takes the postcard. </stage>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Marge's ill. Ate a funny whelk ... <stage> BAM! Dudley brings the
     Smelting stick down hard on the table . </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> Dad! Look! Harry's got a letter! <stage> Quickly, Uncle Vernon SNATCHES it
     away. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> That's mine! </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Yours. Who'd be writing to you-<stage> Uncle Vernon's face goes pale.
    </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" HALLWAY- DAY "> The boys come flying into the hall, throw themselves
    against the door as it slams shut. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I want my letter! </sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> I want my stick! <stage> Harry and Dudley make a furious play for the
     keyhole, but Dudley's size proves too much and Harry, glasses dangling from one ear, settles
     for the crack between door and floor. HARRY'S POV of Uncle Vernon's thick black shoes pacing
     back and forth. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA "> Vernon. Look at the address. How could they possibly know where he
    sleeps? You don't think they're watching the house? </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON "> Watching. Spying. Following us. We both know the dangerous nonsense your
    sister and her husband were mixed up in. </sp>
   <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA "> But what should we do, Vernon? Should we write back. Tell them we don't
    want- </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON "> No. We'll ignore it. If they don't get an answer... Yes, that's best...
    I'll burn it. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> NO! I WANT MY LETTER! <stage> Uncle Vernon walks to the stove, flips on a gas
     jet. As the letter BURNS, Harry POUNDS the door, and a MONTAGE BEGINS: </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" ROOF - NUMBER FOUR PRIVET DRIVE - MORNING "> An OWL beats its way across
    the sky, flutters down upon the TV ANTENNA, where TWO . OTHER OWLS already sit. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LIVING ROOM - SAME TIME"> A frowning Uncle Vernon stands before the
    TELLY, struggling to unscramble a RUGBY MATCH. The CLICK of the MAIL SLOT is heard and he turns.
   </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" FRONT HALL - DAY "> THREE MORE LETTERS lie on the mat. Uncle Vernon
    enters, snatches them up, RIPS them to pieces. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" CUPBOARD - DAY "> Harry sits sadly upon his bed, when ... BANG! BANG!
    BANG! </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" FRONT HALLWAY - MOMENTS LATER "> Harry eases open the cupboard door.
    Down the hallway, Uncle Vernon stands swinging a hammer, mouth bulging with-nails as he POUNDS
    SHUT the mail slot. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" NUMBERFOUR PRIVET DRIVE - MORNING "> Uncle Vernon exits the house with
    his briefcase, stops. FOUR OWLS sit atop his Vauxhall. He watches curiously as they take flight,
    then looks down. FOUR LETTERS lie at his feet. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LIVING ROOM - NIGHT "> The FIREPLACE BLAZES. Uncle Vernon pitches a
    handful of LETTERS into the flames, turns. Harry stands watching. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" ROOF - NUMBER FOUR PRIVET DRIVE - SAME TIME "> As the CHIMNEY SMOKES,
    FIVE OWLS sit in black silhouette against a full moon. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" KITCHEN WINDOW - NUMBER FOUR PRIVET DRIVE - MORNING "> Aunt Petunia
    cracks an EGG. Inside is a LETTER. She cracks another. Another LETTER. We PAN off the window to
    Dudley' s neglected BICYCLE. Perched atop the handlebars, seat and tires are SIX OWLS. MONTAGE
    ENDS. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LIVING ROOM - SUNDAY MORNING - DAY "> Dudley lies on the floor,
    destroying another birthday toy, as Aunt Petunia carefully sets a cup of coffee by Uncle Vernon,
    who sits in an armchair smiling strangely. </stage>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Fine day, Sunday. Best day of the week in my opinion. Know why I say
    that, Dudley? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(entering)</stage> Because there's no post on Sundays. <stage> Uncle Vernon looks up
     brightly, but Harry's eyes are on the window behind him. Outside, the sky is DARK WITH OWLS.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Right you are, Harry! No damn letters today! No sir. Not one blasted
    ... <stage> Just then, something WHIZZES DOWN the chimney and SMACKS Uncle Vernon flat on the
     back of the head. Seconds later another follows, and then another, until the living room is
     aflock with ... LETTERS. Harry leaps onto a table, trying to snag one, when Uncle Vernon seizes
     him by the waist . </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" HALLWAY - DAY"> As Uncle Vernon stumbles out, Harry shakes free of his
    grasp and stares dumbly: LETTERS swirl up and down the hall. </stage>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> Who on earth wants to talk to you this badly! <stage> A letter flutters on
     Harry's fingertips ... before Uncle Vernon sweeps it away, eyes crazed, SHOUTING CRAZILY:
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> That does it! We're going away! Far away! Where they can't find us!
    Where they can't get to us! <stage> Dudley glances at his mother </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY "> Daddy's gone mad, hasn't he? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" HUT ON THE ROCK - NIGHT "> A very sad-looking HUT sits perched upon a
    large ROCK far at sea. Wind whistles. The sea rages. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" HUT ON THE ROCK - NIGHT  "> Uncle Vernon and Aunt Petunia sleep on a
    lumpy bed in the hut's only bedroom. Dudley SNORES on a moth-eaten sofa. Harry lies on the bare
    floor beneath a ragged blanket. LIGHTNING FLASHES. As the room goes dark again, Harry studies
    the lighted dial of Dudley's watch. As it ticks toward midnight, Harry puts the last touches to
    a BIRTHDAY CAKE he's etched in the dust that layers the floor. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Make a wish, Harry. <stage> Closing his eyes, he ... blows ... and the
     "flames" of dust scatter. Eyes still closed, Harry holds the wish when... BOOM! The DOOR
     SHUDDERS. HINGES squeal. A pin squirrels out of its housing. Falls to the floor. BOOM! Uncle
     Vernon comes sledding into the room in his socks, a RIFLE in hand, paper hanging by a string
     from the. barrel. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> Who's there'? I warn you--I'm armed! <stage> SMASH! The door falls
     flat. An IMMENSE SILHOUETTE stands against the raging sea outside, identical to the beastly
     figure seen climbing the stairs in Godric's Hollow. He is HAGRID and is, rather obviously, a
     GIANT. Presently he is standing on the front door. 路 路 </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Er, right. Sorry 'bout that ... <stage> Hagrid steps clear, takes the door,
     and fits it back into its frame. Glances at Dudley. Frowns. Mind, I haven't seen yeh since you
     was a baby, Harry, but yeh' re a bit more along than I woulda expected. 'Specially round the
     middle. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUDLEY ">
    <stage>(terrified)</stage> I'm not Harry. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I am. <stage> Hagrid turns, watches Harry's face come into the light.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Well now, course yeh are. </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> I demand that you leave at once, sir! You are breaking and entering! </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Ah, dry up, Dursley, yeh great prune. <stage>Hagrid takes the rifle, knots it
     like a piece of licorice. </stage> Anyway, Harry. Got summat fer yeh. 'Fraid I mighta sat on it
    at some point, but 'magine it'll taste all right jus' the same... let's see now... got it here
    somewhere ... <stage>Hagrid rummages in his coat, removes: a kettle, frying pan, sausages, one
     PINK UMBRELLA and, finally, a squashed paper box containing a CHOCOLATE CAKE with "Happee
     Birthdae, Harry" scrawled in green icing. </stage> Baked it meself, words an' all. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Thank you . </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Well, it's not ev'ry day yer young man turns 'leven. <stage> Hagrid turns to
     the fireplace, gives the embers a poke with the pink umbrella. As they ROAR to life, he takes
     the frying pan, lobs in the sausages. Dudley perks up as they sizzle. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Excuse me, but ... who are you? <stage> Harry stares blankly. Hagrid frowns.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID  "> Blimey, Harry, did yeh never wonder where yer parents learnt it all? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Learned what? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> What? DURSLEY!!! Do yeh mean ter tell me the boy knows nothin? <stage> Uncle
     Vernon stands mute. Hagrid simmers, then shakes his head and turns back to the fire. Harry, yer
     a wizard. For a moment, the hut is utterly silent. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> I'm a what? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> A Wizard. And a thumpin' good 'un, I'd wager, once yeh've been trained up a
    bit. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> No. You've made a mistake. I ... I can't be a ... wizard. I mean ... I'm just
    ... Harry. Just Harry. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Tha' right. Tell me, Harry. Ever make somethin' strange 'appen? When yeh was
    scared maybe. Or angry? <stage> As Harry looks up in recognition, Hagrid slaps a soggy ENVELOPE
     into Harry's hand. Harry opens it, reads. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> 'Dear Mr. Potter, We are pleased to inform you that you have been accepted at
    Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry ... ' <stage> As Harry looks up, Hagrid winks, and
     takes a bite of sausage. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON "> He'll not be going, I tell you! We swore when we took him in we'd put a
    stop to that rubbish! </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> You knew? You knew I'm a ... a wizard? <stage> Aunt Petunia--looking
     furious--emerges from the shadows. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#AUNTPETUNIA "> Of course we knew! How could you not be, my dratted sister being what
    she was? Oh, mother and father were so proud when the letter came. A witch in the family. Isn't
    it wonderful. I was the only one who saw her for what she was ... a freak!
     <stage>(distastefully) </stage> Then she met that Potter and had you. I knew you'd be the same.
    Just as strange, just as abnormal. And then, if you please, she went and got herself blown up
    and we get landed with you- </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Blown up? You told me my parents died in a car crash. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> CAR CRASH! A car crash kill Lily and James Potter? It's an outrage! A
    scandal! </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLE VERNON "> HE'LL NOT BE GOING, I TELL YOU! </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> An' I s'ppose a great Muggle like yerself is gcin' ter stop him. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Muggle? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Non-magic folk. <stage>(turning to Uncle Vernon)</stage> This boy's name's
    been down ever since he was born. He's off to the finest school of witchcraft and wizardry in
    the world and he'll be under the greatest headmaster Hogwart's has ever known, Albus
    Dumbledore-- </sp>
   <sp who="#UNCLEVERNON "> I will not pay for some crackpot old fool to teach him magic tricks!
     <stage> Hagrid spins, eyes bulging. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> NEVER ... INSULT ALBUS ... ... DUMBLEDORE ... IN ... FRONT... OF ... ME!
     <stage> Hagrid spins, points the umbrella at Uncle Vernon, then spies Dudley, one hand deep in
     Harry's birthday cake. POP!-a FLASH of VIOLET LIGHT hits Dudley square in the rump. Instantly,
     a PIG'S TAIL curls through the back of his trousers. Uncle Vernon ROARS, hurries everyone out
     of the room.</stage> 
    Tha' s curious. Meant ter turn 'im into a complete pig, whole hog an' all. suppose
     be was so much like a pig already, there wasn't much left ter do. Hagrid sees Harry staring in
     awe at the pink umbrella. Er, be grateful if yeh didn't mention that to anyone at Hogwarts.
     Strictly speakin', I'm not allowed ter do magic. <stage>(checks pocket watch) </stage> Bit
     behind schedule, aren't we? Best be off. Hagrid exits, leaving Harry to consider his sorry
     surroundings. He looks momentarily at a loss, then ... Hagrid pokes his head back in. 'Less o'
     course, yeh'd rather stay. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" STREET LONDON - DAWN  "> Harry, reads ALOUD from his LIST as he trails
    Hagrid, who draws an eye . or two-- as a giant in Central London will. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> 'First year students will require three sets of plain work robes, one plain
    pointed hat for day wear, one pair of dragon-hide gloves...'<stage> Hagrid chuckles at a PARKING
     METER. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Things these Muggles dream up ... </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" TRAIN LONDON - DAWN  "> Harry sits beside Hagrid, continues to read from
    his list. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> ' ... and the following Set Books: The Standard Book of Spells by Miranda
    Goshawk. One Thousand Magical Herbs and Fungi by Phyllida Spore ... ' </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where="STREET /LEAKY CAULDRON - LONDON - DAWN"> Hagrid leads Harry on, parting
    the crowd easily. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> 'One wand, one standard Size 2 pewter cauldron and may bring, if they desire,
    either an owl, a cat, or a toad.' <stage>(looking up) </stage> Can we find all this in London?
     <stage> Hagrid pauses by a NARROW GRAY DOOR that stands between a BOOK SHOP on one side and a
     RECORD SHOP on the other. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> If yeh know where to go. <stage> A dark, shabby pub. In corner, some OLD
     WOMEN sit drinking, one smoking a pipe as long as her arm. Up front, a TINY MAN in a TOP HAT
     talks to the BARTENDER, who resembles gummy walnut. Harry and Hagrid enter. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#BARTENDER "> Hagrid! The usual, I presume <stage>(spying Harry)</stage> Good Lord. Is
    this? Can this be him? Bless my soul. It's Harry Potter. <stage> The pub goes quiet. Then ...
     everyone is up and around Harry, holding out their hands and gabbling, while Hagrid looks on,
     beaming. Slowly, a NERVOUS YOUNG MAN makes his way forward. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL "> Harry P-P-Potter. C-Can't tell you how p-pleased I am to meet you. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Professor! Didn't see yeh there. Harry, this Professor Quirrell. He'll be yer
    Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts. </sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL "> F-F-Fearfully f-fascinating subject. NNot that you n-need it, eh,
    P-P-Potter? <stage> Quirrell's eyes flutter nervously over Harry's scar. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Yes, well, must get on. Lots ter buy, <stage>(as he pulls Harry along)
    </stage> See? Tol' yeh you was famous. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where="BACK COURTYARD/LEAKY - MOMENTS LATER"> Hagrid TAPS the bricks of one wall
    with the tip of his umbrella while Harry stands by, deep in thought. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Why am I famous, Hagrid? All those people back there. How is it they know who
    I am? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Don' know that I'm the right one ter tell yeh that, Harry. Let's see now ...
    Three up ... Two across ... Right. Stand back now. <stage> Hagrid gives the wall one last TAP
     and the bricks QUIVER, wriggling and jiggling until an ARCHWAY appears, giving out on a COBBLED
     STREET so long and twisting it seems never to end. As Harry's jaw drops, Hagrid grins. Welcome,
     Harry. To Diagon Alley. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" DIAGON ALLEY - CONTINUOUS MORNING"> As Harry steps through, the archway
    SHRINKS INSTANTLY into a solid wall. All around him, Harry sees mothers and fathers with
    children in tow, clutching LISTS similar to his own. </stage>
   <sp who="#PLUMPWOMAN "> Seventeen Sickles an ounce for Dragon Liver, can you imagine? They're
    mad! </sp>
   <sp who="#MOTHER "> It says brass, Trevor. As such, you will get brass. </sp>
   <sp who="#BOY "> There it is! The Nimbus Two Thousand! Runs a good twenty times faster than the
    old Comets. Neil Marks himself rides it for the Chudley Cannons. </sp>
   <sp who="#FATHER "> Mind you don't drop your bottle of eel's eye, Belinda. I'll not buy you
    another. <stage> Harry tries to take in everything at once, marveling at shops specializing in
     everything from cauldrons, owls and broomsticks to robes, 'unmentionables,' and spell books.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Dragon Liver? Do they mean from a real dragon'? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Well, they don't mean a ruddy penguin. Crikey, I'd like a dragon. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> You'd like a dragon'? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Vastly misunderstood beasts, Harry. Vastly misunderstood ... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(staring in a cauldron shop) </stage> But how am I to pay for all this, Hagrid? I haven't
    any money. <stage> Hagrid gestures to a TOWERING, SNOW-WHITE BUILDING ahead. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> There's yer money. Gringotts. Wizard's. Bank. No place safer, Harry. Not one.
    'Cept perhaps Hogwarts. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GRINGOTTS-DAY "> ONE HUNDRED GOBLINS sit on high stools at a long
    counter, scribbling in ledgers, weighing coins in brass scales. As Harry and Hagrid enter, a
    clever-looking goblin closes the door behind them, watches their every step. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Hagrid, what exactly was that? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Yer basic Door Goblin. Clever as they come goblins, but not yer most friendly
    beasts. Best stay close. <stage>(stepping up to a teller) </stage> Mornin'. Mr. Harry Potter
    wishes to make a withdrawal. </sp>
   <sp who="#GOBLIN "> And Mr. Harry Potter has his key? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Let's see, got it 'ere somewhere ... <stage>The Goblin looks on disfavorably
     as Hagrid rifles his coat, producing in rapid succession: a jangly RING of KEYS, one BALL of
     STRING, a fistful of MINT HUMBUGS, two TEABAGS, and a MOTH..... which simply flutters from one
     pocket to 路another. </stage> Ah, 'ere' s the li' l devil. <stage>(leaning close) </stage>
    There's another matter as well. I've got a letter from Professor Dumbledore. It's about the
    You-Know-What in Vault You-Know-Which. </sp>
   <sp who="#GOBLIN "> Very well. I'll have Griphook take you. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" STONE PASSAGEWAY DAY-GRINGOTTS "> CLOSE ON: GRIPHOOK ... a swarthy,
    slit-eyed goblin, driving a small cart with white-knuckle precision down a STONE PASSAGEWAY with
    lit FLAMING . TORCHES. They plunge deeper, come ... ... whistling to a halt before a SMALL DOOR.
    Griphook steps out, takes Harry's key and UNLOCKS the vault, revealing great glittering pyramids
    of coin. Harry is speechless. </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Din' think yer parents would leave yeh with nothin', did yeh? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" CART - PASSAGEWAYS - A FEW MINUTES LATER"> The cart hurtles even
    DEPEPER, abruptly stops. </stage>
   <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> Vault Seven Hundred Thirteen. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> What's in here, Hagrid? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Can't tell yeh that, Harry. Hogwarts business. Very secret. <stage>Griphook
     steps up to a door with no keyhole, strokes it with one long finger, and it simply MELTS
     away.</stage> Anyone but a Gringotts goblin tried that, they'd be sucked through the door. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> How often do you check to see if anyone's inside? </sp>
   <sp who="#GRIPHOOK"> About once every ten years.<stage> Harry peers into the vault, sees... a
     GRUBBY LITTLE PACKAGE. Hagrid slips it into his LEFT COAT POCKET, returns. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Best not mention this ter anyone either, Harry. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" DIAGON ALLEY - LATER - DAY"> Harry and Hagrid exit the Apothecary,
    loaded with Harry's various purcahses. Harry studies the list in his hand. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I still need ... a wand. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID ">
    <stage>(points ahead) </stage> Only place for wands, is Ollivanders. You go inside. I got one
    more thing I gotta' do. <stage>Harry nods, walks into Ollivanders. </stage>
   </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" OLLIVANDERS WAND SHOP - DAY "> Harry and Hagrid stand in a very narrow
    shop where thousands of slender boxes are stacked to the ceiling. Hovering above them on a
    spindly ladder is a pale old man with eyes like silver moons. He is OLLIVANDER. </stage>
   <sp who="#OLLIVANDER "> I wondered when I'd be seeing you, Mr. Potter. Seems only yesterday your
    mother and father were in here buying their first wands ... <stage>Ollivander steps down with a
     pair of slender boxes. (extending a box)</stage> Here we are. Just give it a wave.
     <stage>Feeling a bit supid, Harry raises his arm. Nothing. </stage> No. Apparently not. Perhaps
    this. <stage>Harry raises it and ... BRIGHT LIGHT shoots a CRYSTAL VASE OF BLACK ROSES
     shattering forth... to the sending floor. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#OLLIVANDER "> No. No. Definitely not. No Matter. After all ... it's the wand that
    chooses the wizard. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" OLLIVANDERS WAND SHOP - LATER"> HUNDRED OF WAND BOXES lie at Harry's
    feet. Hagrid, eyes heavy, sits on a spindly chair. Ollivander, meanwhile, stands at the top of a
    spindly ladder, eyeing his inventory. </stage>
   <sp who="#OLIVANDER"> I wonder... <stage>Olivander descends, presents a box. Stifling a yawn,
     Harry takes the wand... and his expression changes.</stage> Go on then. <stage>As Harry extends
     his arm, his hand trembles. A breeze stirs, sending the shop's tiny bell RINGING. The pages of
     a . BOOK FLUTTER on the counter, and Harry's hair feathers off his forehead, showing his scar.
     Astounded, Harry smiles and then... Ollivander slips the wand from his fingers and the breeze
     dies, the shop returning to its eerie calm.</stage> Curious. Very curious. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Sorry, but what's curious? </sp>
   <sp who="#OLLIVANDER"> I remember every wand I've ever sold, Mr. Potter. It so happens that the
    phoenix whose tail feather resides in your wand, gave another feather. Just one other. It's
    curious that you should be destined for this wand when its brother <stage>(eyes shifting)
    </stage> gave you that scar. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> And who owned that wand? <stage>Ollivander exchanges a surprised glance with
     Hagrid. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> We don't speak his name, Harry. </sp>
   <sp who="#OLLIVANDER "> As I said, the wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter. It's not always clear
    why. But I think it's clear we can expect great things from you. After all,
    He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named did great things. <stage>Ollivander slides the lid on the box, hands it
     to Harry. </stage> Terrible, yes. But great. <stage>Harry looks out the window, sees Hagrid
     standing there, holding a cage with a snow white owl inside. Harry turns to say goodbye to
     Ollivander. He's gone. Harry runs outside. </stage>
   </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" DIAGON ALLEY - DAY "> Harry runs up to Hagrid, looks at the owl. </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Happy Birthday, Harry. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(excited) </stage> For me? Really? He's Mine? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Crikey, yeh'd think yeh hadn't gotten. a birthday present before. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> I haven't. Not really. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LEAKY CAULDRON "> Hagrid and Harry sit at a table in the corner. Hagrid
    dips a spoon into a huge bowl of soup, looks up. </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> You all right, Harry? Yer very quiet. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(touching his scar) </stage> He killed my parents, didn't he? The one who gave me this.
    You know, Hagrid. I know you do. <stage>Hagrid studies Harry, conflicted, then sets down his
     spoon. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> 'Course I know. Who do yeh think carried yeh out o' yer parents' house,
    Hallowe'en night, ten years ago? Who do yeh think brought yeh ter Dumbledore an' watched him lay
    yeh on yer Aunt an' Uncle's doorstep? 'Course I know, Harry. <stage>Hagrid leans in closer, his
     eyes glimmering in the dim pub. </stage> Firs', un'erstand this, 'cause it's important: not all
    yer wizards are good. Some go bad. Years ago, there was this one wizard who weent as bad as you
    could go. His name was... was... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Maybe if you wrote it down. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Nah--can' spell it. All right-- Voldemort. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Voldemort? <stage> Hagrid shivers, holds up his hand, and glances quickly about
     the shadows of the pub before continuing. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Dark days those were, Harry. Volde... You-Know-Who... started lookin' fer
    followers. Got 'em too. Anyone that stood up to him ended up dead. Including yer parents. No one
    lived once he decided to kill 'em. Not one. 'Cept you. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Me? Voldemort tried to kill me? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> That's no ord'nary cut on your forehead. A mark like that only comes when
    yeh've been touched by a curse. An evil curse. <stage> Just then, a HIGH, CACKLING VOICE pierces
     the silence. Harry turns, sees an OLD WOMAN laughing with the gummy bartender. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But what happened to Vol... to You-Know-Who? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Some say he died. Codswallop, in my opinion. I reckon he's out there
    somewhere, jus' too weak to carry on. But one thing's fer certain, Harry. Somethin' about you
    stumped him that night. That's why you're famous. That's why e'ryone knows yer name.
     <stage>Hagrid leans close once more and this time his voice is barely a WHISPER. </stage> You
    're the boy who lived. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene><stage cat="EXT" where="KING's CROSS STATION - DAWN"> Harry and Hagrid, laden with a heavy
    TRUNK and SNOWY OWL, stand outside the station in the shimmering dawn light. Hagrid checks his
    WATCH, looks suddenly urgent. </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Blimey, look at the time. 'Fraid I 'ave ter be leavin' yeh now, Harry.
    Dumbledore will be wantin' <stage>Hagrid pats his LEFT POCKET. Catches himself. </stage> He'll
    be wantin' 'ter see me. <stage>(handing him a TICKET)</stage> That there's yer train. Leaves in
    about ten minutes time. Jus' make sure yeh stick ter yeh ticket. That's very important, Harry.
    Stick ter yeh ticket... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> There must be something wrong, Hagrid. This says Platform Nine and Three
    Quarters. There's no such thing.
    <stage>Harry looks up, but Hagrid is gone. </stage> ...Is there?  </sp></scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="LOWER LEVEL - KING'S CROSS MOMENTS LATER"> Harry dashes through a
    bustling King's Cross, sledding to a halt in front of a pair of PLATFORM SIGNS. One reads NINE.
    One reads TEN. Harry turns to a passing STATION OFFICER. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Excuse me. Can you tell me where I might find Platform Nine and
    Three-Quarters. </sp>
   <sp who="#STATION OFFICER ">
    <stage>(grumbling off)</stage> Think you're funny, do you? Nine and Three-Quarters indeed...
    Harry looks about, despairingly, then HEARS... </sp>
   <sp who="#MRS.WEASLEY">
    <stage>(O.S.)</stage> ...packed with Muggles, of course. <stage>Harry turns, sees a plump woman
     (MRS. WEASLEY) hurrying along FOUR RED-HEADED BOYS and their little, red-headed sister (GINNY).
     The boys all tow trunks identical to Harry's. </stage> All right, Percy. You first.
     <stage>Harry watches the tallest boy walk straight toward a dividing barrierand... VANISH.
     Harry squints in confusion. Next, Mrs. Weasley turns to a pair of cheeky twins (FRED and
     GEORGE). </stage> Fred. You next. </sp>
   <sp who="#FRED "> I'm not Fred I'm George. Honestly, woman, you call yourself our mother? </sp>
   <sp who="#MRS. WEASLEY "> Sorry, George. </sp>
   <sp who="#FRED "> Only joking. I am Fred. <stage> Fred dashes off, trailed by George. They too
     vanish. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Excuse me. Could you tell me-- </sp>
   <sp who="#MRS. WEASLEY "> How to get onto the platform? Not to worry, dear. It's Ron's first time
    to Hogwarts as well. <stage>Harry looks at the youngest red-haired boy. He is tall, gangly, and
     presently has a SMUDGE on his nose. </stage> All you have to do is walk straight at the barrier
    between Platforms Nine and Ten. Focus ... but don't stop and don't be scared you'll crash into
    it either. Best do it at a bit of a run if you're nervous. <stage> Harry looks. Shrugs.
     Sprinting at full speed, the barrier coming closer and closer, he shuts his eyes and...
    </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene><stage cat="EXT" where=" PLATFORM NINE AND THREE QUARTERS - DAY  "> ... SLEDS onto a
    platform milling with people. A sign above reads HOGWARTS EXPRESS. Below it sits a SCARLET STEAM
    ENGINE .. Harry glances behind, sees a wrought-iron archway where the barrier had been, with the
    words PLATFORM NINE AND THREE QUARTERS on it. Just beyond, he sees Kings Cross and the world
    he's left behind. </stage>
   <stage>NEW ANGLE ON PLATFORM Harry struggles with his heavy trunk as all around him
   people say goodbye to their families. A round-faced boy (NEVILLE LONGBOTTOM) turns frantically to
   his GRAN.</stage> <sp who="#NEVILLE "> Gran! I've lost my toad again. </sp>
   <sp who="#GRAN "> Oh, Neville. Honestly. Not again... <stage> Further up, a BOY IN DREADLOCKS
     (LEE JORDAN) holds a BOX. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#STUDENT "> Go on, Lee. Give us a look. <stage> As Lee lifts the LID, a LONG HAIRY LEG
     protrudes and students SHRIEK. Unimpressed, one of the twins spots Harry struggling.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#GEORGE "> Want a hand? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Yes, please. </sp>
   <sp who="#GEORGE "> Oy! C'mere, Fred! Take a handle. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" PLATFORM - FURTHER ALONG - SECONDS LATER "> Fred and George heave
    Harry's trunk atop other, similar trunks while Harry sets Hedwig with the owls. Harry wipes his
    sweaty hair off his brow... revealing his scar. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Thanks very much. </sp>
   <sp who="#GEORGE "> Blimey. You're... </sp>
   <sp who="#FRED "> Harry Potter. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What'? Oh, him. Yes. I mean, I am. </sp>
   <sp who="#MRS. WEASLEY "> Fred! George! Come say goodbye to Ginny. Mrs. Weasley stands waving,
    the redheaded girl clinging to her dress. The twins take one last look at Harry, dash off. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="TRAIN COMPARTMENT/EXT. PLATFORM - DAY"> Harry exits the crush of the
    aisle, enters an empty compartment. Very much alone, he sits, peers out the window as Percy
    Weasley strides forth in billowing BLACK ROBES. </stage>
   <sp who="#PERCY "> Have to go, Mother. The other Prefects are expecting me up front. </sp>
   <sp who="#FRED "> Mum! Guess who's on the train? Right now... </sp>
   <sp who="#FRED #GEORGE"> Harry Potter! </sp>
   <sp who="#GINNY "> Oh, Mum, can I go on and see him? Please. </sp>
   <sp who="#MRS. WEASLEY "> Certainly not. The boy isn't something you goggle at in a zoo.
     <stage>(as the WHISTLE BLOWS) </stage> All right, on you go, all of what is that on your nose?
     <stage>She goes for a handkerchief, but Ron spins away. She sighs, calls after the
     twins.</stage> You two watch out for your brother. And behave yourselves this year. If I get
    one more owl teeling me you've blown up a toilet or something-- </sp>
   <sp who="#FRED "> Blown up a toilet? We've never blown up a toilet. </sp>
   <sp who="#GEORGE "> Great idea, though, thanks, Mum! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS EXFRESS - DAY "> As the train moves out of the station, Ginny
    chases after. Harry watcher her from his window until she drops back. King's Cross, and the life
    he's known, drift away. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" SCOTLAND - HOGWARTS EXPRESS - DAY "> The train whips past fields, small
    country lanes. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" TRAIN COMPARTMENT - DAY"> Harry sits quietly. Then the compartment door
    slides open. Ron stands there. Seeing Harry, he hesitates. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Mind? Everywhere else is full. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Not at all. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I'm Ron, by the way. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I heard. I'm Harry. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I... heard. <stage>(unable to resist) </stage> Is it true? I mean, have you
    really got the... you know... <stage>Without prompting, Harry lifts his hair.. Shows the scar ..
    </stage> Wicked. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Are all your family wizards? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Huh? Oh. I think so. Well, Mum's got a second cousin who's an accountant. But we
    never talk about him. I heard you went to live with Mugg1es. What are they like? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Horrible. Well, not all of them. Mine are, though. Trade them for three wizard
    brothers any day. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Five. I'm the sixth in our family to go to Hogwarts. Everyone expects me to do
    as well as the others. But if I do, it's no big deal because they did it first. You never get
    anything new, either, with five brothers. I've got Bill's old robes. Charlie's old wand. Even
    Scabbers used to be Percy's... <stage>Ron reaches into his pocket, pulls out a fat, gray,
     seemingly unconscious, RAT (SCABBERS). </stage> Hardly ever wakes up. He's useless basically.
    Percy got an owl for making Prefect, but Mum and Dad couldn't afford-- I mean, I got Scabbers
    instead. <stage> Ron looks embarrassed. Just then, a DIMPLED WOMAN pushing a TROLLEY FULL OF
     SWEETS pops her head in. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DIMPLED WOMAN "> Anything off the trolley, dears? <stage> Ron mumbles 'No thanks,'
     takes out a lumpy sandwich. Harry studies him, then digs into his pockets, heavy with coin.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> We'll take the lot. <stage> CLOSE UP: TROVE OF TREATS </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" TRAIN COMPARTMENT DAY - LATER "> ... spread out on an empty seat. Harry
    marvels at the strange, wondrous candies before him. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> 'Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans'? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> They mean every flavor. There's chocolate, peppermint... but you can also get
    liver or spinach or tripe. George reckons he had a bogey-flavored one once. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> These aren't real 'frogs, are they? <stage> Harry holds up a pack of
     "CHOCOLATE FROGS"--something is wriggling under the foil--then sees that Ron already has a very
     realistic leg squirreling out the corner of his mouth. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON ">
    <stage>(mumbling) </stage> Just a spell. Besides, it's the card you want. Each pack's got a
    Famous Witch or Wizard. Got about 500 myself. Watch it! <stage>As Harry breaks the foil on his
     pack, the frog springs into the air and out the open train window. </stage> That's rotten luck.
    They've only got one good jump in them to begin with. <stage>Harry glances at the card in his
     hand. On it, there's a MAN with a crooked nose, long silver beard, and half-moon glasses.
     Underneath is a name: ALBUS DUMBLEDORE. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I've gotten Dumbledore! </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I've about six of him. Trade you Scabbers though, if you get Agrippa or Ptolemy. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(reading the back) </stage> Considered by many the greatest wizard of modern times,
    Dumbledore is particularly famous for his defeat of the dark wizard Grindelwald in 1945, for his
    discovery of the 12 uses of dragon's blood, and his work on alchemy with his partner, Nicolas
    Flamel. Approximately one hundred and fifty years old, Professor Dumbledore enjoys chamber
    music, tenpin bowling, and...' <stage>(looking up) </stage> One hundred arid fifty years old? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Thought he'd be older, did you? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> No-- I--Hey, he's gone. <stage> Harry holds up the card--now blank--to Ron,
     who only shrugs. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON"> Well, you can't expect him to hang around all day, can you? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> It's just, in the Muggle world, people stay put in photos. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Really? They don't move at all? Weird! <stage>Just then, Scabbers SNORTS, falls
     back asleep. </stage> Pathetic, isn't it? Fred gave me a spell that's to turn him yellow. Want
    to see? <stage> Harry nods, eager to see some magic. Ron pulls out a BATTERED WAND--just as the
     compartment door OPENS and a GIRL with bushy brown hair and rather large front teeth looks in.
     She is HERMIONE GRANGER and is already wearing her school robes. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Has anyone seen a toad? A boy named Neville has lost one. <stage>(seeing
     Ron's wand) </stage> Oh, are you doing magic? Let's see then. <stage> She sits down. Ron looks
     a bit taken aback, but clears his throat nonetheless, poises his wand over Scabbers.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Sunshine, daisies, butter mellow, Turn this stupid. fat rat yellow. <stage>
     Scabbers SNORTS, but otherwise remains fat, grey, and asleep. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Are you sure that's a real spell? Well, it's not very good, is it? I've
    only tried a few simple ones myself but they've all worked for me. For example ... <stage>To
     Harry' surprise, Hermione takes her wand, points it directly over his brow, then...
     stops.</stage> Goodness. You're Harry Potter, aren't you? I know all about you, of course. I
    was doing a little recreational reading and you're in Modern Magical History, The Rise and Fall
    of the Dark Arts and Great Wizarding Events of the 20th Century. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Am I? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Didn't you know? I'd have found out everything I could if it was me.
     <stage>(raising her wand) </stage> Anyway ... Oculus Reparo. <stage>Instantly, the cracked
     bridge of Harry's glasses is mended. </stage> There. That's better, isn't it? I'm Hermione
    Granger, by the way. And you are ... ? 路 <stage>Ron is still staring at the glasses, feeling a
     bit outdone. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Um... Ron Weasley. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Pleasure. Do either of you know what House you'll be in? I'm hoping for
    Gryffindor--I hear Dumbledore himself was in it--but I think I might just die if they put me in
    Slytherin. That was You-Know- Who' s House. Anyway, you two had better change into your robes. I
    expect we'll be arriving soon. You've got dirt on your nose, by the way, did you know? <stage>
     As she exits, Harry and Ron just sit, staring at the door. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=". HOGSMEADE STATION - HOGWARTS - NIGHT "> As the scarlet engine HISSES to
    a stop, Harry and the others spill out. Harry's robes shimmer grandly, while Ron's secondhand
    silks show a bit too much sneaker. </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Firs' years! Firs' years over here!<stage> Hagrid gives Harry a wink as he
     comes loping out of the darkness, swinging a LAMP. Ron, preoccupied with wiping his nose clean
     on his robes, stops, dumbstruck by Hagrid's size. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" BLACK LAKE - NIGHT - MOMENTS LATER"> A FLEET of TINY BOATS glides
    silently over a glassy lake. Harry rides with Ron, Hermione and Neville Longbottom, gazing at
    the DARK TREES of the FOREST that surrounds them. A GLINT OF SILVER flickers through the black
    trees, like a dream. Harry watches, transfixed, then... </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> You there! Don' be trailin' yer fingers in the water. Yeh might find yeh don'
    get 'em all back. <stage> Harry turns, sees that Hagrid is speaking to a POINTY-FACED. BOY
     (DRACO MALFOY). Malfoy eyes Hagrid darkly, whispers to a PAIR OF THICK-LOOKING BOYS (CRABBE and
     GOYLE). Harry peers into the black water, sees his own pale face looking back, then a soft
     GLITTER of REFLECTED LIGHT dances on the surface. He looks up, watches a magnificent CASTLE
     drift into view. Hogwarts. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" ENTRANCEHALL - HOGWARTS CASTLE - NIGHT "> Harry and the others enter a
    grand entryway lit with flaming torches. PROFESSOR MCGONAGALL, a rather severe-looking witch in
    an emerald cloak, stands before a pair of TOWERING DOORS. She lifts her chin, surveys the new
    students. </stage>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Welcome to Hogwarts. In a moment, you will pass through these doors and
    join your classmates, but before you can take your seats,you must be sorted into your Houses.
    They are Gryffindor, Hufflepuff, Ravenclaw, and Slytherin. While here, your House is, in many
    ways, your family. Your triumphs will earn your House points, while any rule-breaking will lose
    points. At the end of the year, the House with the most is awarded the House Cup, a great honor.
    I hope each of you...<stage> Just then, a rather LARGE TOAD springs forth, CROAKS. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE "> Trevor! <stage> Neville, blissfully relieved, gathers his toad, then peers
     up from the hem of Professor McGonagall's robes. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> ...will be a credit to whichever House becomes yours. The Sorting Ceremony
    will begin momentarily. <stage> Professor McGonagall glowers at Neville, then exits. As she
     goes, there is a BRIEF CLAMOR of SOUND from the students waiting in the Great Hall beyond.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> How exactly do they sort us? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Some kind of test, I think. Fred says it hurts like hell, but I'm sure he was
    joking. At least... I think he was. <stage> Just then, Draco Malfoy pushes through the crowd,
     shadowed by the boys from the boat. Malfoy stares openly at Harry's scar. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO  "> It's true then, what they were saying on the train. Harry Potter has come to
    Hogwarts. <stage>Harry's eyes slide, appraise the other two boys. </stage> Oh. This is Crabbe
    and Goyle. And my name's Malfoy. Draco Malfoy. <stage>Ron COUGHS, masking a snigger. Malfoy's
     eyes narrow. </stage> Think my name's funny, do you? No need to ask yours. Red hair, freckles,
    and a hand- me-down robe--you must be a Weasley. <stage>(to Harry)</stage> You'll soon find out
    some wizarding families are better than others, Potter. You don't want to go making friends with
    the wrong sort. I can help you there. <stage> Malfoy extends his hand, but Harry's gaze remains
     level. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I think I can tell the wrong sort for myself, thanks. <stage> Malfoy's eyes
     glitter with rage. Finally he drops his hand, turns away. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE . "> Well, he's rather disagreeable, isn't he? <stage> Ron and Harry turn, see
     Hermione. Just then, Professor McGonagall returns. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> We are ready for you. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - NIGHT "> Harry and the others file into a strangely
    splendid place lit by THOUSANDS OF CANDLES FLOATING in midair over four long tables lined with
    students. Harry looks to the windows below the ceiling, finds glorious stars and an icy blue
    moon. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> It' s not real, the ceiling. It's only bewitched to look like the night
    sky. I read about it in Hogwarts, A History. <stage> Professor McGonagall sweeps to the front of
     the room where a WIZARD'S HAT--patched and frayed--sits on a stool. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Before we begin, Professor Dumbledore would like to say a few words.
     <stage> Harry watches with great interest as the great wizard himself rises from his seat at
     the High Table. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Yes, and here they are: Nitwit! Blubber! Oddment! Tweak! Thank you!
     <stage> The Great Hall THUNDERS with APPLAUSE. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I hear he's a genius. <stage> As the applause subsides, the hat TWITCHES.
     At the brim, a rip OPENS WIDE, and the hat begins to TALK. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#SORTINGHAT  "> Oh, you may not think I'm pretty But don't judge on what you see I'll
    eat myself if you can find A smarter hat than me. There' s nothing hidden in your head The
    Sorting Hat can't see So try me on and I will tell you Where you ought to be.... <stage> As the
     students APPLAUD, the hat takes a bow and Professor McGonagall steps forward with a ROLL OF
     PARCHMENT. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> When I call your name, you will come forth, put on the hat and be sorted.
     <stage>(consulting her list) </stage> Hermione Granger. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Oh dear. Here it is, isn't it? The moment. Goodness. What if the hat says
    nothing and we're all just left standing here forever ... </sp>
   <sp who="#RON ">
    <stage>(as she goes mumbling off) </stage> Mental, that one. I'm telling you. <stage> Both watch
     Hermione seat herself, lower the Hat. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#SORTING HAT "> GRYFFINDOR! <stage> Percy pulls out a chair for Hermione at the
     Gryffindor table. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Draco Malfoy. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Slytherin. <stage> Draco Malfoy swaggers forth and grips the hat. He's barely
     touched it to his head, when: </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#SORTING HAT "> SLYTHERIN! </sp>
   <sp who="#RON">
    <stage>(off Harry's amazement) </stage> There's not a witch or wizard who went bad who wasn't in
    Slytherin. Draco's father was one of the first to join You-Know-Who when he got power. And one
    of the first to come back when he lost it. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL. "> Susan Bones. <stage> As SUSAN BONES dashes up front, Harry glances to
     the High Table. Dumbledore watches the proceedings placidly, while Professor Quirrell talks to
     a hook-nosed man with greasy black hair and sallow skin, PROFESSOR SNAPE. Slowly, as if he can
     feel Harry's gaze, Snape turns, looks straight into Harry's eyes. Instantly, a sharp, hot PAIN
     shoots across Harry's scar. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Ouch! </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Harry? What is it? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> N-nothing. I'm fine. </sp>
   <sp who="#SORTING HAT "> Hufflepuff! <stage> As Susan Bones runs off... </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Ronald Weasley. <stage> As Ron steps nervously away, Harry glances back
     to the High Table. Snape has returned to his conversation. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#SORTING HAT "> Gryffindor! <stage> Fred and George WHOOP LOUDLY as Ron comes grinning
     out of the hat, greatly relieved. Harry starts to clap himself when... </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Harry Potter. <stage>There is an abrupt drop in the CHATTER. As Harry
     makes his way, he avoids the eyes of the many who stare and whisper. </stage> If you will, Mr.
    Potter. <stage> Harry sits, takes the hat, and... slowly... lowers it. He waits, then the hat
     begins to SPEAK. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#SORTING HAT "> Hmmm. Difficult. Very Difficult. Plenty of courage, I see. Not a bad
    mind either. There's talent, oh yes, and a thirst to prove yourself. But where to put you...?
     <stage>Harry grips the edge of the stool, closes his eyes. His lips move ever so slightly: Not
     Slytherin. Not Slytherin.</stage> Not Slytherin, eh? Are you sure? You could be great, you
    know, it's all here in your head, and Slytherin will help you on the way to greatness, no doubt
    about that... No? Well, if you're sure... better be GRYFFINDOR! <stage> A ROAR erupts from the
     Gryffindor table. Harry stands shakily and walks to his table, where Percy, the Weasley twins,
     and Hermione all welcome him. At the High Table, Dumbledore lifts his goblet and, meeting
     Harry's eyes... nods. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - LATER "> Freshly sorted and seated, the Gryffindor first
    years watch in amazement as the empty plates before them suddenly... fill with food. There is
    roast beef, chicken, pork chops, lamb chops, sausages, bacon, steak--the feast of all feasts.
    Harry listens as a rather wild-looking boy named SEAMUS talks to another student, DEAN THOMAS. </stage>
   <sp who="#SEAMUS "> I'm half and half. Me dad's a Muggle, Mam's a witch. Bit of a nasty shock for
    him when he found out. <stage> As Percy leans over to pour a strange liquid into Harry's goblet,
     Harry nods to the High Table, to Professor Snape. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Say, Percy. Who's that teacher talking to Professor Quirrell? </sp>
   <sp who="#PERCY "> Hm? Oh. Professor Snape. Head of Slytherin House </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What's he teach? </sp>
   <sp who="#PERCY"> Potions. But everyone knows it's the Dark Arts he fancies. Been after
    Quirrell's job for years. <stage>Just then, several STUDENTS SHRIEK as a volley of GHOSTS stream
     into the hall overhead. One swoops down. </stage> Hello, Sir Nicolas. Have a nice summer? </sp>
   <sp who="#NEARLY HEADLESS NICK "> Dismal. What with the Slytherins winning the House Cup six
    years in a row, the Bloody Baron's become unbearable. <stage>Nick nods his head in the direction
     of the Slytherin table, where a horrific, BLOOD-STAINED GHOST hovers imperiously. </stage> Then
    again, he's always been unbearable. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON  "> I know you. You're Nearly Headless Nick. </sp>
   <sp who="#NEARLY HEADLESS NICK "> I prefer Sir Nicolas, if you don't mind. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Nearly headless? How can you be nearly headless? </sp>
   <sp who="#NEARLY HEADLESS NICK "> Like this. <stage> Seizing himself by the left ear, Nick swings
     his ENTIRE HEAD off his neck and onto his shoulder, as if it were on a hinge. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE ">
    <stage>(blanching) </stage> I think I'm done eating. <stage> Just then, Dumbledore rises at the
     High Table. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> If I may, I have a few start-of-term notices to announce. First Years
    should note that the Dark Forest is strictly forbidden to all pupils. Also, our caretaker, Mr.
    Filch has asked me to remind you that... <stage>FILCH, a sour-looking man, stands near a side
     exit while MRS. NORRIS, a cat with glittering REDEYES, sits by his feet. </stage> ... no magic
    should be used between classes in the corridors. And finally, please note that this year, the
    third floor corridor on the right hand side is out of bounds to everyone who does not wish to
    die a most painful death. <stage>Hearing this, Ron stops chewing for the first time, glances at
     Harry. But before either can speak...</stage> And now, let us sing the school song! Everyone
    pick their favorite tune and off we go! <stage>Professor McGonagall rolls her eyes slightly as
     Dumbledore wields his wand. Consulting the PARCHMENT of LYRICS placed beside their plates,
     Harry and his fellow First Years join a rousing, but rather dischordant, chorus of VOICES.
    </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#SCHOOL SINGING "> Hogwarts, Hogwarts, Hoggy Warty Hogwarts Teach us things worth
    knowing Bring back what we've forgot Just do your best, we'll do the rest And learn until our
    brains all rot ... </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" MARBLESTAIRCASE - HOGWARTS - LATER - NIGHT  "> As the new Gryffindors
    follow Percy up the staircase, Harry stares in wonderment at the PORTRAITS on the walls: the
    people in them MOVE. </stage>
   <sp who="#PERCY "> This is the most direct path to the dormitory, except on Fridays, of course,
    when the staircases change. <stage>As the staircase before them moves to the right, Percy waits
     briefly, then leads on without comment to a... </stage>
   </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="7TH FLOOR CORRIDOR - MOMENTS LATER - NIGHT"> ...a new corridor. Up ahead,
    Harry spies a bundle of WALKING STICKS floating in midair. Without warning, the walking sticks
    come flying forth. As the First Years duck and dodge, Percy sighs in annoyance. </stage>
   <sp who="#PERCY "> Gryffindors, I givee you Peeves, Hogwarts resident poltergeist<stage> POP! A
     tiny translucent man with wicked eyes and wide mouth appears, clutching the last walking stick.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#PEEVES "> Oooh! Ickle Firsties ! What fun! <stage> With that, Peeves swoops off,
     wagging his tongue and bouncing a walking stick off Neville's head. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#PERCY ">
    <stage>(walking on)</stage> Rather a nuisance, I'm afraid. Ah. Here we are. <stage> At the very
     end of the corridor, hangs a PORTRAIT of a WOMAN in a pink silk dress. She looks at Percy.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#PINK LADY "> Password? </sp>
   <sp who="#PERCY "> Caput Draconis. <stage> The portrait SWINGS FORWARD, revealing a ROUND HOLE in
     the wall. The students all scramble through it, into the ... </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GRYFFINDOR COMMON ROOM - NIGHT "> The students enter a cozy, round room,
    filled with squashy armchairs. At the top of a SPIRAL STAIRCASE, are two DOORS. </stage>
   <sp who="#PERCY "> Girls' dormitory to the left. Boys to the right. You'll find your belongings
    have already been brought up. Any questions? <stage>(no one speaks) </stage> Then, goodnight
    all. Oh, and don' t forget. Before retiring, please place all living potion ingredients in your
    cupboards. This includes slugs, fire beetles and cutworms. Sweet dreams... </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" BOYS TOWER DORMITORY - LATER - NIGHT"> Moonlight falls through the tower
    windows as Ron, Neville and Seamus slumber. As we find Harry, he is sleeping too, but it is not
    restful. He twitches and turns... there is a FLASH OF GREEN... then he awakens with a start,
    sits up. Trembling. He glances about the room, then lies slowly back. Eyes open. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="STAIRWAY - 12 NORTH - HOGWARTS - MORNING"> The stairway bustles with
    students as Harry and Ron make their way. Clearly lost, Ron consults his TIMETABLE. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> This is Staircase Twelve North, which should take us to Backward Staircase
    Seven--no wait a minute, we're on Backward Staircase Seven... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> How many staircases are there? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> One hundred forty-two, though, in A History of Magic, Bathilda Bagshot
    makes unattributed reference to three others. <stage> Harey and Ron watch Hermione pass by,
     apparently holding every single First Year course book in her arms, </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON"> I hate her. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="MCGONAGALL'S CLASSROOM - MORNING"> Students sit attentively, looking
    front... at a CAT. Its markings, particularly around the eyes, are somehow familiar. Harry and
    Ron burst in, glance around. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Whew! We made it, mate. Can you imagine old McGonagall's face if we were late
    first day out... <stage>Hearing this, the cat narrows its eyes, leaps up and... TRANSFORMS...
     into old McGonagall herself. Ron's mouth drops open in amazement. </stage> That was bloody
    brilliant! </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Thank you for that assessment, Mr. Weasley. But perhaps it might be more
    useful if I transfigured Mr. Potter or yourself into a pocket watch. That way one of you might
    be on time. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> We got lost. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Then perhaps a map. I trust you don't need one to find your seats?
     <stage>Harry and Ron slink past Hermione, sitting front row center. </stage> Transfiguration is
    some of the most complex, dangerous and valuable magic you will learn at Hogwarts. Use it
    skillfully and it may, one day, save your life. Make a mistake and you could find yourself with
    a toad's head and a monkey's tail. <stage>(opening a textbook) </stage> All right then .. Shall
    we? <stage> Harry and Ron exchange a glance, whip open their books. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" DUNGEONS - POTIONS - NEXT MORNING - DAY "> As Professor Snape paces
    imperiously, Harry and the others sit in dead silence, eyes wandering to the PICKLED ANIMALS
    floating in GLASS JARS along the cold stone walls. </stage>
   <sp who="#SNAPE "> There will be no foolish wand waving or silly incantations in this class. As
    such, I don't expect many of you to appreciate the subtle science and exact art that is potion
    making. However, for those select few... <stage>(glances at Malfoy) </stage> ... who possess the
    predisposition, I can teach you how to bewitch the mind and ensnare the senses. I can tell you
    how to bottle fame, brew glory, even stopper death. Then again, maybe some of you have come to
    Hogwarts in possession of abilities so formidable that you feel confident enough to... not pay
    attention. <stage>Harry blinks, realizes Snape is looking at him. </stage> Mr. Potter. Our
    new... celebrity. Tell me. What would I get if I added powdered root of asphodel to an infusion
    of wormwood? <stage>Harry looks at a loss. Hermione's hand shoots into the air. </stage> You
    don't know. Well, let's try again. Where, Mr. Potter, would you look if I told you to find me a
    bezoar? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I don't know, sir. </sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE "> And the difference between monkshood and wolfsbane? <stage> Harry sees Malfoy,
     Crabbe and Goyle sniggering. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I don't know, sir. </sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE "> Pity. Clearly fame isn't everything, is it, Mr. Potter. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Clearly Hermione knows. It seems a pity not to ask her. <stage> Neville,
     Seamus and a few other Gryffindors LAUGH. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE"> Silence! And put your hand down, you silly girl! <stage>Hermione wilts. Snape
     steps toward Harry, eyes glimmering. </stage> For your information, Potter, asphodel and
    wormwood make a sleeping potion so powerful it is know as the Draught of the Living Dead. A
    bezoar is a stone taken from the stomach of a goat and it will save you from most poisons. As
    for monkshood and wolfbane, they are the same plant, which also goes by the name of ... aconite.
     <stage>(to the others) </stage> Well, why aren't you all copying this down? <stage>The students
     scramble for their quills and parchment.</stage> And Gryffindors. Note,that five points will be
    taken from your House for your classmate's cheek. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - LATER - DAY "> Harry stares glumly at the FOUR HOURGLASSES
    as the PRECIOUS GEMS drop in Gryffindor's, rise in Slytherin's. Down the table, Seamus is
    MUTTERING. </stage>
   <sp who="#SEAMUS "> Eye of rabbit, harp string hum... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What's Seamus trying to do to that glass of water? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Turn it to rum. Actually managed a weak tea yesterday before it...
     <stage>PFFFT!BLUE FLAMES shoot over the rim of the glass. </stage> Two Knuts says he loses his
    eyebrows by week's end. Ah, mail's here. <stage>DOZENS OF OWLS circle the ceiling, then swoop
     down, dropping parcels from home. A copy of The Daily Prophet rolls onto the table near Harry.
    </stage> Hey look! Neville's gotten a Remembrall! <stage>Neville holds a GLASS BALL filled with
     WHITE SMOKE. Slowly, the smoke begins to turn a DEEP SCARLET. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I've read about those. If the smoke turns red it means you've forgotten
    something. </sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE "> Only problem is... I can't remember what I've forgotten. <stage> Harry,
     Daily Prophet in hand, nudges Ron. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Hey, Ron. Somebody broke into Gringotts! Listen: 'Believed to be the work of
    Dark wizards or witches unknown, Gringotts goblins, while acknowleging the breach, insist
    nothing was taken. The vault in question had, in fact, been emptied earlier that very same day.'
    That's odd. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> It's mad. Dad says there are dragons guarding some of the vaults. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> No. It's just odd... That's the day Hagrid and I were there. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" THE GROUNDS - HOGWARTS - DAY  "> Harry stands in a cluster of
    Gryffindors, across from Malfoy and his Slytherin cronies. Between them, there is a LONG LINE OF
    BROOMSTICKS. MADAME HOOCH, a rangy witch with short grey hair and hawk-like eyes, stands between
    the two groups. </stage>
   <sp who="#MADAME HOOCH "> Welcome to your first Flying Lesson. Well, what are you all waiting
    for? Everyone step up to a broomstick. Come now. Hurry up. <stage>Harry steps forward nervously,
     glances down. His broom is old, with twigs sticking out at odd angles. </stage> Stick out your
    right hand, over the broom, and say "Up"! <stage>SHOUTS of "Up!" ring on the cold afternoon air.
     Though he barely WHISPERS the command, Harry's broom SNAPS smartly into his hand. Hermione's
     simply rolls over. Ron's FLIES UP and CRACKS HIM IN THE NOSE.</stage> Now. Once you've got hold
    of the broom, I want you to mount it. And grip it tight. We don't want you sliding off the end.
     <stage>(walking the row) </stage> Your other right hand, Mr. Finnegan. Goodness, boy, what have
    you done with your eyebrows? </sp>
   <sp who="#SEAMUS "> Lost 'em, ma'am. </sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO"> Excuse me, Madam Hooch. Given that a few of us have been on sticks for years,
    would it not make sense to separate the expert flyers from... <stage>(glancing at Harry)</stage>
    the neophytes? </sp>
   <sp who="#MADAME HOOCH "> Thank you, Mr. Malfoy, but I'm sure even an expert flyer such as
    yourself can appreciate the benefits of reacquainting oneself with the basics. Your grip, for
    example. It's thumb in, not out. <stage>As Malfoy reddens, Harry and Ron share a grin. </stage>
    Very well. Now when I blow my whistle, I want each of you to kick off from the ground. Hard.
    Keep your brooms steady, hover for a moment, then lean forward slightly and touch back down. On
    my whistle...Three ... Two ... <stage>Jumping the gun entirely, a nervous Neville shoots
     straight up into the air, like a cork out of a bottle. </stage> Mr. Longbottom! Exactly where
    do you think you're going? <stage>Clutching desperately to his broom, Neville caroms crazily off
     a tree, flops upside down, rockets past the other students--who duck--then soars into a mad
     spiraling climb. </stage> Come down here this instant! <stage>Neville's pale face peers down,
     his eyes roll up...</stage> On your broomstick, Longbottom! <stage>Too late. With a giant THUD
     and a nasty CRACK, Neville hits the pitch. Madame Hooch and the Gryffindors rush over. </stage>
    Broken wrist. Corne on, dear. Up you get. <stage>(leading him off) </stage> Everyone's to keep
    their feet on the ground while I take Mr. Longbottom to the Hospital Wing. Understand? If I see
    a single broom in the air, the one riding it will find themselves out of Hogwarts before they
    can say 'Quidditch.' <stage>As they go, Harry watches Neville's broom sail high over Hagrid's
     house, where the giant himself sits in the front garden, watching with a pair of BINOCULARS.
     Malfoy scoops Neville's Remernbrall from the grass, cackles. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO"> Did you see his face? Perhaps if the great lump had given this a squeeze, he
    would've remembered to fall on his fat arse. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Give it here, Malfoy. </sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO "> No, I think I'll leave it somewhere for Longbottom to find. How about up a
    tree? <stage>Malfoy slings a leg over his broom, KICKS into the air. </stage> What's the matter,
    Potter? A bit beyond your reach? <stage>Harry glowers up at Malfoy, then GRABS his broom.
    </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Harry! No! You heard what Madame Hooch said. Besides you don't even know
    how to fly. <stage> Harry shoots into the sky, so angry that it's a moment before he realizes
     what the others see clearly: he's a natural. Turning his broomstick sharply, he hovers, glaring
     at Malfoy. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Give it here. Or I'll knock you off that ruddy broom. </sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO "> Is that so? <stage>Harry SHOOTS forth like a javelin, Malfoy just managing to
     slip his charge. As Harry whips around, Malfoy glances down at the ground, clearly unnerved.
     Harry simply smiles. </stage> Have it your way, then! <stage>Malfoy hurls the ball high. As it
     plummets, Harry throws himself into a steep dive, rocketing recklessly downward, ignoring the
     earth as it rushes toward him, extending his hand and snatching the ball only feet from the
     ground. He lands running, grinning, as the Gryffindors CHEER. Then...</stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> HAR-RY POT-TER! <stage> Harry's stomach drops. Malfoy grins hideously.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO "> Chin up, Potter. They might let you stay on as Hagrid's assistant. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - HOGWARTS - MOMENTS LATER - DAY  "> Harry trails silently
    after Professor McGonagall. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" ADJOINING CLASSROOM - MOMENTS LATER  "> Professor McGonagall leans into
    an adjacent classroom. </stage>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Excuse me, Professor Quirrell, could I borrow Wood for a moment.
     <stage>Startled, Professor Quirrell jumps, then OLIVER WOOD, a burly fifth-year, emerges,
     glances curiously at Harry. </stage> Potter, this is Oliver Wood. Wood... I've found you a
    Seeker. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" CORRIDOR - HOGWARTS - EVENING "> Harry and Ron walk, buffeted by the
    stream of students heading for dinner. Hermione walks a few steps behind. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Seeker! But first years never make the House teams. You must be the youngest
    Quidditch player in- </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> --a century. According to McGonagall. Just then, Fred and George descend. </sp>
   <sp who="#FRED "> Well done, Harry. Wood's just told us. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Fred and George are on the team too. Beaters. </sp>
   <sp who="#GEORGE "> Our job to make sure you don't get bloodied up too bad. Can't make any
    promises, of course. Rough game, Quidditch. </sp>
   <sp who="#FRED "> Brutal. But no one's died in years Someone will vanish occasionally... </sp>
   <sp who="#GEORGE "> But they turn up in a month or two. <stage> As the twins dash off, Ron reads
     Harry's troubled face. </stage></sp>

   <sp who="#RON"> Oh go on, Harry. Quidditch is great. Best game there is. And you'll be great too. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I've never even played Quidditch. What if I make a fool of myself? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> You won't make a fool of yourself. <stage>Ron and Harry turn. They hadn't
     even noticed Hermione. </stage> It's in your blood. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" TROPHY STAIRCASE - MOMENTS LATER. "> Hermione leads Harry and Ron to a
    DISPLAY CASE. Inside is a history of Quidditch at Hogwarts, with ancient brooms, strange
    equipment, and various. TROPHIES. She points. Etched upon a SILVER TRAY, below a GRYFFINDOR
    LION, one NAME shines: James Potter. Seeker. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Harry ... you didn't tell me your father was a Seeker too. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I... didn't know. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" MARBLE STAIRCASE - MOMENTS LATER "> As Harry and Ron trail Hermione up
    the staircase, Ron WHISPERS. </stage>

   <sp who="#RON"> I'm telling you, it's spooky. She knows more about you than you do. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Who doesn't? <stage> Just then, the staircase LURCHES beneath their feet...
    </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" FORBIDDEN CORRIDOR - CONTINUOUS "> ... and transports them to a very
    dark, very creepy corridor. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Does anybody feel like ... we shouldn't be here? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> We're not supposed to be here. This is the Third Floor. It's forbidden. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(intrigued)</stage> Why, though? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Because Dumbledore said so. Let's go. <stage> Meow. They freeze. A CAT sits
     watching路them, eyes glittering in the dark. Then ... a SHADOW scales the wall. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#FILCH  "> Who goes there! <stage>They turn, dash the opposite way. As they reach a
     DOOR, Harry grips the knob, twists. It's LOCKED. </stage> Lead me to them, my sweet.... </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> That's it. We' re done for. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Oh, move over. Alohomora! <stage>Hermione gives her wand a swish and... the
     door swings open. Harry and Ron stare incredulously. </stage> Standard Book of Spells. Chapter
    Seven. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" FORBIDDEN ROOM - CONTINUOUS  "> As they fall inside, Hermione presses
    her ear to the door. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Chapter Seven? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Shhh! Filch is... gone. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> He probably thinks this door is locked. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> It was locked. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> And for good reason... <stage>Hermione and Ron turn. Standing a feet away is a
     DOG... only this one has three heads, three pairs of mad, rolling eyes, and three sets of
     hideous yellow fangs dripping with saliva. As the dog ROARS, they tumble back outside and...
    </stage>
   </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="3RD FLOOR CORRIDOR"> Harry FLINGS home the DOOR just before the dog
    throws itself against it. They exchange a glance, dash off. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GRYFFINDOR COMMON ROOM - NIGHT "> The Pink Lady frowns as they spill
    through, stand gasping. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> What do they think they're doing keeping a thing like that locked up in school? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> You don't use your eyes, do you? Didn't you see what it was standing on? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I wasn't looking at its feet. I was a bit preoccupied with its heads. Or maybe
    you didn't notice. There were three. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"> It was standing on a trapdoor, which means it's not there by accident. It's- </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Guarding something. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> That's right. Now, if you don't mind, I think I'll go to bed before either
    of you figures out another clever way to get us killed. Or worse... expelled. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" PRACTICE FIELD - DUSK "> Harry stands with Oliver Wood on the empty
    practice pitch. </stage>
   <sp who="#WOOD "> Quidditch is easy enough to understand. Each team has seven players: Three
    Chasers, two Beaters, one Keeper and the Seeker--that' s you. There are three kinds of balls.
    This one's called the Quaffle. <stage>(holds up a red ball) </stage> The Chasers handle the
    Quaffle and try to put it through one of three hoops. The Keeper--that's me--defends the hoops.
    With me so far? <stage> Harry nods, points to a WOOD CRATE rocking violently. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I think so. What's in there? </sp>
   <sp who="#WOOD "> Here. Take this. <stage>Wood hands Harry a SMALL CLUB, kneels before the crate,
     and unlashes a leather strap. Instantly, a BLACK BALL rockets into the sky, then, without
     warning, PLUMMETS straight down--at Harry's head. Startled, Harry jumps aside and--purely on
     instinct--clubs it back into the sky. </stage> Not bad, Potter. You'd make a fair Beater.
    Careful now, it's coming back. <stage>As the ball screams back to earth, Wood crates it.
    </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What was that? </sp>
   <sp who="#WOOD "> Bludger. Nasty little buggers. But you're a Seeker. The only ball I want you to
    worry about is... this. <stage> Wood takes out a TINY BALL about the size of a walnut. BRIGHT
     GOLD, it has little, fluttering WINGS. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I like this ball. </sp>
   <sp who="#WOOD "> You,like it now. Just wait. It's wicked fast and damn near impossible to see. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> What do I do with it? </sp>
   <sp who="#WOOD "> Catch it. Before the other team's Seeker. You catch this, the game is over. You
    catch this, Potter... we win. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="PROFESSOR FLITWICK'S CLASS - DAY"> PROFESSOR FLITWICK, a very tiny,
    gnome-like wizard, stands on a PILE OF BOOKS as he oversees the class. </stage>
   <sp who="#PROFESSORFLITWICK "> Now don't forget that nice wrist movement we've been practising.
    Swish and flick. Swish and flick. <stage> Harry, paired with Seamus, poses his wand over the
     FEATHER before him and begins to swish and flick. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Wingardium Leviosa. <stage> The feather flutters, but never leaves the table.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#PROFESSORFLITWICK "> And enunciate! Never forget Wizard Bartiffio, who said 's' instead
    of 'f' and found himself on the floor with a buffalo on his chest. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> WINGARDIUM LEVIOSA! <stage> Ron windmills his arms grandly. Nothing. Hermione
     frowns. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Honestly. You're going to take someone's eye out. Besides, you're saying it
    wrong. It's Levi-ohhhh-sa. Not路 Levi-o-saaaah. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON"> You do it then, if you're so clever. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Wingardium Leviosa. <stage> Hermione swishes and flicks. Instantly the
     feather rises. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#PROFESSORFLITWICK "> Oh, well done! Everyone see here. Miss Granger's done it! <stage>
     PFFFT! Across the room, SMOKE curls between Seamus and Harry. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I think we're going to need another feather over here, Professor. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" COURTYARD - LATER - DAY "> As Harry and Ron cross the courtyard, Ron
    mimics Hermione. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON"> It's Levi-ohhhhh-sa. Not Levi-o-saaaah. She's a nightmare, honestly. No wonder
    she hasn't got any friends. <stage> Just then, someone BUMPS into Harry. He turns, sees Hermione
     dash by, hugging her books, eyes glittering with tears. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I think she heard you. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - NIGHT"> Candlelit PUMPKINS flicker throughout the hall,
    while THOUSANDS OF LIVE BATS flutter overhead. Harry sits quietly, studying an EMPTY CHAIR, then
    sees Professor McGonagall standing across the way with Hagrid. Both are looking at him.
    McGonagall says something to Hagrid, who nods, then she steps away, approaches Harry. </stage>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> How are you, Potter? All right? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Yes, Professor. Fine. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> I know ... that is, we know... the members of the staff... that this is
    perhaps a difficult night for you. Halloween. Your parents...<stage> Harry realizes what she is
     talking about. Nods. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I'm all right, Professor. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Very well. <stage> She turns, starts to go. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Professor... Thank you. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> You're welcome, Potter. <stage> As she goes, Harry sees Ron glumly
     pushing his food around, listening to Neville speak across the EMPTY CHAIR to Seamus.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE "> Parvati Patil said she wouldn't come out of the girls' bathroom. Said she's
    been in there all afternoon. Crying. <stage> Just then, Professor Quirrell runs into the room,
     CRIES OUT: </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL "> TROLL IN THE DUNGEON! TROLL IN THE DUNGEON!Thought you ought to
     know...<stage> He faints to the floor. There is a brief silence, then utter pandemonium breaks
     out, Students SHRIEK. Bats SCREECH. POP! POP! POP! The hall goes still, all eyes on Dumbledore,
     standing at the front, purple smoke trailing from his wand. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Everyone will please not panic. Prefects, lead your Houses back to the
    dormitories. Teachers, follow me to the dungeons. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" MARBLESTAIRCASE - MOMENTS LATER - NIGHT "> As they follow Percy up the
    stairs, Ron still looks glum. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> How could a troll get in? </sp>

   <sp who="#RON "> Not on its own. Trolls are really stupid. Probably Peeves' playing jokes...
     <stage>(seeing Harry's face)</stage> What? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Hermione. She doesn't know. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="GIRL'S BATHROOM CORRIOOR - MOMENTS LATER - NIGHT"> Harry and Ron slip
    away from the Gryffindors, in with the Hufflepuffs, then down a deserted hallway. As FOOTSTEPS
    ring out, they duck behind a STONE GRIFFIN, see Snape hurry past. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> That's the third floor he's going to. Teachers were supposed to go to the
    dungeons... <stage>(wrinkling his nose) </stage> What's that? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Smells like Fred's socks. Only... worse. <stage> Much worse. Lumbering toward
     them is a TROLL with an ENORMOUS CLUB. As it comes into a PATCH OF MOONLIGHT, it blinks
     stupidly, peers into a doorway, then slouches slowly inside. Harry studies a SUIT OF ARMOR
     beside the door, thinks... </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Follow me.<stage> Harry edges forward, pulls the SWORD from the suit of armor,
     and runs it through the door handle, trapping the troll. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Yes! <stage> Harry grins, then HEARS a high, petrified SCREAM. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> This wouldn't be the girl's bathroom, would it?<stage> CUT TO: </stage></sp>
   <stage>CLOSE UP -- HERMIONE SCREAMING </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="GIRL'S BATHROOM - NIGHT"> A HUGE SHADOW falls over Hermione's face.
    HERMIONE'S POV .... as the troll advances directly toward her. She dashes into a stall, bolts
    the door. Trembling, she peers upward... watching as... the troll's face appears over the top,
    looking in. Panicked, she drops to the floor and shimmies into the next stall, out of sight~
    Angered, the .troll rai~es its club and- SMASH!--shatters the stall Hermione just vacated. As
    wood rains down in jagged, splintered pieces... Harry and Ron rush in, staring in horror as the
    troll raises the club high and SHATTERS the next stall. Hermione, still crawling, covers her
    head and peers back. SMASH! The club comes thundering down yet again, this time just inches from
    her foot. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Don't worry, Hermione! We're here! <stage>(turning to Harry) </stage> She's
    dead. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I heard that! </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> What do we do? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY">
    <stage>(looking about frantically)</stage> Confuse it! </sp>
   <sp who="#RON  "> Confuse it? <stage>(shrugging)</stage> Hey, pea brain! <stage>Harry and Ron
     grab anything they can and begin to hurl it at the troll, but they might as well be throwing
     marshmallows. As shards of wood bounce off its pint-sized head and great lumpy shoulders, the
     troll brings the club down once more and SHATTERS the last stall. As Harry and Ron look on
     grimly, the troll jabs its club into the hash of wood before it, poking about for Hermione,
     when, at the last second... ... she scrambles out and dashes under the sink. GRUNTING
     furiously, the troll turns, begins-to advance on her. Harry, thinking fast, rushes forward and
     leaps upon the troll's rising club... rising himself... right out of FRAME... and then...
     dropping... ... right onto the troll's slimy neck. The troll blinks dimly and, before it can
     react, Harry--purely on instinct--shoves his wand straight up the troll's nose. The troll ROARS
     in pain, dropping the club and stamping about. Ron watches helplessly, then glances at the club
     on the floor, an idea flickering across his face. Raising his wand, he SPEAKS: </stage>
    Wingardium Leviosa. <stage>Harry swings around, sees Ron standing, wand poised. It does not
     inspire confidence. Ron looks at Hermione, takes a breath, and this time, employs the correct
     pronunciation. </stage> Wingardium LEVI-OHHHH-SA! <stage> With that, the club quivers upon the
     floor... begins to rise. The troll, still raging, grabs Harry's leg and peels him off his body.
     As he holds Harry up high, suspended by one leg, Harry's world goes upside down, spinning,
     when... ... the club floats by his face. The troll pauses, watching in confusion as the club
     rises toward the ceiling, hanging in magical suspension until ... ... THUNK! It drops smack on
     the troll's head. Wobbling, the troll releases its grip on Harry's leg and... ... drops him
     hard to the floor. Harry peers up. The troll wobbles one last time and starts to fall...
     directly on top of Harry. Quickly, Harry rolls away... ... just before the troll SLAMS to the
     floor, inches away. All is quiet for a moment. Then Hermione steps forward. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Is it--dead? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I don't think so. Just knocked out. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON"> No need to kill it, after all. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Yes, well, that was big of you. Ugh. Troll snot. <stage> Harry extracts his
     wand, wipes it on the troll's trousers. A sudden VOLLEY of FOOTSTEPS announces the arrival of
     Professors McGonagall, Snape, and a still queasy Quirrell. Harry notices a SPOT OF BLOOD on
     Snape's leg, sees Snape shift his cloak to cover it. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#PROFESSOR MCGONAGAL"> Explain yourselves! Both of you. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> It's my fault, Professor McGonagall. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Miss Granger! </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I went looking for the troll. I've read about them and thought I could
    handle it. But I was wrong. If Harry and Ron hadn't come along ... I'd be dead. <stage> Ron
     drops his wand, stunned by Hermione's lie. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> I'm very disappointed in you, Miss Granger. Five points will be taken
    from Gryffindor for your very serious lack of judgement. As for you gentlemen, I hope you
    realize just how lucky you are. Not many First Years could take on a full grown mountain troll
    and live to tell the tale. I award each of you five points... for sheer dumb luck. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" SEVENTH FLOOR CORRIDOR - MOMENTS LATER - NIGHT "> Hermione walks
    silently beside Harry and Ron. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Good of her to get us out of trouble like that. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Mind you, we did save her from a full grown mountain troll. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Mind you, she might not have needed saving if we hadn't locked the thing in
    with her. <stage> Ron glances at Hermione, then away. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> What are friends for? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - DAY "> Harry, Ron and Hermione sit together. Harry ignores
    his breakfast. Ron, as usual, is stuffing his face. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Take a bit of toast, mate. Go on. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Ron's right, Harry. You're going to need your strength today. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I'm not hungry. </sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE ">
    <stage>(appearing) </stage> Good luck today, Potter. Then again, now that you've proven yourself
    against a troll, a little game of Quidditch should be easy work for you. Even if it is against
    my boys. <stage> Snape smiles, LIMPS away toward the Slytherin table. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> That was ... disturbing. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I tell you what's disturbing. Snape smiling. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> That explains the blood. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Blood? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Last night, Ron and I saw Snape heading for the third floor. I'm guessing he
    let the troll in as a diversion, tried to get past the three-headed dog, and got himself bit.
    That's why he's limping._ </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> But why would anyone go near that dog? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Listen. The day I was at Gringotts, Hagrid took something out of one of the
    vaults. Said it was Hogwarts business. Very secret. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"> So you're saying... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> That's what the dog's guarding. That's what Snape wants. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> But what's safer than Gringotts? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> One place, according to Hagrid. Hogwarts. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Well, whatever it is, it must be really valuable. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Or really dangerous. <stage> Just then, an OWL beats into the room.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Bit early for mail, isn't it? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> That's Hedwig. <stage>All watch as she swoops down with a LONG, THIN PACKAGE.
     Harry slips Hedwig a piece of his uneaten toast, strips open the parcel and finds, inside, a
     sleek mahogany BROOMSTICK. </stage> It's a broomstick. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON  "> That's not a broomstick, Harry. That's a Nimbus Two Thousand. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But who...?<stage> Harry glances up, sees--far across the room--Professor
     McGonagall looking his way. Quickly, she turns away. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" QUIDDITCH FIELD - DAY "> The stadium is full. Ron and Hermione join
    Neville and Seamus in the Gryffindor section, unfurl a banner that reads POTTER FOR PRESIDENT.
    As the Slytherin and Gryffindor teams take the field, the CROWD ROARS. Oliver Wood runs up
    alongside a nervous Harry, who clutches his new Nimbus 2000. </stage>
   <sp who="#WOOD "> I know what you'ree thinking, Harry. I'm playing my first game of Quidditch,
    the entire school's watching me and, worst of all, it's against Slytherin. Am I right? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Pretty close. </sp>
   <sp who="#WOOD "> It' s all right. I felt the same way before my first game. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What happened? </sp>
   <sp who="#WOOD "> I don't really remember. I took a Bludger to the head about two minutes in and
    woke up in the hospital week later. <stage> Madame Hooch, clad in REFEREE ROBES, addresses the
     players. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MADAMEHOOCH "> Now, I want a nice clean game. From all of you. <stage> She glances
     tellingly at Slytherin Captain MARCUS FLINT. Harry leans over to ANGELINA JOHNSON, Gryffindor
     Chaser. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Who's he, Angelina? </sp>
   <sp who="#ANGELINA "> Marcus Flint. Slytherin Captain. They say he's got troll blood in him.
     <stage> Harry swallows as Flint glares at him murderously. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MADAME HOOCH "> Mount your brooms, please. <stage> Hands trembling, Harry waits,
     then... the WHISTLE BLASTS. FOURTEEN BROOMSTICKS rise into the air. As the crowd ROARS, Madam
     Hooch kicks the crate, releasing two SCREAMING Bludgers, then tosses up the Quaffle. In the
     stands, LEE JORDAN does COMMENTARY. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#LEE JORDAN "> Quaffle's up... and straight off taken by Angelina Johnson of Gryffindor.
    What an excellent Chaser that girl is, and rather attractive too, I might add... <stage>
     Professor McGonagall casts a disapproving glance at Jordan, then turns to watch the action
     below. Cradling the Quaffle, Angelina Johnson WEAVES wickedly past a Slytherin Chaser, DUCKS
     UNDER a sizzling Bludger that Fred Weasley CHIPS AWAY, then DISHES OFF to a speeding Alicia
     Spinnet. Alicia FALLS into a FIFTEEN FOOT ROLLING DIVE, feeds the Quaffle back to Angelina...
     but has it INTERCEPTED by a slashing Marcus Flint. Flint FLIES FAST for the hoop, rears back...
     but has his shot BLOCKED by Oliver Wood. Wood bumps the Quaffle to Chaser Katie Bell, who
     ROCKETS past Flint the length of the field... only to take a Bludger to the back of the head.
     As the Quaffle pops loose, Marcus Flint grabs it, drives with astonishing speed-back the other
     way, then takes a Bludger himself, courtesy of George Weasley. Angelina Johnson swoops down,
     snatches the spinning Quaffle and, flying like lightning, races the field to score. As
     Gryffindor CHEERS fill the cold air, Hagrid makes his way up the stands, scattering students in
     his wake. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Budge up there. Clear the way.How's Harry holdin' up? <stage> Ron and
     Hermione squeeze together, giving Hagrid space. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> He hasn't had much to do yet. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> First game. He stays outta trouble, that'll be doin' enough. <stage> Above the
     pitch, Slytherin's ADRIAN PUCEY eludes two Bludgers, two Weasleys and the Chaser, ZOOMING
     toward the goals... when suddenly a FLASH OF GOLD zips by his left ear. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> The Snitch!</sp> 
   <stage>Far below, Slytherin Seeker TERENCE HIGGS makes his move. Harry
    DIVES. Faster than Higgs, he closes the gap quickly, eyes locked on the tiny golden ball. He
    adds some speed, reaches out, and--WHAM!--Marcus Flint HITS HIM full on, sending him reeling.
    Harry PULLS UP his tip, LEVELS-OFF,and glances about. But the Snitch is GONE.</stage> 
   <sp who="#RON #HERMIONE #HAGRID"> FOUL! FOUL! FOUL! <stage> As a Bludger screamspast Harry, he
      tries to kick his broom higher. Instead, it LURCHES, nearly tossing him off. Below, Hagrid
      peers through his BINOCULARS, frowns. </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID "> Dunno what Harry thinks he's doin'. If I didn't know better, I'd say he's
     lost control of his broom... </sp>
    <sp who="#RON "> Maybe something happened to it when Flint blocked him. <stage> In the stands,
      people gasp as the broom ROLLS OVER and leaves Harry DANGLING from one end. Neville buries his
      face. </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID "> No. Can't nothin' interfere with a broomstick except powerful Dark magic. No
     kid could do that to a Nimbus 2000. <stage> Hearing this, Hermione GRABS Hagrid's binoculars.
     </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE ">
     <stage>(whispering to Ron) </stage> It's Snape. He's jinxing the broom. <stage> Ron takes the
      binoculars, looks. Snape sits MUTTERING in the opposite stands, staring into the sky. Staring
      at Harry. </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#RON "> Jinxing the broom? What do we do? </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Leave it to me. As Hermione dashes off, Ron turns the binoculars back to
     the sky. Harry hangs from the broom with two hands while Fred hovers nearby. George circles
     about ten feet below. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY "> What's George doing? </sp>
    <sp who="#FRED "> Just in case you fall, George will... <stage>(not sure of this himself)
     </stage> ... catch you. </sp>
    <sp who="#HARRY "> I knew I should have gone out for football. </sp>
    <sp who="#GEORGE "> What's football? <stage> Hermione fights her way through theSlytherin
      faithful, who cackle at Harry's plight, toward Snape. </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#DRACO "> Take a good look, lads. With any luck we'll be having Potter soup for supper.
      <stage> Just then, Hermione brushes past, sending Malfoy ass over tea kettle into Professor
      Quirrell in the row below. Reaching Snape, Hermione crouches down and whips out her wand.
      Across the field Ron peers through the binoculars ... </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#RON "> Come on, Hermione...<stage> Just then, BLUE FLAMES spit from Hermione's wand,
      climbing quickly up Snape's robes. Snape continues to mutter, staring skyward, then realizes
      he's on fire, and looks away. In the commotion, that ensues, Ron sees Hermione scoop the blue
      fire into a little jar, slip it into robe, and make her escape. Instantly, Harry's broom stops
      jerking. He clambers back on, when--SWOOSH!--A FLASH OF GOLD streaks by him: the Snitch. Higgs
      ZOOMS UP from below and he and Harry give chase. The Snitch SWERVES, then... DIVES. As it
      PLUMMETS, Harry and Higgs plummet too, giving it all they've got. On the pitch below, Hermione
      puts her hand to her mouth. In the stands, Neville buries his head again. As the Snitch drops,
      the ground rushes crazily upward, the speed breathtaking. Harry seems intoxicated by it,
      slightly crazed, eyes riveted to the fluttering Snitch, seeing it and only it. Higgs, on the
      other hand, sees only the ground and, at the last minute, can bear it no longer, PULLING UP on
      his broom-and SWERVING to safety. As Harry and earth collide, the Nimbus cartwheels away,
      Harry rolls off and, coming up on all fours, claps his hand to his mouth. As if he were sick.
     </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> Well, that's unfortunate. Understandable, but unfortunate. <stage> As
      Harry COUGHS, Hagrid takes back his binoculars, which,unfortunately for Ron, are still-around
      Ron's neck. </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#HAGRID "> Unfortunate nothin'. He's got the Snitch! <stage> Harry SHOOTS his hand in
      the air. The crowd ROARS. Marcus Flint touches down, fuming. </stage></sp>
    <sp who="#FLINT "> He didn't catch it. He swallowed it!. </sp>
    <sp who="#HERMIONE ">
     <stage>(popping in) </stage> Nothing in the Quidditch rulebook discriminates against catching
     the Snitch in your mouth. Or any other place for that matter. In fact, in a game played in
     Greece in the late seventeenth century- </sp>
    <sp who="#MADAMEHOOCH "> Thank you, Miss Granger. We can dispense with the more unattractive
     historical details of the game. Nevertheless, your point is well taken. Match to Gryffindor!
      <stage>As Harry's teammates lift him to their shoulders, Hermione spies Snape in the far
      stands, limping quickly away, hisrobes still smoking. </stage>
    </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS GROUNDS - LATER DAY "> Harry, Ron, and Hermione walk with
    Hagrid towards his home, a WOODEN HUT on the edge of the Dark Forest. </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Rubbish! Why would Snape put a curse on Harry's broom? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Who knows? Why was he trying to get past that three-headed dog on Halloween? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> How do you know about Fluffy? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Fluffy? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> That thing has a name? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> 'Course he's got a name. He's mine. Bought him off an Irish bloke I met in the
    Pub las' year. Lent him to Dumbledore to guard the... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Yes? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Don' be askin' me anymore. That's top secret, that is. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But Hagrid, whatever Fluffy's guarding, Snape's trying to steal it. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Codswallop! Snape's a Hogwart'steacher. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Hogwarts teacher or not, I know a jinx when I see one, Hagrid. I've read
    all about them. You've got to keep eye contact, and Snape wasn't blinking. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Now listen to me, all three of yeh-- yer meddlin' in things that shouldn't be
    meddled. It's dangerous. What that dog's guardin' is strictly betw'n Professor Dumbledore and
    Nicolas Flamel--<stage> Hagrid stops, furious with himself, then turns for his hut, where FANG,
     an enormous black boarhound, greets him. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Nicolas Flamel. Why does that name sound familiar? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS CASTLE - DAY "> December Snow falls, dusting the castle turrets
    and blanketing the grounds. Hagrid drags a GIANT CHRISTMAS FIR toward the Castle, Fang trotting
    by his side. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - DAY"> Nearly Headless Nick SWOOPS about a TOWERING
    CHRISTMAS TREE, running GARLAND over the limbs, while Peeves plucks ORNAMENTS from the branches,
    hurling them to the floor. </stage>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Listen up! As the lake is frozen, all students going home for holiday
    will take a flying sleigh to the departure platform. Earmuffs are strongly recommended. <stage>
     Harry and Ron pay no attention to the students bustling about them, sitting alone by the window
     playing WIZARD CHESS. Unlike Muggle chess, these figures are alive. Presently, Harry's BISHOP
     looks cross. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#BISHOP "> Don't send me there! Can't you see his Knight? Send him. We can afford to
    lose him. <stage> The bishop points to a PAWN. Harry sheepishly complies. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Queen to pawn six. <stage> Ron YAWNS as his queen steps forward and--with
     extreme prejudice--disposes of the pawn. Hermione, huge trunk in tow, arrives just in time to
     witness the carnage. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Oh my god! That' s barbaric ! </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> That's chess. I see you're packed. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I see you're not. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON  "> Change of plans. My parents decided to go to Romania to visit my brother
    Charlie. He's studying dragons there. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"> You can help Harry then. He promised to keep looking in the library for
    Nicolas Flamel over holiday. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> We have looked. A hundred times. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE ">
    <stage>(as she exits)</stage> Not in the Restricted Section. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" BOYS TOWER DORMITORY - MORNING"> CAMERA PANS a stack of PACKAGES at
    Harry's bed. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON  "> Happy Christmas, Harry! <stage> Harry rubs his eyes, sees Ron wearing a MAROON
     SWEATER over his pajamas. Ron tosses him a present. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I've got presents. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON  "> What'd you expect? In your hand's from Hagrid. And by the looks of that lumpy
    one, Mum's sent you a Weasley sweater. <stage> Harry opens Hagrid's, finds a WOODEN FLUTE. As he
     blows it, Hedwig cocks her head. It sounds like an owl. Harry takes up the next parcel. It' s
     very light. He reads the NOTE attached. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Your father left this in my possession before he died. It is time it was
    returned to you. <stage>Harry tears the paper away, finds something SHINY and translucent
     slithers to the floor. </stage> It's some kind of... cloak. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Well let's see then. Put it on. <stage>As Harry takes the cloth, we hang on Ron,
     watching, then: </stage> Ahhh! <stage>Harry's head is floating in midair. Ron looks on in
     awe.</stage> Harry, do you know what this is? It's an invisibility cloak. They're really rare.
    Who gave you this? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> ...There's no name ... It just says, 'Use it well.' </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LIBRARY - NIGHT "> Pitch black. A match STRIKES, floats by itself, in
    midair. It drifts forward, LIGHTS a LAMP. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LIBRARY - ROW OF BOOKS - MOMENTS LATER - NIGHT"> The lamp floats eerily
    among the books, then rises, illuminates a SIGN: RESTRICTED. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" RESTRICTED ROOM - LIBRARY - NIGHT "> The lamp FLOATS into the room, the
    invisibility cloak drops. and, bit by bit, HARRY appears. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Flamel. Nicolas Flamel...<stage> Harry runs his finger along the spines,
     stops. Takes a LARGE BOOK from the shelf. Runs his hand over the course leather, then... opens
     it. At once it begins to SHRIEK! Harry SLAMS it shut, but it goes on WAILING. Stumbling back,
     Harry tips the lamp and all GOES dark. FOOTSTEPS ring out. Frantically, Harry sifts the
     darkness for the cloak, panicking, when his hands... DISAPPEAR. Pitching the cloak over
     himself, he dashes to the door, just as it CLANGS open--revealing Filch. As Filch's pale, wide
     eyes stare straight ahead, Harry glides right past him... </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LIBRARY CORRIDOR - NIGHT "> ...then dashes into the corridor, the book's
    SHRIEKS echoing behind him, coming face to face with Snape and Quirrel, in the midst of a heated
    conversation. </stage>
   <sp who="#SNAPE  "> Have you found out how to get past that beast of Hagrid's, yet? </sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL "> B-b-but Severus, I- </sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE "> You don't want me as your enemy, Quirrel. </sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL"> I don't know what you- </sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE "> You know perfectly well what I mean. Your little bit of hocus pocus...
     <stage>Harry walks slowly, carefully around them, trying not to be heard. Snape stops, as if
     he's felt a small breeze, then... turns... seeing soft FEATHERS OF VAPOUR. Snape reaches out to
     touch them... Inside the cloak, Harry puts his hand to his mouth, to stop his breath... Snape
     finds nothing in front of him. He turns back to Quirrel. </stage> We'll have another little
    chat soon, when you've had time to think things over and decide where your loyalties lie.
     <stage> The door behind them slowly opens and closes... quietly... carefully. Filch appears,
     from around the corridor, walks up to Snape and Quirrel. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#FILCH "> Professors... I found this. In the Restricted Section. It's still hot. </sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE "> Then they can't be far. <stage> Snape, Quirrel and Filch exit. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" EMPTY CLASSROOM - NIGHT"> Harry drops the cloak, exhales, and absently
    rubs his scar, wincing mildly. As his eyes adjust, he sees a MAGNIFICENT MIRROR, as high as the
    ceiling, across the room. On the frame is an INSCRIPTION: Erised stra ehru oyt ube cafru oyt on
    wohsi. He steps in front. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Ah! <stage>Harry turns--as if expecting to see someone--but finds only the
     dark shapes of desks and chairs. Slowly, he turns back. In the mirror, Harry sees his own
     startled reflection and... beyond... a MAN and a WOMAN. </stage> Mum? Dad? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" BOYS TOWER DORMITORY - MOMENTS LATER - NIGHT"> CLOSE UP: A SLEEPING RON </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Ron! Ron! Wake up! <stage>Ron squints in confusion, then Harry lowers the
     cloak. </stage> There's something you've got to see! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" EMPTY CLASSROOM - A FEW MINUTES LATER - NIGHT "> Harry drags Ron to the
    mirror. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Come look! It's my family. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON ">
    <stage>(yawning)</stage> That's you, Harry. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Look in properly, go on, stand here. <stage>Harry steps aside. Ron takes his
     place and... freezes. </stage> There. You see them, don't you? That's- </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Me. Only I'm... Head Boy! And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup and... bloody
    hell... I'm Quidditch Captain too! Harry, do you think this mirror shows the future? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(troubled)</stage> How can it? All my family are dead. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - THE NEXT MORNING - DAY "> The Hall looks deserted as the
    students who remain eat breakfast. The Weasleys chatter amongst themselves, laughing, then Ron
    looks away, sees Harry staring into the distance. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Want to play chess? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> No. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Want to go visit Hagrid? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> No. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Harry, I know what you're thinking. But don't. There's something not right about
    that mirror. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" EMPTY CLASSROOM - NIGHT  "> Harry sits before the mirror, transfixed.</stage>
     <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE">
     <stage>(O.S.)</stage> Back again, Harry? <stage>Harry turns. Dumbledore slips off a desk, sits
      beside him. </stage> I see that you--like so many before you--have discovered the delights of
     the Mirror of Erised. I expect by now you realize what it does. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> It shows me my family. </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> And it showed your friend Ron himself as Head Boy. <stage>Harry looks
     surprised. Dumbledore smiles. </stage> I don't need a cloak to become invisible. <stage>(re:
     the mirror)</stage> I'll give you a clue, Harry. The happiest man on earth would look into the
    Mirror of Erised and see only himself, exactly. as he is. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> So, then, it shows us what we want... Whatever we want... </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Yes and no. It shows us nothing more or less than the deepest, most
    desperate desire of our hearts. You, who have never known your family, see them gathered around
    you. Ronald Weasley, who has always been overshadowed by his family, sees himself standing
    alone. Remember this, though, Harry. This mirror gives us neither knowledge or truth. Men have
    wasted away before it. Even gone mad. <stage>(rising) </stage> That's why it will be moved to a
    new home tomorrow. I ask that you do not go looking for it again, Harry. It does not do to dwell
    on dreams and forget to live. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Can I ask you something, Professor? What do you see when you look in the
    Mirror? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> I? I see myself holding a pair of thick, woolen socks. One can never have
    enough socks, Harry. You'll do well to remember that as well. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" SCHOOL COURTYARD - DAY "> Bundled against the chill, Harry--burdened by
    heavy thoughts-- enters the empty courtyard~ Hedwig on his arm. As he releases her, she sails
    high over the castle walls... wending her way through the turrets and then out over the wintry
    grounds, her reflection glimmering on the surface of the icy lake below. As she turns, beating
    her way back, the dark sky lightens, turning a slow, glorious blue and the once-dark trees
    shimmer in the crisp Spring light. Hogwarts itself shimmers as well, no longer dusted with snow.
    Hedwig glides over the castle walls, swoops, and comes to a fluttering rest outside one of the
    high windows of the Great Hall. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - DAY "> Hermione--book in hand--quizzes Ron, who seems more
    interested in the pack of Chocolate Frogs in his hand. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I'll ask you again. What are the three most crucial ingredients in a
    Forgetfulness Potion? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> And I'll tell you again. I forgot. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> And what, may I ask, do you plan to do should you get that question on
    final exams? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Crib off you. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> You will not. Besides, according to Professor McGonagall, we're to be given
    special quills bewitched with an anti-cheating spell. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> That's insulting. It's as if they don't trust us. <stage>(frowning) </stage>
    Dumbledore again. <stage> As Ron tosses the wizard card onto the table, HARRY WATCHES IT SPIN...
     just as ... a smattering of LAUGHTER erupts across the hall. Neville is HOPPING like a bunny,
     legs STUCK TOGETHER, while Seamus trails after. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON #HERMIONE"> Leg-Locker Curse. <stage>(and then to each other) </stage> Malfoy.
     <stage> Neville, breathing hard, reaches the Gryffindor table, then, before anyone can catch
     him, topples to the floor. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> You've got to start standing up to him, Neville. </sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE "> How? I can't stand up at all. </sp>
   <sp who="#SEAMUS "> I offered to do the countercurse, but he wouldn't let me. </sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Of course not. That's all I need, you to set my bloody kneecaps on fire. </sp>
   <sp who="#SEAMUS "> I don't appreciate the insinuation, Longbottom. Besides, if anyone cares to
    notice, my eyebrows have completely grown back. <stage> As Seamus turns away, the others see a
     curious BALD SPOT on the back of his head. Ron takes out his wand. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON"> All right then, Neville, who shall it be? Me, Hermione, or... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I've found him. <stage> Ron stops, sees Harry holding up Dumbledore's wizard
     card. Ron takes it. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> He's bowling. So what? He's always bowling. <stage>Harry rolls his eyes, turns
     the card over for Ron to READ. </stage> Dumbledore is particularly famous for his defeat of the
    dark wizard Grindelwald, for the discovery ofthe twelve uses of dragon's blood... and his work
    on alchemy... with his partner, Nicolas Flamel. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> I knew the name sounded familiar. I read it on the train that day.<stage>
     Hermione steps right over Neville. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Follow me. </sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE "> Hey! Wait! What about that counter-curse! Neville's eyes shift. Seamus
    smiles, raises an eyebrow. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LIBRARY - MOMENTS LATER - DAY"> CLOSE UP: A BOOK ON ALCHEMY as it hits
    the table with a LOUD THUD. Hermione flips through the pages as Harry and Ron look over her
    shoulder. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> How could I be so stupid! I checked this out weeks ago for a bit of light
    reading. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> This is light? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Of course! Here it is! <stage>(whispers dramatically)</stage> Nicolas
    Flamel is the only known maker of the Sorcerer's Stone! <stage> Harry and Ron glance at each
     other, then Hermione. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> The what? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Oh, honestly, don't you two read? <stage>(reading) </stage> The sorcerer's
    Stone is a legendary substance with astonishing powers. It will transform any metal in to pure
    gold, and produces the Elixir of Life, which will make the drinker immortal. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Immortal. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> It means you'll never die. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I know what it means-- </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> The only stone currently in existence belongs to Mr. Nicolas Flamel, the
    noted alchemist, who last year celebrated his six hundred and sixty-fifth birthday.
     <stage>(looking up)</stage> That's what Fluffy's guarding on the Third Floor. That's what's
    under the trapdoor. The Sorcerer's Stone! </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> So Flamel knows someone's after the Stone... gives it to Dumbledore to keep
    safe at Hogwarts ... not realizing that the one who's after it .. . </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Teaches at Hogwarts. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> So Snape wants piles of gold and to live forever. Who wouldn't? <stage> Hermione
     closes the book, troubled by something. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What is it, Hermione? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I don't want to scare you, Harry. It's just ... if all Snape wants is the
    Sorcerer's Stone ... why did he try to kill you that day on the Quidditch pitch? <stage> Harry
     ponders this, but doesn't have an answer. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where="HAGRID'S HUT - LATER - NIGHT"> Harry, trailed by Ron and Hermione, KNOCKS
    on Hagrid's door. The door rattles, opens a crack, and Hagrid peers out. </stage>

   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Oh. Hullo. Er... not ter be rude, but I'm not really fit ter entertain right
    about- </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> We know about the Sorcerer's Stone. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="HAGRID'S HUT - NIGHT"> Everything here is oversized. Hagrid adds wood to
    an already roaring fire, putters about a large, simmering kettle. </stage>

   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Snape! Blimey, yer not still on abou' him, are yeh? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Hagrid, we know he's after the Stone. We just don't know... why. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Harry, Snape was one o' the teachers in on protectin' the Stone. He's not
    abou' ter steal it. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Yeh heard me: Snape was one o' the teachers in on protectin' the Stone. Now,
    as I said, I'm a bit preoccupied at moment-- </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Wait a minute. One of the teachers? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Of course! There are other things defending the Stone, aren't there?
    Spells, enchantments... </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Tha' right. Bloody waste o' time if yeh ask me. T'ain't no one goin' ter get
    past Fluffy. Not a soul knows how 'cept me an' Dumbledore--<stage> CRACK! A CLICKING SOUND is
     heard coming from the kettle, then a curious SCRAPING. Harry looks. Sees a HUGE BLACK EGG.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Hagrid... exactly what is that? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Ah. Well. That's ... er ... </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I know what that is! But Hagrid. How did you ever get one? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Won it. Off a stranger in the village. Think he was glad ter be rid of it,
    ter be honest. Blimey...<stage> The scraping is furious now.Quickly, Hagrid takes the egg from
     the kettle, sets it on a table. Fissures spread like veins over its surface, then it...
     EXPLODES... SHELL FLYING LIKE SHRAPNEL. Harry, Ron and Hermione cover themselves. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE. "> Is that... a dragon? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> That's not just a dragon! That's a Norwegian Ridgeback! My brother Charlie works
    with these in Romania </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Isn't he' beautiful! Bless 'im, look, he knows 'is Mummy! <stage>(tickling
     the dragon's tummy)</stage> Hullo, Norbert. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Norbert? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Well, he's got ter have a name. <stage>The dragon blinks at Hagrid, screws up
     its face and... SNEEZES, spewing forth a shower of SPARKS, which sends Fang whimpering and
     kindles a brief blaze in Hagrid's beard. </stage> Needs ter be trained up a bit, o' course.
     <stage>(stopping cold) </stage> Hey, you there! <stage>All turn. Peering through the window is
     a FACE. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Malfoy! <stage> They leap to the door--see a fleet figure racing across the
     grounds, disappearing in the night. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS GROUNDS - MOMENTS LATER - NIGHT  "> Harry, Ron and Hermione
    walk toward the glittering castle. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Hagrid always wanted a dragon. Told me so the first time I ever met him. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> But it's crazy. And worse, Malfoy knows. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I don't Understand. Is that bad?</sp> 
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL">
     <stage>(O.S.) </stage> Mr. Potter. Mr. Weasley. Miss Granger. <stage>Up ahead stands Professor
      McGonagall, a jagged silhouette in castle-light. Beside her, Draco Malfoy grins arrogantly.
     </stage>
    </sp>
    <sp who="#RON "> It's bad. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="PROFESSOR MCGONAGALL's CLASSROOM - MOMENTS LATER"> Harry, Ron and
    Hermione stand before a displeased McGonagall, while Malfoy looks on, practically quivering with
    pleasure. </stage>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> As every schoolchild knows, dragon- breeding is against our laws, has
    been ever since the Warlock's Convention of 1709. And for good reason. It's hard to keep the
    Muggles from noticing us if we've got a thirty-foot Ukranian Ironbelly running around the back
    garden. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Norwegian Ridgeback. <stage>Professor Mcgonagall's eyes shift, narrow on
     Ron.</stage> I just meant... in this case... sorry. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Personally, I don't care if Hagrid has a Chinese Fireball sitting in his
    kitchen, Mr. Weasley. He answers to Dumbledore. You, on the other hand, answer to me. Nothing--I
    repeat, nothing--gives a student the right to walk about the school at night. Therefore, as
    punishment for your actions, fifty points will be taken. <stage> As the others gasp, Malfoy's
     eyes glimmer with cruel ecstasy. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Fifty? </sp>
   <sp who="#PROFESSOR MCGONAGALL  "> Each. And to insure it doesn't happen again, all four of you
    will receive detention. </sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO "> Excuse me, Professor. Perhaps I heard you wrong. I thought you said the four
    of us. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Indeed. You see, Mr. Malfoy, noble your intentions, you too were out of
    bed after hours. You will classmates in detention. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - MORNING "> As Harry, Ron and Hermione eat breakfast, the
    HOURGLASSES tell the tale: Gryffindor has slipped to last place. Just then, Fred and George pass
    by. </stage>
   <sp who="#FRED "> Don't worry, you three. This'll all blow over. </sp>
   <sp who="#GEORGE "> It may take a year or two, but eventually people will start talking to you
    again. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE ">
    <stage>(sniffing defensively) </stage> Well, I for one, see nothing wrong with a reduced social
    life. It'll give us more time to revise for finals. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Why bother? Even with Malfoy losing points, Slytherin's a lock for the House
    Cup. And look. Malfoy knows it. <stage> All three peer at Malfoy. He raises a goblet in their
     direction, cackles with Crabbe and Goyle. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> He won't be smiling tonight. <stage>(off Harry and Ron's looks) </stage>
    Haven't you heard? For detention they're taking us into the Dark Forest. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where="HOGWARTS GROUNDS - NIGHT"> Beneath a pale moon, Filch, carrying a
    lantern, leads Harry, Ron, Hermione and Malfoy across the dark grounds. </stage>

   <sp who="#FILCH "> A pity they let the old punishments die. Was a time, detention would find you
    all hanging by your thumbs in the dungeons... </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where="HAGRID'S HUT - MOMENTS LATER"> As Filch and the others reach the yard,
    they find Hagrid stringing a crossbow, Fang at his side. </stage>
   <sp who="#FILCH "> A sorry lot this, Hagrid. I pity you. <stage>Filch squints, sees tears running
     down Hagrid's face. </stage> Good god, man, you're not still on about that bloody dragon, are
    you? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID ">
    <stage>(to Harry, Ron, Hermione)</stage> Norbert's gone. Dumbledore's sent him off ter Romania
    ter live in a colony. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Well, that's good, isn't it? He'll be with his own kind. Better all around,
    don't you think? Especially for Fang. <stage> Hearing his name, a singed Fang beats his BANDAGED
     tail. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> But what if Norbert doesn't like Romania. What if the other dragons are mean
    to him? He's only a baby, after all. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> A baby that breaths fire. <stage> Harry elbows Ron, silencing, him.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#FILCH "> For god's sake, pull yourself together, man. You're going into the Forest,
    after all. Got to have your wits about you. </sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO "> The Forest? But I thought that was just a joke. We can't go in the Forest.
    Students aren't allowed. And there's... werewolves. </sp>
   <sp who="#FILCH ">
    <stage>(turning away) </stage> Oh, there's more'n werewolves in those trees, lad. You can be
    sure o' that. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" DARK FOREST - LATER"> Harry and the others trail Hagrid down a skinny
    path through the dark trees. Hagrid turns to Harry, speaks low. </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Sorry abou' this, Harry. Know it's me that deserves punishin', not you. By all
    rights I should be sittin' in a cell in Azkaban tonight. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> It's all right Hagrid. Besides, it's not your fault we were out after hours. If
    we hadn't come knocking on your door in the middle of the night-- <stage>Abruptly Hagrid kneels,
     takes something onto his fingers. (a bit warily) </stage> What's that? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> The reason we're here. <stage>(rising) </stage> All righ' now, lis'en up. See
    this here? <stage>Hagrid holds up his fingers. They're marked with SILVER. </stage> It's unicorn
    blood. I found one dead a few weeks back and two before that first term. This one here's been
    hurt bad by summat. It's our job to find the poor thing. Only one way ter get that done and
    that's ter split inter two parties. Ron, Hermione--yeh'll come with me. Harry, yeh'll go with
    Malfoy. </sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO "> I want Fang then. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Fine. But jus' so yeh know. He's a bloody coward. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" PATH - DARK FOREST"> Fang trots down the path ahead of Harry, while a
    nervous Malfoy trails behind. </stage>
   <sp who="#DRACO"> Wait until my father hears about this. This is servant stuff. We should be
    writing lines or... something. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> If I didn't know better, Draco, I'd say you were scared. </sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO "> You're too stupid to be scared, Potter, growing up with Muggles. If you were
    from a real wizard family, you wouldn't be laughing. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I'm not, believe me...<stage> As Malfoy joins Harry, he stops dead. The trees
     ahead are striped violently with DRIPPING SILVER, and beyond--lying in a small clearing--is the
     broken body of a UNICORN. Fang backs off, something primal in his eyes. Harry watches. him,
     reading his fear, then... the SLITHERING SOUND returns. Seconds later, a HOODED FIGURE slithers
     over the leaves, drops its head over the leering WOUND on the unicorn's side... and begins to
     DRINK ITS BLOOD </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DRACO"> AAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!<stage> Malfoy bolts, slipping and sliding as Fang whimpers
     after. Harry WINCES, clutches his scar, then sees that the Hooded Figure is staring directly at
     him, silver dribbling, down its front. Woozy from pain, Harry staggers back, then falls, the
     SLITHERING SOUND DRAWING CLOSER, when... HOOVES pummel the path behind him and some thing leaps
     clear over him, flickering past the moon above. It charges the hooded figure, drives it back
     into the trees... and away. A SHADOW FALLS across Harry's face. It is a CENTAUR with eyes like
     pale saphires. He is FIRENZE. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#FIRENZE"> Harry Potter. You are known to many creatures here. You must leave. The
    forest is not safe at this time. Especially for you. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What was that thing you saved me from? </sp>
   <sp who="#FIRENZE  "> Only one who has nothing to lose would commit such a crime. It is a
    monstrous thing to slay a unicorn. The blood of a unicorn will keep you alive, even if you are
    an inch from death, but at a terrible price. You have slain something so pure that--from the
    moment the blood touches your lips--you will have a half life. A cursed life. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But who would choose such a life? </sp>
   <sp who="#FIRENZE "> Can you think of no one? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Do you mean to say that thing that killed the unicorn, that was drinking its
    blood, that was Voldemort! </sp>
   <sp who="#FIRENZE"> Do you know what is hidden in the school at this very moment, Harry Potter? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> The Sorcerer's Stone. <stage>AND FOR THE UK AUDIENCE...</stage> The
    Philosopher's Stone.<stage> A commotion is heard as Hagrid and the others come slashing through
     the trees. As Harry reacts, the others break into the clearing. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Harry! </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID"> Oh, it's you, is it, Firenze. I see you've met our Mr. Potter. All right
    there, Harry?<stage> Harry nods... but he looks anything but all right. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GRIFFINDOR COMMON ROOM - LATER"> Harry paces before the fire while Ron
    and Hermione watch. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> You mean... You-Know-Who's out there, right now, in the forest! </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But he's weak. He's living off the unicorns. Don't you see? We had it wrong.
    Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself. He wants the Stone for Voldemort. With the Elixer of
    Life Voldemort will be strong again. He'll... come back. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> But if he comes back, you don't think he'd try to... kill you? Do you? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I think if he'd had the chance, he might have tried to kill me tonight.
     <stage> Ron looks vaguely sick. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> And to think I've been worrying about my Potions final. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> No. We're forgetting one thing. Who's the one wizard Voldemort always
    feared? <stage>(as they turn)</stage> Dumbledore. As long as Dumbledore's around, you're safe,
    Harry. As long as Dumbledore's around...you can't be touched. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGWARTS CASTLE - DAY "> Students flock onto the sunny grounds, finished
    with exams. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I'd always heard Hogwarts' end of year exams were frightful. But I found
    that rather enjoyable. Weren't you stunnei:l not to be asked about Elfric the Eager? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I'm stunned my head didn't explode. Alright there, Harry? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> My scar. Keeps... burning. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> It's happened before... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Not like this... <stage>Harry glances across the grounds at Hagrid, sitting in
     his front garden playing a FLUTE. At his feet, Fang's eyes droop. </stage> No... </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Harry? <stage> Harry starts across the grounds. Hermione and Ron glance at
     one another, rush after. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Don't you think it's a bit odd, that what Hagrid wants more than anything is a
    dragon? And a stranger turns up who just happens to have one? I mean, how many people wander
    around with dragon eggs in their pocket? Why didn't I see it before? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="HAGRID'S HUT - MOMENTS LATER"> Hagrid shrugs, goes on polishing the FLUTE
    in his hand. </stage>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Ne'er saw his face... Kept his hood up. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Didn't that strike you as unusual? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Yeh meet a lot o' unusual types in the village. Ain't 'xactly usual meself. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> This stranger, though. talked... You and he must've... </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> He asked what I did, the sorta creatures I look after. Tol' him after Fluffy
    a dragon would be easy. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> And did he seem interested in Fluffy? </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Well, yeah. How many three-headed dogs do yeh meet, even if yeh're in the
    trade? So I tells 'im, this stranger, the trick with any beast is ter know what calms 'em. Take
    Fluffy, fer example. Jus' play 'im a bit o' music an' he'll go straight off ter sleep-- <stage>
     Hagrid stops, horrified by his slip. </stage> I shouldn'ta tol' yeh that! Forget I said it!
    Hey! Where yeh goin'! Hey! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="MCGONAGALL'S CLASSROOM - DAY"> Harry, Ron and Hermione clang through the
    door, Professor McGonagall looks up. </stage>

   <sp who="#HARRY "> We have to see Professor Dumbledore. Immediately. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> I see. Well, I'm afraid Professor Dumbledore is not here. Only moments
    ago, he received an urgent owl from the Ministry of Magic and flew off to London. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> He's gone? Now? But this is important! This is about... the Sorcerer's
     Stone.<stage> Professor McGonagall nearly drops the book in her hands. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> How do you know-- </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Someone's going to try and steal it. </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Nonsense. I don't know how you three found out about the Stone, but I
    assure you it is well protected. Now, run along. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" CORRIDOR - MOMENTS LATER "> Harry leads the others down the corridor. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> That was no stranger Hagrid met in the village. It was Snape. Which means be
    knows how to get past Fluffy. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> And with Dumbledore gone... </sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE">
    <stage>(O.S.) </stage> Good afternoon. <stage>They freeze. Up ahead, Snape stands, studying
     them. </stage> Now what would three fine Gryffindors such as yourselves be doing inside on such
    a lovely day? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> We were just... </sp>
   <sp who="#SNAPE "> You want to be careful. People will think you're... up to something. <stage>
     Snape eyes Harry, then turns away. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> What do we do now? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Go through the trapdoor. Tonight. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GRYFFINDOR COMMONROOM - NIGHT  "> Empty. Dark. Two doors ease open.
    Hermione slips out the one, Harry and Ron the other. They creep toward the Pink Lady
    when--CROAK!--they freeze. Look. Breath a sigh of relief. HARRY/RON/HERMIONE Trevor. Trevor the
    toad blinks up at them. CROAK! </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Trevor! Shh! Go! You shouldn't be here! </sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE"> Neither should you. <stage>They all jump. Neville rises from an armchair.
    </stage> You're sneaking out again, aren't you? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Now, Neville, listen... </sp>
   <sp who="#NEVILLE "> No! I won't let you. You'll get Gryffindor in trouble again. I'll... I'll
    fight you! You were the ones who told me I had to stand up to people! </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> To people. Not us. <stage> Neville raises his fists. Unfortunately, his teddy
     bear pyjamas somewhat undermine the intended effect. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Neville. I'm really, really sorry about this. <stage>(raising her wand)
    </stage> Petrificus Totalus! <stage> Instantly, Neville's arms and legs snap to his sides. He
     SWAYS... then FALLS FLAT ... only his eyes moving, staring at them in horror. Harry and Ron
     look a little horrified too. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> You're a little scary sometimes, you know that? Brilliant. But scary. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" THIRD FLOOR CORRIDOR - MOMENTS LATER - NIGHT  "> CAMERA DRIFTS... down
    the corridor. Suddenly, up ahead, Peeves rounds the corner, MUMBLING to himself as he JUGGLES a
    trio of APPLES. Suddenly, he stops, eyes narrowing suspiciously. </stage>
   <sp who="#PEEVES  "> Who's there? Know you're there, even if I can't see you. Are you ghoulie or
    ghostie or wee student beastie? <stage>Nothing. Peeves smiles slyly, reaches back, and hurls one
     of the apples. It streaks through the air... then...disappears in mid-flight. Peeves smile
     fades. </stage> Never mind. <stage> He backpedals frantically, turns, and swoops off the way he
     came. Seconds later, Harry drops the cloak, tosses the APPLE in his hand to Ron. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> That was close.<stage> Harry steps to the chamber before them. Inside, the
     thrum of MUSIC can be heard. Slowly, Harry starts to ease open the door...when... CRUNCH!
     Hermione and Harry jump, turn. Ron stands chewing the apple. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON  "> Sorry. I get hungry when I'm nervous. <stage>Harry pushes the door clear...
     finds... a giant quivering nose and yellow fangs dripping with saliva. They GASP, then...
    </stage> Wait a minute. He's... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Snoring.<stage> Harry pushes the door further and the light from the corridor
     falls on a TINY HARP. Playing by itself. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" FORBIDDEN CORRIDOR - NIGHT "> As they enter, Harry takes a FLUTE from
    his pocket. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Suppose we won't be needing this now. Look, its obvious Snape's already got
    past Fluffy. If you two want to go back-- </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Don't be stupid. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> We're coming. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Right then. All together now. <stage>Straining mightily, they put their
     shoulders to the massive paw that lays across the trapdoor. Once done, Harry flings it open.
     Below lies only darkness... a faint whistling wind.</stage> I'll go first. Don't follow until I
    give you a sign. If something... bad happens... get yourselves out-- <stage>(stopping)</stage>
    Does it seem a bit... quiet...to you? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> The harp... what happened to the--<stage> Splat! Something wet and sticky
     hits Ron's shoulder. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Yuck! What's this ruddy stuff-- <stage> Slowly, they look up. A MONSTROUS,
     DROOLING SHADOW darkens their faces. Fluffy. Awake. Hungry. Each head ponders its own
     particular snack, then, with a mighty GROWL, swoops. Instantly, the trio pitches themselves
     into the darkness... </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="SHAFT/DEVIL'S SNARE - SECONDS LATER"> Harry PLUMMETS down a glittering
    shaft, tumbling head over heels, down, down, down, until... FLUMP! He lands in something soft
    and yarnlike, followed quickly by Ron and Hermione. Harry adjusts his glasses, looks up. A tiny
    SQUARE OF LIGHT--the trapdoor--glimmers far above. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> That was...cool. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> We must be miles under the school. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Lucky this plant thing's here, really. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Wo! <stage> A vine snakes out Ron's back collar. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Wo! <stage> Twin creepers encircle Harry's chest. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Stop moving! Both of you! This is Devil 's Snare! You have to relax. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Uh, Hermione, it's a bit difficult to relax... <stage>(as a vine encircles his
     neck)</stage> ...given the circumstances. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I know, Harry. But you must. If you don 't, it'll only kill you faster. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Kill us faster? Oh now I can relax. As they watch, Hermione takes a LONG, SLOW
    BREATH and... is SUCKED beneath the surface... VANISHING. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY #RON"> Hermione! <stage> Panicking, Harry and Ron begin to struggle anew, but the
     vines only wrap more tightly around them. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> What are we going to do now! </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"><stage>(O.S.) </stage> Just relax. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(glancing about)</stage> Hermione? But how... where? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE">
    <stage>(O.S.) </stage> Do what I say! <stage> Harry looks at Ron. He's almost completely
     entwined. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I suggest we do what she says. <stage> Harry takes a DEEP BREATH and closes
     his eyes. Slowly, like witch's fingers... the vines DRAW him beneath the surface. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="STAIRCASE (BENEATH DEVIL'S SNARE)"> Harry drops through the ceiling,
    twisting through the webby undergrowth of Devil's snare and onto the ground next to Hermione.
    From above, Ron can be HEARD screaming for HELP. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> He's not relaxing, is he? <stage> Ron's VOICE BELLOWS again. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Apparently not. <stage> Hermione furrows her brow, thinking ALOUD in a
     sing-song. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"> Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare. Dances in the dark, delights in the damp...
   </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="SHAFT/DEVIL'S SNARE"> Ron, wrapped tight as a mummy by this point, cocks
    his ear in disbelief. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON"> Is she doing a poem? It's not possible she's doing a poem, is it? </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="STAIRCASE (BENEATH DEVIL'S SNARE)"> Hermione ignores him, continuing in
    deep concentration. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> It's deadly fun, but will... sulk in the sun! That's it! Light! Devil's
    Snare. hates the light! <stage> She whips out her wand, points it at the vines hanging from the
     ceiling, and sends forth a BRIGHT BURST of GOLD. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="SHAFT/DEVIL'S SNARE"> As the LIGHT BURNS through, the plant withers. An
    OPENING forms, the vines SNAP free of Ron, and... he DROPS through. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="STAIRCASE (BENEATH DEVIL'S SNARE)"> Ron lands heavily, looks up. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Lucky we didn't panic. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Lucky Hermione pays attention in Herbology. <stage> Just then... they detect a
     SOUND: a RUSTLING, a CLINKING. The three exchange a glance, begin to descend the staircase.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> What is that? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I don't know... sounds like wings. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" CHAMBER OF KEYS  "> Harry, Hermione and Ron enter a brilliantly lit
    chamber where hundreds of JEWEL BRIGHT BIRDS flutter below a high arching ceiling. On the
    opposite side is a HEAVY WOODEN DOOR and, floating in the center of the chamber, a single
    BROOMSTICK. Ron and Hermione begin to cross to the door, gazing in wonder at the strangely
    beautiful creatures overhead. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Curious. I've never seen birds like these... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> They're not birds... <stage>Ron and Hermione turn, see Harry standing by the
     floating broom in the center of the room, looking up. </stage> They're keys. And I'll bet one
    of them fits that door. <stage>Hermione tests the doorknob, nods. </stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Locked. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Alohomora! <stage>Hermione turns, sees Ron waving his wand at the knob. No good.
     It's still locked. He shrugs. </stage> Well, it was worth a try. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE ">
    <stage>(peering up)</stage> So what do we do? There must be a thousand keys up there... </sp>
   <sp who="#RON ">
    <stage>(examining the lock)</stage> We're looking for a big, old-fashioned one--probably silver,
    like the handle. There! That one, see! With the bright blue wings! <stage> Ron points.
     Fluttering within a pocket of brass keys is a larger, SILVER one. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> What's wrong with its wing? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> The feather's pinched. Probably from Snape catching it before us. <stage>
     Hermione nods, sees Harry still staring at the broom. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Harry? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> It's... too simple. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Oh, go on, Harry. If Snape could catch it on that old CleanSweep, you can. It's
    not for nothing you're the youngest Seeker in a Century. <stage>Harry nods uncertainly--still
     troubled--but slowly reaches out nonetheless. As his fingers touch the broomstick... ...the
     KEYS EXPLODE IN A FRENZY, hissing like wasps, swarming in great, glittering clouds. Ron's smile
     droops. </stage> Well,this complicates things a bit. <stage>As Harry kicks into the air, a
     seething cluster of keys falls like HARD RAIN, CHATTERING at his arms and legs, SLICING at his
     skin, SHREDDING his sweater...</stage> He'll be torn to pieces. <stage>Horrified, Ron and
     Hermione watch Harry soar higher, fending off the keys with his free hand, until... HARRY'S POV
     Through a MAD CLATTERING, CLUSTER of KEYS, he spies the larger, silver one, fluttering only
     feet beyond his grasp. Harry hovers, grimacing as the hissing keys drop like DARTS onto his
     extended hand... then SNATCHES the silver key. Instantly, Harry whips downward in a wide,
     dizzying circle, trying to outrun the now furious keys. They shadow his every move, drawing
     closer and closer, HUMMING VICIOUSLY as they begin to CHIP at the TAIL TWIGS of the broom.
     Desperate, Harry throws the broom into a reckless dive and, steering with one hand... ...FLINGS
     the key to Ron. As Ron dashes to the door, Harry soars back up, taking the rging keys with him,
     then circles back and watches Ron JAM the key into the lock. As Hermione and Ron scurry
     through, Harry rockets straight after, the keys gaining once again, CHIPPING at the tail of
     broom like a buzzsaw through balsa wood. As the broom begins to WAFFLE, Harry gives one last
     BURST of SPEED and... SOARS through the open door. Together, Hermione and Ron FLING the door
     SHUT... just before the keys rain down like BULLETS. </stage>
   </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" CHESS ROOM"> ... UTTER DARKNESS. Hermione's VOICE pierces the darkness. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> I don't like this. I don't like this at all.<stage> A small bouquet of BLUE
     FLAMES blooms in Hermione's hands, illuminating little more than the trio's faces and some
     VAGUE SHAPES looming ahead. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Where are we? A graveyard? <stage> Harry Steps forward and--suddenly--one of
     the SHAPES moves towards them. Hermione GASPS. The SHAPE stops. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> This is no graveyard... <stage>Ron takes an unlit torch from the wall, touches
     it to the blue flames fluttering in Hermione's palms, and kneels. As he paints the floor with
     light, a SPARK SPITS from the torch and ignites a trail of FIRE. </stage> It's a chessboard.
     <stage>Sure enough. As the chamber glows with light, a kind of battlefield is revealed, studded
     with faceless soldiers.</stage>
   </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> But what're we to do? <stage> As Hermione takes a tentative step onto the
     board, a BISHOP'S STONE SWORD drops heavily down, barring her way. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> It's obvious, isn't it? We've got to play our way across the room. Excuse me...
    are we meant to join you? <stage>(as the bishop nods). </stage> Brilliant. <stage>(to Harry,
     Hermione) </stage> Now don't be offended, but neither of you are particularly good at chess- </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Just tell us what to do. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> All right. Harry, you take the empty Bishop's square. Hermione--you'll be the
    Queenside castle. As for me... <stage>Ron leaps astride the only riderless horse. </stage>
    ...I'll be a Knight. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> What happens now? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> We play. <stage> Across the board, a WHITE PAWN moves forward two squares (e4)
     As Ron contemplates his own move, Hermione glances apprehensively at the fierce pieces across
     the board. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Ron, you don't suppose this is going to be like real wizard's chess, do
    you? <stage> Ron--contemplating something--doesn't answer immediately, instead gesturing to his
     own pawn. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> You there... d5 <stage>As Ron's BLACK PAWN obliges, WHITE'S PAWN slides swiftly
     forth (to d5) and, with a THUNDEROUS collision, the black pawn EXPLODES, rubble raining to the
     ground. </stage> Yes, Hemione. I think this is going to be exactly like wizard's chess.
     <stage>Dissolve to: .... the chess board, a real battlefield now, littered on both sides with
     fallen pieces. Ron, drained but intense, surveys the board, MUTTERING to himself. </stage>
    Think...Think... <stage>(deciding) </stage> Castle to... c3 <stage> The BLACK CASTLE advances.
     Instantly, the WHITE QUEEN sweeps forward and, with cruel indifference, SHATTERS the Rook.
     Harry, only one square removed, stares with horror. Unnerved, he glances up at Ron, but Ron's
     eyes see only the board. Harry turns, taking a look himself... and blinks. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Wait a minute... <stage>(pointing to the Queen)</stage> She's made the same
    mistake I always make. If I go there, she has to take me, and the Ring is exposed! <stage> Ron
     nods, but it's clear he doesn't share Harry's enthusiasm. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> There's just one problem with that. It's you that has to go on, Harry. I know
    it. Not me. Not Hermione. You. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> No, Ron... </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> What is it? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> He's going to sacrifice himself. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE"> No. There has to be another way! </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Do you want to stop Snape from getting the Stone or not! <stage>(turning to
     Harry) </stage> You understand, right, Harry? Once I make my move, the Queen will take me. Then
    you're free to check the King. <stage> Harry stares at Ron--an understanding between them--then
     simply nods. Ron grips the reins then and, without a word, drives his horse forward (Nh3).
     Instantly, the White Queen POUNCES. As Ron hits the floor, Hermione SCREAMS She starts to go to
     him, when Harry holds up his hand. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> No! <stage>(as she freezes)</stage> Don't forget we're still playing.
     <stage>Hermione nods, staring at Ron. Harry steps forward. (Bc5). The WHITE QUEEN moves to
     block (Qe3), but it's futile. Harry stares at her, eyes full of hatred, then steps forward,
     places his trembling hand on the cold stone of her gown and, with the gentlest of shoves...
     topples her. </stage>
    <stage>(softly) </stage> Checkmate. <stage>As a veil of dust hovers, the white king removes his
     CROWN, lets it roll from his fingers, across the stone floor, where it comes to rest at Harry's
     feet. Harry stares at Hermione' s stricken face. </stage> If you can, go to the owlery and send
    a message to Dumbledore. Ron's right. I have to go on. <stage> Hermione turns, her eyes
     glittering. Without warning, she rushes forward, embraces Harry. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> You're a great wizard, Harry Potter! You are, you know! </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(a bit embarrassed)</stage> Not as good as you. </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Me! Books. And cleverness. There are more important things--friendship and
    bravery and--oh, Harry, be careful! <stage> She turns then, goes to Ron. Harry studies his two
     friends, then looks away. The remaining chessmen bow, parting the way to the next door. He
     steps forward. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" LAST CORRIDOR - MOMENTS LATER"> Alone, Harry makes his way through a
    corridor that drops down like a tunnel. Up ahead, a chamber glimmers. </stage>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" THE LAST CHAMBER - NIGHT"> Harry descends a staircase. As the chamber
    below comes into view, he sees a FIGURE standing before the Mirror of Erised. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY. "> You! <stage>The figure turns. It is Professor Quirrell.</stage> No. It can't
    be. Snape... </sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL "> Mm, yes, he does seem the type, doesn't he? So useful Snape. Swooping
    around like an overgrown bat. Next to him, who would suspect p-poorr st- stuttering Professor
    Quirrell? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> But that day, during the Quidditch match... Snape to kill me. </sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL"> No, dear boy, I tried to kill you. And, trust me, if Snape's cloak hadn't
    caught fire and broken my eye contact, I would've succeeded. Even with Severus muttering his
    little countercurse. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Snape was trying to save me? </sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL"> Oh, don't misunderstand. He hates you, just as he hated your father when
    they were at Hogwarts together. But he never wanted you dead. Your father, after all, saved his
    life once, long ago. <stage>Harry looks stunned. Quirrell looks amused. </stage> Didn't know?
    Surprising, given how curious you are Potter. I knew you were a danger to me right off.
    Especially after Halloween. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> You let the Troll in. <stage> Quirrell nods, examining the Mirror as he
     speaks: </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL"> Yes. I have a way with trolls. Snape, unfortunately, wasn't fooled. While
    everyone else was running about the dungeons, he went straight to the Third Floor to head me
    off. That three headed dog didn't even manage to bite Snape's leg off properly. He of course,
    never trusted me again. Rarely left me alone.. But he doesn't understand. I am never alone.
    Never... <stage>(frowning)</stage> Now what does this mirror do? I see what I desire, I see
    myself holding the Stone. But how do I get it? </sp>
   <sp who="#VOICE">
    <stage>(O.S.) </stage> Use the boy. <stage> Harry glances about in horror as the DARK VOICE
     echoes. Quirrell turns, eyes Harry. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL"> Come here, Potter <stage>Quirrell points to the mirror. As Harry steps in
     front, he sees himself, looking pale and scared. Then, slowly, his reflection SMILES, puts its
     hand in its pocket, and pulls out a BLOOD-RED STONE. Harry's own eyes widen--in a mixture of
     stunned disbelief and fear. Struggling to control his expression, he shuts his eyes briefly...
     as if making a wish... lets out a breath, and opens them once again. His reflection WINKS,
     returns the Stone to its pocket and, to Harry's amazement... ...it DROPS HEAVILY into his own:
     He's gotten the Stone. </stage>
    <stage>(studying him) </stage> What is it? What do you see? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I... I'm shaking hands with Dumbledore. I... I've won the House cup. </sp>
   <sp who="#VOICE">
    <stage>(O.S.)</stage> He lies. </sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL"> Tell the truth! What do you see? </sp>
   <sp who="#VOICE">
    <stage>(O.S.)</stage> Let me speak to him. </sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL"> Master, you are not strong enough. </sp>
   <sp who="#VOICE">
    <stage>(O.S.)</stage> I have strength enough... for this. <stage> Quirrell reaches up, unfurls
     his turban. In the mirror, Harry watches a FACE appear... on the back of Quirrell's head.
    </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(in a whisper)</stage> Voldemort. </sp>
   <sp who="#VOLDEMORT "> Harry Potter. We meet... again. <stage>Petrified, Harry stares at the
     face. It is hideous, constantly changing, struggling to become whole. </stage> Yes. You see
    what I've become. Unicorn blood can sustain me, but it cannot give me a body of my own. But
    there is something that can. Something that, conveniently enough... lies in your pocket...
     <stage>Harry wheels, dashing toward the staircase.</stage> Stop him! <stage> Coolly, Quirrell
     SNAPS his fingers and, just as Harry reaches the threshold, FLAMES SHOOT from the floor,
     barring his way.</stage> Don't be a 拢ool, Harry. Why suffer a horrific death, when you can join
    me... and live. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Never! </sp>
   <sp who="#VOLDEMORT "> Ah, bravery. Your parents had it too. Tell me, Harry... would you like to
    see your mother and father again? <stage>Harry stops, looks up. Quirrell steps aside,
     Voldemort's face sliding from the glass and revealing... Harry's parents. </stage> Together, we
    can bring them back. All I ask... is for something in return. <stage>Slowly, almost
     involuntarily, Harry removes the stone from his pocket. </stage> That's it, Harry. There is no
    good and evil, there is only power, and those too weak to seek it. Together, we'll do
    extraordinary things. Just... give me the Stone. <stage> Harry studies his parents' faces,
     drifting to his mother's, when... we RACK FOCUS...and Voldemort's hideous face surfaces through
     her's... and she is gone. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Liar! <stage> Voldemort's eyes narrow. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#VOLDEMORT "> Kill him! <stage> Instantly, Quirrell flies across the room, knocking
     Harry clean off his feet and the Stone tumbling from his grasp. Quirrell drops, his hand
     closing on Harry's neck. Harry winces at the touch, face creased in pain, looking up into
     Quirrell' s face, when... for the briefest of moments--it becomes Voldemort's. Harry gasps,
     struggling, when--to his amazement--Quirrell's own face returns, SCREAMING, releasing Harry and
     recoiling. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#QUIRRELL"> Wh-what is this magic? <stage> Harry, breathing hard, follows Quirrell's
     gaze, stares in horror: Quirrell's fingers are slowly turning to dust. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#VOLDEMORT"> Fool! Get the Stone! <stage> Harry rises, looks at Quirrell's withering
     fingers, then to his own hands, healthy and whole. As Quirrell starts to move, Harry, in the
     flash of a second... ...decides. He bolts forward, reaches up with both hands and... presses
     them to Quirrell's face. Quirrell SCREAMS, but Harry holds tight, growing weaker as the face
     under his fingers begins to DISSOLVE until, finally, just when Harry looks ready to pass out...
     Quirrell's face drops away. Harry staggers back. Quirrell's body steps forward, blindly
     lurching towards Harry, and then... crumbles to dust. Harry stands still, just staring, then
     turns wearily, picks up tbe Stone, when... an APPARITION--bearing Voldemort's devilish
     face--SWOOPS up behind. Harry spins, watching in terror as... WHOOSH!--in a VIOLENT RUSH--
     Voldemort returns to DUST and WHISTLES FORWARD, passing through Harry, blasting him back
     through the air and onto the stone floor. As the dust disappears, all is quiet once more, and
     we CUT TO: WIDE SHOT</stage> Of Harry. Lying on the floor. The Stone glimmering dully in his
    palm. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" HOGWARTS HOSPITAL WING - DAY "> A PAINTING... of an INJURED SOLDIER
    lying in a HOSPITAL BED. A NURSE enters the frame, begins to tend to his dressings as... Harry
    awakens in a hospital bed of his own. On the table next to him, TREATS are piled high, including
    a raft of open WIZARD CARDS. In one, Dumbledore beams down. </stage>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Good afternoon, Harry. <stage>Harry squints, as if the card itself had
     spoken to him, then sees that the real Dumbledore is sitting on the windowsill. The great
     wizard slides off, gestures to the treats. </stage> Tokens from your admirers. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Admirers? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> What happened down in the dungeons between you and Professor Quirrell is
    a complete secret--so naturally the whole school knows. Your friend Ronald has saved you the
    trouble of opening your chocolate frogs. Though one suspects Agrippa and Ptolemy still elude
    him. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY"> Ron was here? Is he all right? What about Hermione-- </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Fine. Both of them. Madame Pomfrey has explicitly forbidden visitors. But
    I think--with the help of a certain cloak-- they've managed to monitor your progress. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But what happened to the-- </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Relax, dear boy. The Stone has been destroyed. My friend Nicolas and I
    had a little chat and agreed it was best all around. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY. "> But then, Flamel... he'll die, won't he? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> He has enough Elixir to set his affairs in order. But, yes, he will die.
    To one as young as you, I'm sure it seems incredible. But to the well-organized mind, death is
    but the next great adventure. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But to destroy such a remarkable thing... </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Yes, yes. As much money and life as one could ever want--the two things
    most human beings would choose above all else. Unfortunately, humans do have a knack for
    choosing precisely those things that are worst for them. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> How is it I got the Stone, Sir? One minute I was staring in the mirror-- </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Ah. You see, only a person who wanted to find the Stone--find it, but not
    use it-would be able to get it. One of my more brilliant ideas and, between you and me, that's
    saying something. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Does that mean--with the Stone gone, that is--that Voldemort can never come
    back? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> I'm afraid there are other ways for him to return. And when--if--he does,
    it will take someone willing to fight a losing battle to stop him again. Someone like your
    parents. Someone like you. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY ">
    <stage>(troubled)</stage> Professor Dumbledore. Voldemort said... if I gave him the Stone, he
    could bring back my...family. Could he have, sir? Really? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Some people are like mirrors, Harry. They reflect our most desperate
    desires. We see what they want us to see. As painful as it surely was... you made the right
    choice. <stage>Harry nods. Dumbledore studies him thoughtfully.</stage> Do you know why
    Professor Quirrell couldn't bear to touch you, Harry? It's because of your mother. She
    sacrificed herself for you. And that kind of act leaves a mark. <stage>Harry reaches up to his
     scar. </stage> No, this kind of mark cannot be seen. It lives in your very skin. It is the very
    thing someone like Professor Quirrell-full of hatred and greed--cannot understand. Or bear to
    touch. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What is it? </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Love, Harry. Love. <stage>Dumbledore looks away then, smiles at Harry's
     treats. </stage> Ah! Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans! I was unfortunate enough in my youth to
    come across a vomit flavored one, and since then I'm afraid I've lost my liking for them. But I
    think I'll be safe with a nice toffee. <stage>(popping it)</stage> Alas! Ear wax! </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" MARBLE STAIRCASE - NIGHT "> As Harry limps down the staircase, he can
    hear the good cheer of those feasting beyond the doors of the Great Hall. Below, Hermione and
    Ron stand talking. Harry stops, simply studying them, then they turn, see him. Nothing is said
    for a moment. All of them beyond words. Then Harry nods to Ron's bruises. </stage>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> All right there, Ron? </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> All right. You? </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> All right. Hermione? <stage> She smiles. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Never better. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where=" GREAT HALL - NIGHT "> The roaring Hall is bedecked in GREEN AND
    SILVER--Slytherin colors--in honor of their winning the House Cup. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON"> D'you think Dumbledore meant for it all to happen'? And for you to do it'?
    Sending you your father's cloak and all? </sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Well,if he did-- I mean--that's terrible. You could have been killed. Come
    to think of it, I could've been killed... </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I think Dumbledore knows pretty much everything that goes on here. The only
    thing I don't understand is Snape... </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Professor Snape, Potter. <stage> Harry looks up, sees Professor
     McGonagall there. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> Yes, of course. I was only wondering. Is it true? Did he hate my father? </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> They were not compatible personalities, if that's what you mean. And
    then, of course, your father did something Severus could never forgive. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> What was that? </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL"> He saved his life. <stage>Astonished, Harry glances at Snape sitting at
     the High Table.</stage> I suppose he felt it his... obligation ...to look after you this year. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> Of course! And now that he's squared things, he can hate Harry in peace, right,
    Professor? </sp>
   <sp who="#MCGONAGALL "> Hogwarts teachers do not hate their students, Mr. Weasley...
     <stage>(pointedly, as she exits) </stage> No matter how taxing they may be. </sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> I think she's warming up to me. <stage> At the High Table, Dumbledore rises and
     the Hall quiets. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE"> Another year gone! Now as I understand it, the House Cup needs awarding,
    and the points stand thus: In fourth place, Gryffindor, with 312. <stage> Percy turns and glares
     at Ron. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#RON "> You'd think saving the bloody school from a Dark Lord would count for something. </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> In third place, Hufflepuff, with 352.In second, Ravenclaw, with 426. And
    in first place, with 472 points... Slytherin House. <stage>The Slytherin table erupts. Draco
     Malfoy, banging his goblet, casts a smirk at Harry, Ron and Hermione.</stage> Yes, well done,
    Slytherin. However, recent events must be taken into account. I have a few last minute points to
    award. <stage>The hall goes very STILL. The Slytherin smiles FADE a bit. </stage> First, to Miss
    Hermione Granger, for the cool use of intellect when others were in grave peril... fifty points.
     <stage>As the Gryffindors cheer, Hermione looks overwhelmed.</stage> Second, to Mr. Ronald
    Weasley, for the best played game of chess Hogwarts has seen in many years... fifty points. </sp>
   <sp who="#PERCY"> My youngest brother, you know! </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> Third, to Mr. Harry Potter, for pure nerve and outstanding courage, I
    award Gryffinder House... sixty points.<stage> The DIN is deafening as Hermione makes the
     calculations. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Oh my goodness. We've tied Slytherin! </sp>
   <sp who="#DUMBLEDORE "> And finally... it takes a great deal of bravery to stand up to our
    enemies, but even more to stand up to our friends. I therefore award 10 points to Mr. Neville
    Longbottom. <stage>As the room ROARS and the HOURGLASSES shift, a stunned Neville accepts wild
     slaps on the back. </stage> Assuming my calculations are correct, I believe a change of
    decoration is in order. <stage> Dumbledore CLAPS his hands and--instantly--the green and silver
     of Slytherin become the scarlet and gold of Gryffindor. Neville, white with shock, disappears
     under a pile of people hugging him. Draco Malfoy, looks stunned and horrified. Snape, with a
     horrible, forced smile, shakes Professor McGonagall's hand, then catches Harry's eye, his
     hatred still evident, but not enough to mar the moment. Harry considers the cheering faces that
     surround him, alone in the eye of a happy huricane. For a moment, he is not part of them, just
     watching. Then his voice joins the others, his face saying it all... This is a long way from
     the cupboard under the stairs. </stage></sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" HOGSMEADE STATION - NEXT DAY - DAY "> The Hogwarts Express stands
    steaming, ready to depart. From the doorway, Ron calls to Harry, alone on the platform. </stage>
   <sp who="#RON "> Come on now, Harry. <stage> Harry glances about once more, then starts for the
     train. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> Didn' think yeh'd be leavin' without sayin' goodbye, didya? <stage>Harry
     stops, smiles as Hagrid comes loping forward. Hagrid hands him a LEATHER-COVERED BOOK. </stage>
    That there's fer you to open on the train. Which seems to be leavin', by the way. <stage>Harry
     holds out his hand. Hagrid takes it, then pulls him into a rough hug. </stage> Go on now. An'
    Harry? If tha' dolt of a cousin o' yers Dudley gives yeh any grief, yeh can always threaten ter
    give 'im a pair o' ears ter go with that tail of 'is. </sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> But Hagrid. We' re not allowed to do magic away from Hogwarts. You know that. </sp>
   <sp who="#HAGRID "> I do... <stage>(a wink) </stage> But yer cousin don't. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="INT" where="TRAIN COMPARTMENT - DAY "> Ron half-dozes against the window, while
    Hermione does some "light reading." Harry sits opposite them, studying Hagrid's gift curiously.
    Then he opens it. Inside, the pages are filled with WIZARD PHOTOGRAPHS. Smiling and waving at
    Harry from every page are the faces he first saw in the Mirror of Erised. The faces of his
    mother and father. As the train lurches forward, Hermione looks up. </stage>
   <sp who="#HERMIONE "> Feels strange, doesn't it? To be going home. <stage> Harry traces his
     finger over the smiling face of his mother, then looks up, following Hermione's gaze to the
     window. </stage></sp>
   <sp who="#HARRY "> I'm not going home... Not really. </sp>
  </scene>
  <scene>
   <stage cat="EXT" where=" TRAIN -  MOVING AWAY - SAME TIME "> As Harry peers out, his face is
    calm. Peaceful. Hogwarts Castle glimmers in reflection on his window and we ... </stage>
   <stage>PULL AWAY ... rising high above Hogsmeade Station, above the Dark Forest and Hogwarts
    Castle itself as the Scarlet Express glitters far below, making its way back to the Muggle
    world. Slowly, we... FADE TO BLACK </stage>
  </scene>
 </script>
</xml>
